Welcome to Cooking Diary! Today in our Cooking Diary, we're going to see how to make a special biryani. Biryani is always special, but Dindigul Thalappakatti Biryani is extra special because its aroma and taste are unlike any other.
Use Seeraga Samba rice for biryani. Use Seeraga Samba rice. Use Seeraga Samba rice. Use Seeraga Samba rice. Use Seeraga Samba rice. Use Seeraga Samba rice.
If you want it spicier, grind green chilies. Before grinding, chop the ginger like this and add it. Now pour 1/4 cup water into it and grind into a fine paste. This way, we'll get a good paste.
If you have small onions for biryani, definitely use them. If you have small onions for biryani, definitely use them. If you have small onions for biryani, definitely use them. If you have small onions for biryani, definitely use them. If you have small onions...
Along with this, add 6 tablespoons of oil. The oil is now hot. Now we can add what we ground earlier — the Thalappakatti biryani masala. First, add the ginger-green chili paste.
Mix it well and sauté on medium heat for about 10 minutes. Let that raw smell go away and the flavor comes out. Until then, keep sautéing. Look, it’s releasing oil now — that means it’s ready.
We’ve added the mutton. I’ve taken 1 kg of good mutton pieces. I’m adding them now. Mix it all well. Now we can add 1/2 teaspoon chili powder and salt as required.
Add the required amount of water for the biryani. I’ve taken 1.5 tumblers of rice, so I’m adding 3 tumblers of water. Always use 2 tumblers of water for 1 tumbler of rice. That’s the ratio. Similarly, for 1 kg rice...
You can pressure cook this for 6 to 7 whistles for mutton to cook well. If it’s chicken, 2 whistles will do. Now it’s cooked well, and the fat has separated. See, the mutton is well cooked. Now switch off the stove.
As soon as it comes to a boil, add 1/4 cup of curd. Mix it well once. See, it’s starting to boil. Now add a handful of mint leaves and a handful of chopped coriander leaves. Add them and let it cook for five minutes.
Look, it’s boiling well now. Add the rice that we soaked earlier. Always soak biryani rice for 30 minutes before cooking. Only then it cooks without sticking and comes out fluffy and beautiful.
The salt and spiciness in the biryani water must be slightly higher. Only then, after it cooks, the taste will be perfect. Look, it’s boiling well, and the water is reducing. At this stage, lower the flame to simmer.
Thalappakatti Biryani is ready! Now it looks like a wedding feast. The biryani is ready! Now it looks like a wedding feast. The biryani is ready! Now it looks like a wedding feast...
Mix it gently and close the lid for about 15 minutes. After that, serve. See how amazing our Dindigul Thalappakatti Biryani has turned out? Whoever tastes it will love it. It will taste just like the original. Definitely try it at home!