In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful...
You can make it very delicious and in a very simple way. Many people make it very complicated, but I'll show you such an easy method that you can make it at home easily. For Sindhi Biryani, we have one kilogram of soaked rice...
We have whole spices, fresh green spices, biryani masala, and oil. So let’s begin with the name of Allah. First, in a wok we’ve added water in which we’ll parboil the rice...
We’ve added one star anise, a small piece of cinnamon, two green cardamoms, and some nutmeg and mace to make the rice aromatic...
Now we will let it come to a boil. On the other side, in a pot, we've added water to boil half a kilogram of potatoes. We’ve added one-fourth teaspoon of...
In a frying pan, add oil and fry the onions until golden brown...
So don’t skip any part of the video, watch the whole thing carefully. Now we’ll strain the onions – they should be golden, not darker than this...
We’ve drained all the oil from them. This same oil will be used in our Sindhi Biryani. So now we have boiled potatoes, fried onions, and the oil. Let’s put them aside and take a mixing bowl...
We’ve added chopped onion and tomato, two tablespoons of chopped coriander, and two tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste...
Now we add half of the fried onions (we saved the other half for layering). We’ll mix these with the chicken...
If you don’t like store-bought masalas, you can prepare them at home like this. This homemade biryani masala is much better. We’ve added about 3 tablespoons...
Mix everything well. If you have time, marinate for an hour, or you can cook it directly too. Now the rice water is also boiling...
We will boil the rice up to 70-80% only. They should remain a bit undercooked so that they can finish cooking later...
On another stove, we’ve placed a pan with the same oil used to fry onions. Add 4–5 chopped green chilies...
The aroma of the biryani masala is so amazing! You have to try this recipe and share your experience with me. Let it cook like this for 5 minutes...
In any meat recipe, it’s essential to roast the meat properly. Look at the color of the masala – now we’ll add half a cup of water so the chicken can soften. Cover and cook...
Meanwhile, the rice is almost done. It still has a bit of a bite. We’ll strain them now. On the other side, we’ll remove the lid of the pan...
Now we add the boiled potatoes. Bismillah... Look how beautifully colored the potatoes are. This is how your delicious Sindhi Biryani comes together...
It’s almost complete now. On the counter, we’ve placed another pot where we’ll assemble layers. First, we’ve added a bit of oil at the bottom so the rice doesn’t stick...
Now we’ll add a layer of rice. If you haven’t subscribed to the channel, please do so. On top of the rice, we add a layer of the prepared chicken curry...
After that layer, we’ll remove the cinnamon stick – no need for it now. Spread the rice evenly, then add another layer of chicken curry...
This layer is complete. Now add sliced tomatoes. It looks colorful, fragrant, and amazing! We also have fresh mint leaves...
Spread everything across the layer. Now add the remaining fried onions we had saved. Just like this...
Nothing is difficult – it’s made difficult. Watch videos to make cooking easier for yourself. God willing, you’ll learn everything at home. Now we’ll add yellow food color...
Now we’ll let it steam (dum). Place a tawa (griddle) on the stove and the biryani pot on top. Cover with a lid and steam for 15–20 minutes...
The steaming is done. The aroma – I can’t even describe it! Now we’ll take a spoon and gently mix the rice so it stays fluffy...
This prevents the rice from breaking and keeps the layers distinct. Some grains are yellow, some white – it looks beautiful. Now, we add some more aroma...
The smell is so good, I think the whole neighborhood will come today! Let me show you the final look. Alhamdulillah, your Sindhi Biryani is ready – very tasty and...
Make it, make it, make it, make it, make it, make it, make it, make it, make it, make it, make it, make it...
The appreciation I receive from you is like an award. Don’t forget to give it. With that, I take your leave. Take care, remember me in your prayers. Thank you so much, Allah Hafiz!