Today we’re making Mughlai Chicken Biryani. If you like Hyderabadi biryani, you’ll definitely enjoy this too. Be sure to try it!
If you enjoy this recipe, don’t forget to like and share it. Let’s get started. First, wash basmati rice thoroughly and soak it for 30 minutes. Next, we’ll marinate the chicken.
Add 3 tbsp chopped coriander, 2 tbsp mint, 1/4 cup fried onions, and 3 tbsp of the same oil used to fry the onions. Mix it all well.
Cover and let it marinate for 30 minutes. After that, we’ll prepare a paste. In a mixer, blend 1/2 cup fried onions and 1/4 cup curd (yogurt). No need to add water.
Once blended, set aside. Now, we’ve set 7 cups of water to boil for the rice. Add salt to taste and whole spices like 1 tsp caraway seeds...
As soon as we add rice, water temperature will drop, so bring it back to boil. Let the rice cook for 2 minutes. It should be soft but not fully cooked.
Drain the rice once done. Now let’s quickly make the biryani gravy. Heat 2 tbsp oil, add cinnamon, star anise, 3 green cardamoms, and...
The chicken is now turning from pink to white. Add 1/4 cup water and mix. Cover and cook for 15 minutes on medium heat. Stir occasionally.
Add the spices: 1/4 tsp turmeric powder, 1 tsp red chili powder, 2 tsp coriander powder, and 1/2 tsp cumin powder. Fry this for 2–3 minutes.
Mix well. Cover and cook until the gravy comes to a boil. Once it does, give it a stir and add 2 green chilies. Cover and cook for another 10 minutes.
By now, the chicken should be completely cooked. Stir occasionally so the spices don’t burn. After 10 minutes, the oil has separated and the gravy looks perfect.
Mix it once. As soon as you add cream, the gravy’s color will change to a lighter shade. Add coriander and fried onions. Mix again.
The Mughlai chicken gravy is ready and tastes amazing. Taste it and adjust salt if needed. Now we’ll layer cooked rice on top of this.
Add orange food color if available; if not, that’s okay. Add 1 tsp biryani masala. Soak saffron in 1/4 cup warm milk for 10 mins and pour that in too.
I’ve already fried cashews and almonds in ghee, so I’m adding them now. Since it’s Mughlai biryani, dry fruits are a must. Add more if you like.
Now cover the pot. If you have a tight-fitting lid, use it. I’m using a plate to cover. Place the biryani pot on a tawa (griddle) to prevent burning.
Place some weight on top and let it cook on dum. This helps retain steam and evenly cook rice and chicken. Cook on medium heat for 5 minutes...
After 10 minutes, open the lid. Wow! The aroma is amazing!
See how perfectly the rice is cooked? Nothing stuck at the bottom. If there’s some gravy left at the bottom, cook uncovered on low heat till dry.
If you liked the recipe, please like the video and don’t forget to subscribe. And if you try this biryani, leave a comment and let me know how it turned out. Until next time!