Today I’m sharing with you the recipe for Kolkata-style Mutton Biryani, which is very easy to make. Do try this recipe at least once — you’re all going to love it.
Here, I’ll also show you the perfect way to boil rice — you could say it’s my secret method. This will ensure your biryani rice turns out fluffy like this. Everyone keeps asking me which rice I use...
Here I’ve taken one kilogram of mutton. Now I’m adding two tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste. Along with that, add 150 grams of fresh yogurt — don’t use very sour yogurt. Now I’ll add some powdered spices.
We’ll now let the marinated mutton sit for half an hour. If you have time, you can keep it in the fridge for one hour. Meanwhile, I’ve taken potatoes — about 250 grams of raw potatoes, cut into big pieces.
Mix everything well into the potatoes. Also, we’ll add one teaspoon of kewra water. You can add kewra water to the potatoes or during the final dum (steam cooking) process. I’m adding it now.
(Repeated unintelligible words — possibly a glitch or audio loop. No meaningful content.)
Yes, if you soak the rice like this for 30 minutes before boiling and add a teaspoon of salt, the rice will swell in size due to soaking. And when boiled, it will cook beautifully and won’t stick together.
Now I’ve taken 200 grams of onion, finely chopped. After 30 minutes, we’ll start making the biryani. Half an hour is up. On high flame, I’ve placed the cooker and added 250 ml of oil.
The onions have changed color. Now we need to strain them out from the oil. Fry only until this point — they will become crisp later when left on the plate. Our birista (fried onions) is ready — set it aside.
Now we’ll fry the potatoes nicely for 4 to 5 minutes on high-medium flame. Any leftover masala will be used later. I’ve fried the potatoes well — now we’ll remove them from the oil.
The remaining masala on the potatoes has added color too. Now we’ll sauté it well until the masala releases oil. At this stage, add 4-5 whole green chilies.
Add 1 cup of mint leaves and 1 cup of coriander leaves, both washed. From the fried onions we set aside, add some here. We’ll use the rest later.
As you can see, I’ve sautéed the mutton well. The masala has released oil and the aroma is amazing. Now we need to tenderize the mutton. It’s not fully cooked yet — just well sautéed for now.
While the mutton is cooking, we’ll boil the rice. It’s been 30 minutes since soaking. In a large pot, I’ve taken 3–4 liters of water. I’m adding 3–4 tablespoons of salt — as per the water amount.
Now I’ll add some whole spices: 2 bay leaves, 1 tsp black pepper, 6 small cardamoms, 1 tsp fennel seeds, 1 tsp shah jeera (caraway), 2 black cardamoms, 2 star anise, and 6–7 cloves.
We’ll wait for the water to boil. As you can see, the soaked rice has puffed up — it has absorbed water and will now cook faster when boiled.
(The phrase “pani pani” is repeated multiple times with no new content. Likely a filler or glitch.)
If you get whole spices in your bite while eating, it’s not pleasant. So strain the water — all the flavors have transferred into it. Now I’m adding the rice. What do we need to do with the rice?
I’ve added all the rice. Turn the flame to high. Stir it gently once to ensure rice doesn’t settle at the bottom. Let it cook on high flame for 3–4 minutes. Cooking time depends on the rice variety.
You can see how long the rice has become — it has almost doubled in size. That’s why soaking for 30 minutes is crucial. As you can see, the grains are fluffy and separate — we didn’t even add lemon juice.
We had already added kewra water to the potatoes. So they carry that flavor.
Let’s now start assembling the biryani for dum. I’ve taken a vessel — first I’ll add a little oil (rogan). Then a layer of rice. The remaining rice will be added later — this is our first layer.
Now I’m adding all the korma (gravy) and spreading it evenly. Then we’ll add the fried potatoes — I’ll place them all around. These are large-sized pieces.
Add 1 cup of milk. You can use mawa (milk solids) too, or even both. Kolkata biryani traditionally uses mawa. Now I’m adding a bit of the reserved rogan (flavored oil) again.
Finally, add 2 to 3 tablespoons of ghee. You *must* add ghee at the end — it gives the biryani a great aroma and adds shine to the rice.
Cook it on high flame for 2–3 minutes, then lower the flame and cook for 15 minutes. After that, turn off the stove. I let it rest for 15 minutes. Now I’ll open the lid and show you...
Do try this Kolkata-style biryani recipe at least once. I’ve shared all my secrets with you. When making biryani, you now know how to soak the rice, how long to cook it, and how to layer it.
So here you go — our masala mutton biryani is ready. You could call it Mutton Aloo Dum Biryani. Kolkata-style — it’s incredibly aromatic and flavorful. It’s as easy to make as it is delicious to eat.
Please like this video, share it, and subscribe to my channel. Also, don’t forget to click the bell icon so you get notifications first. That way you can watch my videos as soon as they release.
See you in the next recipe. Take care, and do remember me in your prayers. Allah Hafiz.