Assalamu Alaikum! I'm Tarif Tawud, and today we're making the queen of all biryanis—Bombay Biryani! And that too, in an authentic, delicious, restaurant-style or wedding-style version. We'll be sharing the recipe with you today. Before we begin making Bombay Biryani, we request you to subscribe to the channel, like, share, and press the bell icon. Let's get started!
Bismillah-ir-Rahman-ir-Rahim. Let's begin with Durood Sharif (blessing on the Prophet). We're making Bombay Biryani with mutton. After taking 1 kg of mutton, add two tomatoes. This will be a great marinade for our Bombay Biryani. I had already chopped 8–10 green chilies here.
Whole spices include 1 tablespoon of cumin seeds, some black pepper, cloves, cinnamon, and black cardamom. Take them whole—not powdered—because ground spices from packets often come in excess quantities. Three onions were browned earlier; I'm adding half (about one and a half onions) to the marinade and keeping the rest aside for layering later.
Now add half a kilo of yogurt—the better the yogurt, the better the marinade. The quality of your Bombay Biryani depends on the spices you use. Add 1 heaped tablespoon of crushed red chili, 1.5 tablespoons of ground red chili, 1 heaped tablespoon of coriander powder, and 1 teaspoon of turmeric.
Add 1 heaped tablespoon of ground garam masala and 1 teaspoon of nutmeg and mace powder. We'll also add some dried plums. Mix the marinade well. Use the same oil in which we fried the onions—this method is simple and authentic. In Bombay, sometimes they marinate without cooking, but this method gives amazing flavor. People love Bombay Biryani!
Alhamdulillah, I make really good recipes, especially Indian ones, and you’ve seen our other Bombay recipes before too. We’ll marinate the meat now. Once it’s marinated well, half your work is done—this is a very easy procedure. Just focus on getting a good marinade.
Marination is done.
You can balance the salt even after cooking, but the Biryani should be slightly salty so that when you add the rice, the flavor is balanced. In our Biryani, spices are kept separate from rice. I’ll show you that later. Marination is now complete.
Now I’ll keep it aside for about two hours to marinate. After two hours, the meat has marinated. We’re not adding any more spices or oil. Just a few things for layering, as per Bombay Biryani tradition. First, I’ll clean the dish (tray) properly and then turn on the stove.
I’ve rinsed the tray with water so that once the meat is sautéed, we can cook it with the same water. First, since the marinated meat is perfect, we’ll sauté it until the color changes and the vegetables (like tomatoes and onions) soften a bit. Sauté it well.
Look, the meat and masala are sautéed.
Always clean your blenders and choppers properly after grinding masala. My tray is clean now. We’ll add water as needed—just enough to soften the meat. The better the meat is cooked, the better the Bombay Biryani will turn out. The water seems perfect now.
Now we’ll cook it for at least an hour. The 1 kg of meat I used had bones and was nice and tender, so the broth will be rich. Let’s cook it. While the meat is cooking, we’ll prepare the rice for Bombay Biryani. The rice is boiled in a very specific way. Add two tablespoons of salt.
Add a little oil so the rice gets a nice shine. For 1 kg of meat, I soaked 1 kg of good basmati rice. Bombay Biryani usually uses sella (parboiled) rice.
Let’s boil these rice. My rice is about 80% done—we'll leave a little undercooked because Bombay Biryani gravy is quite moist. Now let’s drain the rice and move on to the next step.
MashaAllah, the meat is beautifully tender and the masala is amazing. That same feel you get with true Bombay Biryani is here. (Note: repeated “bhung bhung” here appears to be a vocal sound, likely expressing excitement or aroma, not actual words.)
Here’s the brown onion we saved during the marination step. It’s time for the layering now. I sliced one big tomato—these go in along with fresh coriander and mint.
Half a bunch of coriander, half a bunch of mint—you can also use a full bunch of mint. It enhances the flavor beautifully. Now the rice will go on top.
On top, we’ll just add food coloring. Typically, Bombay Biryani doesn’t use kewra essence because the marination already gives a rich fragrance. That aroma spreads through the rice wonderfully. Here comes our yellow food coloring with a little water to give it a two-tone look.
Now we’ll put a lid on and give it a good “dum” (steam cooking) for about 15 minutes.
After 15 minutes—uff, Alhamdulillah, what a fragrance! Don’t stir yet. There’s a process: sprinkle 3–4 tablespoons of oil on top to keep the rice separate. Let’s cover it again for another 2-minute dum. Alhamdulillah, my Bombay Biryani is ready with an amazing aroma.
Now let’s show you a serving method I really enjoy. I always want to present dishes the way they’re made in their origin—authentically. Move all the rice to one side.
And here’s the brown masala underneath—this is the soul of Bombay Biryani! That rich bottom layer color. We’ll plate it and I’ll show you on the presentation table. Let’s go there now.