Hello friends, how are you all? In this video, we are going to see how to make Donne Biryani. It's a very famous recipe from Karnataka. Many people on our channel have asked how to make Donne Biryani.
For the biryani, I’ve taken about half a kilo of chicken. When you buy it from the shop, tell them it’s for biryani—they'll give you big pieces like this. Only if the pieces are this big will it taste good. Now onto the chicken...
Mix all the masala well into the chicken and marinate it for half an hour. Meanwhile, let’s prepare the biryani masala. I’ve taken a handful of coriander leaves and a handful of mint leaves...
Add garlic, onions, and green chilies. Sauté all of these together well for about 2 minutes. After 2 minutes of sautéing, add the chopped mint and coriander leaves.
After adding mint and coriander, sauté for another 30 seconds. Once it cools down a bit, grind it into a paste using a mixie jar. Now the biryani masala paste is ready. You can add a little of this paste later too.
Grind 1 spoon each of fennel seeds and cumin seeds. Take one bay leaf, one star anise, one cardamom, a clove, a small piece of cinnamon, and a Kashmiri chili. Even if it’s a normal chili, it’s okay. Prepare all of this...
Look, it's roasted to a nice golden brown. Transfer this to a plate. Once it cools down, grind it well using the mixie. Meanwhile, place a wide pot on the stove and add oil.
You need to add ghee to biryani—that’s what gives it a great aroma and flavor. I’m adding about two spoons of ghee. Once it heats up, add one star anise, two cardamoms, and two pieces of cinnamon.
The onions for biryani should be sautéed to this level. Now I’ve sautéed them well. Take one big tomato, grind it in the mixie into a paste and add it to the pot. After that, add the ground green masala paste...
After adding the green masala paste, add the marinated chicken. Cook both the chicken and masala together for about 5–6 minutes. Cook them well so the raw smell goes away and the chicken is coated.
Now add salt as needed for the biryani. Mix everything well for about two more minutes. See, I’ve mixed all the masala well. It has started to cook nicely now.
For two tumblers of rice, I’m going to add three tumblers of water. To ensure everything cooks well, I’m adding an extra quarter tumbler of water. Let the water come to a rolling boil. Once it starts boiling...
Add the rice and mix it well. Let it cook uncovered for a while. As the water starts to reduce and the rice starts to cook, I’ll cover it with a lid and let it cook further.
Keep the flame low and place the biryani pot on a dosa tawa (griddle). Then place a plate that fits over the pot. Put some weight on top of it—only then will the 'dum' cooking work well.
Since there are kids at home, we usually do this method. After placing it on the dosa tawa, let it cook for about 5 minutes. You can keep it for about 5 minutes after placing it on the tawa...
Look at this—the rice has cooked perfectly. The biryani looks absolutely delicious. I’m going to lightly mix it now.
There’s absolutely no burning or sticking at the bottom. Look—I tilted the pot and used a ladle, but there was no sticking. That’s because we used the dosa tawa below. Donne Chicken Biryani is ready—have a look!
If you liked this recipe, please share it with others. For more videos like this, don’t forget to subscribe to the channel and click the bell icon.