Today we are going to make a tasty, rich, and very popular Kolkata-style biryani. In this video, we have made this biryani in a very simple way. So let’s begin making it. For this, we need 1.25 kg of chicken.
Add two teaspoons of red chili powder and salt to taste. I’m adding two teaspoons here. Then we’ll add two tablespoons of biryani masala. The link to this biryani masala recipe is given here; you can check out the recipe.
Mix the chicken well with the spices and leave it to marinate in the fridge for two hours. Now in a pot, take one cup of oil. Add 2–3 bay leaves, 2–3-inch pieces of cinnamon, 6–7 green cardamoms.
First, fry these whole spices in the oil for 2–3 minutes. Take two medium-sized onions, sliced, and add them in. Fry the onions until they turn a nice golden color.
Add ginger-garlic paste and fry it well with the onions. Then add the chicken and mix everything together. Let the chicken cook. Meanwhile, let’s get the potatoes ready.
Here I’ve taken peeled potatoes, about 750 grams. If you have large potatoes, you can cut them into two pieces. Using a knife, make holes in the potatoes like this so they cook thoroughly and absorb the spices inside.
Add half a teaspoon of turmeric. If you prefer, you can use yellow food color instead of turmeric. Also add one teaspoon of Kashmiri red chili powder. Now we need to cook the potatoes with the chicken—not too much, just enough. Add them to the chicken.
Now cook the chicken and potatoes together on medium to low flame for 20–25 minutes. While the chicken is cooking, we will prepare the rice. To prepare the rice, take 3–4 times more water than the quantity of rice.
As soon as the water boils, add the rice. This is one kilogram of basmati rice, which has been soaked for half an hour and rinsed thoroughly. Add it in. Add two teaspoons of salt and two teaspoons of lemon juice.
The potatoes have become nice and soft. Now sprinkle one teaspoon of biryani masala over them. Cook the rice till it’s 80% done, then drain it and spread it over the chicken.
Now take one cup of milk. I’m adding half a teaspoon of saffron to it and two drops of kewra water. Mix it well. I’m adding yellow food coloring powder; you can use liquid if preferred. Add two teaspoons of rose water.
Add 4–5 tablespoons of desi ghee. Now pour the milk mixture we just prepared all over the rice. This mixture gives a beautiful color and amazing aroma to the biryani. Now we will put the biryani on dum (slow steam cooking).
If you want, you can seal the lid using dough. Now place the lid. Let the biryani cook on low flame for 15–20 minutes. After 15–20 minutes, remove the lid and the aluminum foil from the top.
Look at that beautiful color. This aromatic Kolkata-style biryani is now ready. First, we’ll move the rice aside gently, then dish out the biryani. This delicious biryani is now ready with a wonderful aroma and taste.