As-salamu alaykum. Today I'm sharing with you the recipe to make Sindhi Biryani. It's quite different from regular biryani — much spicier and more flavorful by comparison.
To make Sindhi Biryani, we first need to prepare the biryani masala powder. Take 1 tbsp coriander seeds, 1 tsp white cumin, ½ tsp black cumin (shahi jeera), and 1 tsp...
...¼ piece of nutmeg, 1 black cardamom, 2 small cinnamon sticks, 12–13 green cardamoms, 1 star anise, and 5–6...
I’ve ground all the whole spices into a powder. Now add 1 tsp Kashmiri red chili powder (you can use regular chili but it'll be spicier), 2 tsp or to taste...
Sindhi biryani uses dried plums (aloo bukhara), so try to add them. If you don’t have them, you can substitute with a bay leaf. Mix everything well, and your masala is ready.
For the biryani, I’ve taken 1 kg chicken. I’ll be using equal parts rice and chicken — so 1 kg rice as well. Now add 3 tablespoons...
Add ginger-garlic paste and the masala we just made. This is a great homemade spice blend — no need for store-bought masala.
Add green chilies to taste — I’m adding 2–3. Also add chopped coriander, mint, and 2 medium-sized tomatoes (about ½ cup).
Mix all ingredients well. If you have time, marinate for longer. If not, just 20–25 minutes is enough — don’t over-marinate.
For layering, I’ve sliced 3 medium tomatoes. Altogether, I’ve used 300g tomatoes in this recipe.
I’ve also taken 3 medium-sized potatoes, cut into large chunks, and soaked them in orange food color for 30 mins. This is optional.
I’ve soaked the rice for 1 hour. Use any good quality basmati rice that you usually prefer for biryani.
Let’s start making the biryani. Take a pan and add ½ cup oil. Total we’ll use 1 cup oil (approx. 250ml). We’ll use the other half later during layering.
We’ll use one onion later for layering. Now add the marinated chicken to the pan. No need to add any extra spices — everything is already in it. Cook on high flame.
We want to cook the chicken, so now add the potatoes as well, and ½ cup water. Mix well and cover to cook for about 20 minutes.
I cooked the chicken for 20–25 minutes on low flame. It's fully done. Now turn the flame to high and dry up any extra water completely.
Take 4 times the rice quantity of water. Add 3 tbsp salt and 2 tbsp oil. This keeps the rice from sticking. Also add lemon slices for flavor.
Once the water boils, add the soaked rice. Since it’s soaked well, it will cook quickly. Cook on high flame till the rice is about 70% done.
Now prepare for layering. First apply oil at the bottom of the pot. This prevents sticking or burning. Add one layer of rice, then...
...add the next layer of chicken masala and some rice. Save a bit of rice for the top layer. Now sprinkle coriander and mint.
Pour the remaining gravy on top. Add the last layer of rice, followed by tomato, mint, coriander, ginger, green chilies, and fried onions.
Now pour the remaining oil on top — this is the same oil we used to fry the onions. I’ve used 1 cup total oil. Don’t worry if it feels like too much — biryani needs it.
Now seal the pot — I’m using foil. You can also use a towel. Cook on high for 2 minutes, then place a heavy griddle (tawa) or plate below for dum.
Once there’s good steam, that means your biryani is cooked through. Now gently mix from bottom to top.
Mix gently so that the rice doesn't break and the masala gets distributed evenly. The biryani is now ready to serve.
So this is how our Sindhi Biryani is made. I wish you could smell how aromatic it is! It’s super tasty and very easy to make — not complicated at all.
I also have a Facebook page — please like it. And if you’re new to the channel, please don’t forget to subscribe. Thank you!