Today we’ll make a very popular and tasty Sindhi Biryani. It tastes great and is an easy recipe. Do watch the full video, and if you like it, don’t forget to like, share, and subscribe. So let’s begin.
First, I’ve taken 700 grams of chicken and I’ll add some spices to it. I added one tablespoon of ginger-garlic paste and some spices along with salt according to the chicken quantity.
I’ve added 2 to 3 green chilies—adjust as per your spice level. I added chopped coriander, mint, one chopped tomato, and two medium-sized onions fried into birista (crispy onions).
This is biryani masala. I used Suhana biryani masala here, but you can use any brand you have available. I added two heaping tablespoons. These are dried plums (Aloo Bukhara), which are essential for Sindhi Biryani.
I’ve taken a pinch of saffron and soaked it in warm water. This gives a nice color and enhances the flavor during the layering of the biryani.
Take a little water, and I’ve added two medium-sized potatoes and some food coloring to it. I also added a few drops of kewra essence. If you don’t have it, you can skip it, but it adds a nice fragrance.
Now I’m adding the potatoes we soaked. They’ve taken on the color and flavor. Keep the flame high so that it comes to a strong boil. I’ll now mix it well on high heat.
Once it starts boiling, reduce the flame to medium. Cover and cook it for 15–20 minutes until the chicken becomes tender. Meanwhile, we’ll prep the rice.
The rice comes out fluffy and separate. Add 2 bay leaves, 2–3 cloves, 2–3 black peppercorns, 2–3 green cardamoms, and 2 cinnamon sticks. Boil the water well before adding rice.
Check the rice—they should be firm but cooked, not mushy or too soft. The chicken is ready now. I checked it once midway to ensure the water hadn’t dried up.
Now layer one-fourth of the rice at the bottom. Then garnish it with thin lemon slices.
Next, arrange tomato slices. Traditionally, thick green chilies are used which are not spicy, but I didn’t have them, so I used chopped regular ones. Add some coriander, mint, and the saffron we soaked earlier.
Spread the chicken evenly. Add the remaining rice on top. I used half a kilo of rice for this recipe. Again, place sliced tomatoes and lemons along with some fresh coriander.
The leftover oil from the chicken korma—add a bit of it here to keep the rice moist and prevent it from drying out. Cover and cook on low heat.
Sindhi Biryani is ready! It’s a slightly different recipe but tastes absolutely delicious. Definitely give it a try. And as always, if you liked the recipe, don’t forget to like, share, and subscribe. That’s all for today—see you next time!