In the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. Peace be upon you. Today I'm sharing a chicken biryani recipe with you. Look at how each grain of rice is perfectly cooked. The chicken is thoroughly cooked inside. This biryani turns out so aromatic and delicious.
First, I have taken 1 kg of golden sela rice. We will make this biryani using sela rice. I have washed this rice thoroughly.
I soaked it for 30 minutes. If you are using basmati rice, soak it for 15 minutes. I have taken a wide pot here with 1.5 liters of water. Make sure to boil the water before adding the rice.
The water is boiling now, and we'll add salt to it. We must add salt at this stage as the rice is boiling. Now I’ll add the soaked rice. Look at this.
All the rice has been added, and I’ll give it a good mix. This is very important. Follow each step properly, and your biryani rice will turn out just like this.
Boil on high flame until the rice is 80-85% cooked. It should still have a slight bite. Sela rice takes longer to cook compared to basmati. See this.
It’s still slightly undercooked. I’ve drained the water and separated the rice. Now we’ll prepare the masala for the biryani. I’ve taken cardamom and black peppercorns.
I’ll provide the ingredients and quantities in the description box. I’ve also added cumin and two cloves. We’ll roast these well.
You can discard the cardamom peels if you like. Look at this. We’ll set this aside. Now I’ve taken a wide pot again for the biryani.
Always use a wide pot for biryani. I’ve added 1 cup of oil. The oil is well heated. Now I’ll add 1 large roughly chopped onion.
We’ll fry them on high flame until they turn golden brown. Look, the onions are perfectly fried. Now I’ll add chicken. I’m adding 3 kg of chicken here — two chickens.
The chicken pieces should be a bit large in biryani. All the chicken has been added, and we’ll fry it on high flame.
Fry on high flame until the color changes. The chicken has turned a bit brown now. I’ll now add 2 tablespoons of ginger garlic paste.
Mix it well. Look, the ginger garlic paste has mixed nicely. I’ll now add half a cup of water and mix it again. Keep the flame high.
Now I’ll add some spices — cinnamon sticks, two black cardamoms, and all the roasted masala we prepared earlier. Also, 1 teaspoon turmeric.
2 tablespoons Kashmiri red chili powder (adjust to taste), 2 tablespoons lemon juice, and 2 tablespoons yogurt.
Add salt to taste. I’ll list ingredients and quantities in the description. I’m also adding a few green chilies — adjust as per your preference.
Cook until the added water dries up and oil rises to the surface. Cook on high flame.
Look, the oil has risen to the top and the spices are well roasted with the chicken. Now I’ll add 1 liter of water and let it boil on high flame.
It’s boiling now. I’ll add the parboiled rice. Spread it evenly.
Mix a bit of the rice with the gravy. More rice is still to be added. Here it is.
I’ve spread the rice evenly. Now we’ll cook it covered until steam forms. Cook on high flame.
See, steam has formed due to high heat — this is very important. Now I’ll add saffron water. I soaked 2 strands in 4 tablespoons of water. You can use red food color instead.
I’ll also sprinkle 1 teaspoon cardamom powder over it. Now we’ll seal and cook it on low flame.
I’ve placed silver foil on the lid to seal it well. You can use a towel or dough as well. Seal it properly. Cook on low flame for 20 to 25 minutes.
The pot should be heavy enough so the rice or chicken doesn’t stick. If not, place a griddle underneath. Cook on low flame for 25 minutes. Turn off the stove and let it rest for 5 minutes.
Look at this wonderful aroma — it turns out very aromatic. Do try it. Look at the beautiful color. I’ll show you how each grain of rice is perfectly cooked.
Look at this — the color, aroma, and flavors are amazing. Made with basic spices available at home. Each grain is perfectly separated. The chicken is fully cooked and incredibly soft.
It’s very easy to make. Do try it. Look how soft the chicken is — fully cooked and packed with flavor.
Do try this biryani. If you liked my recipe, please like, share, and subscribe to my channel. Thank you for watching.