Greetings from Mulakkam Welcome to Tooty’s Kitchen Chennai. Today we’re going to see a very, very famous Dindigul-style Thalappakatti Mutton Biryani. We’ll make it just like how it’s served at the restaurant—guaranteed to get that authentic taste.
Now we’re going to grind a special masala. For that, take 100g of shallots. Shallots are a must for this. Then take 50g of garlic and 50g of ginger. Also, take some green chilies depending on your spice level.
Add 8 cloves, 8 cardamoms, just 1 star anise, a small piece of mace, and a small piece of nutmeg. If you have nutmeg powder, that’s fine too. Just use a little bit.
Now grind everything into a fine powder. No need to dry roast anything—just grind directly. For the mutton, we’ve taken 700g. For half a kilo of rice, use about half a kilo of mutton. You can use a bit more if you like.
Add enough water for the mutton to cook. Then add 2 teaspoons of salt. Mix everything well, pressure cook it for about 4-5 whistles until the mutton is nicely cooked. While that’s cooking, we’ll grind the masala.
When grinding, don’t add too much water. Just a little is enough to make a coarse paste—not too fine. It should look like this. Now let’s grind the garam masala as well. The aroma is so good even while grinding.
Now both our pastes are ready. Once you grind these two pastes, the biryani becomes very easy to prepare. Let’s get started. Heat 3 tablespoons of ghee in a kadai (pan).
Let it heat well for a few minutes. Now add the ground garam masala paste. Sauté this well for a few minutes too.
Now let’s check if the mutton is cooked. Yes, it’s cooked well. Drain the water and add just the mutton to the masala now.
Now roast the mutton in the oil for a few minutes until it slightly changes color. Then add chopped mint and coriander leaves. Roast this together for a few minutes as well.
Once the mutton is well roasted, add the masala powders: 1 tbsp chili powder, 1 tbsp coriander powder, and ½ tbsp cumin powder. Sauté until the raw smell goes away.
Once it reaches this stage and oil starts to separate, add 100g of curd.
Now it looks perfect. At this stage, squeeze in the juice of one lemon. For cooking the rice, measure 2 cups of water for every 1 cup of rice. I’ve used part of the water from the mutton broth and the rest as fresh water.
Personally, I feel seeraga samba rice works better than basmati for this. It cooks faster too. So always use the 1:2 rice-to-water ratio. If not, the rice won’t cook uniformly and might remain a bit hard.
Mix everything well. Once the water boils, add the soaked seeraga samba rice. Mix again and cover. Let it cook on medium flame for about 10 minutes.
After 10 minutes, open it up. The rice should be almost cooked at this stage. Now add 1 tablespoon of ghee on top.
Now close the lid and place a dosa tawa under the pan. Let it go on "dum" for 15 minutes—first 5 minutes on high flame, and the remaining 10 minutes on low flame.
After 15 minutes, it will look like this. Gently mix it once and then close it again. Turn off the heat and let it rest, covered, for another 10 minutes before opening.
Now after 10-15 minutes, we’ll open it. Look at that! The rice is perfectly cooked and fluffy. Our aromatic Thalappakatti-style Mutton Biryani is ready!
The whole house is filled with the aroma. You’ll notice the smell while cooking itself—that’s the magic of our freshly ground masalas and seeraga samba rice.
This biryani is much easier to make than other types and can be done quickly. Honestly, it turned out really well. Try it out and let me know how it came out. I hope all of you love this recipe. If you do, give us a thumbs up!