We have chopped the onions and tomatoes. Now let's prepare a paste for the biriyani. For that, we have taken 3 big pieces of ginger, 30 cloves of garlic, and 9 green chillies. Grind them all in the mixer. We have ground them finely. Now chop some coriander leaves and mint leaves for the biriyani.
We have taken a handful of coriander leaves and a portion of mint leaves. We can cut this before adding to the masala. Now we prepare the "besta" for the biriyani — finely chopped and fried big onions. This gives a special taste to Malabar biriyani. We've taken 4 onions here. Chop and fry them.
1 tsp salt. Sauté the onions on low flame until they are cooked. Now the onions are done. Add the rice. Sauté the chicken.
0.5 tbsp garam masala. (Repeated)
Five minutes have passed and the chicken is cooked well. Now remove some gravy — about half a glass. Add ¾ of the fried onions to it.
Now mix it well. Check the salt and add if needed. Now add the chicken.
Switch off the stove and keep the chicken aside. Start cooking the rice now. If you're experienced, you can cook the rice simultaneously with the chicken to keep the biriyani hot for "dum." Heat a pan. After frying the onions, use half a glass of the remaining oil. Reduce quantity if avoiding too much oil.
If the oil is hot enough, heat the chicken. It’s ready. Reduce the flame. Pour in half of the rice. Add 1 tbsp ghee. Add some of the reserved gravy.
Add half the gravy now. This helps both the chicken and rice get the same flavor. Sprinkle pistachios, cashew nuts, raisins, and a pinch of coriander leaves. Then, add the remaining rice, another tablespoon of ghee, and the remaining gravy.
Keep the stove on very low flame. Switch it off after 1 minute. Done. Let it rest until serving. You don’t need to watch continuously if you're used to cooking. People often ask how much rice and chicken to use.
1.5 kg chicken or 1 kg chicken — both quantities work.
40g cashews and 20g raisins. Adjust to your taste. If not using a non-stick pan, stir constantly after adding the ginger-garlic-green chilli paste to avoid sticking.
Store leftover biriyani in the fridge. When sautéing onion and chicken, don’t discard water from the lid — pour it back. We added rose water for aroma. Don’t overdo it. Real biriyani flavor develops only after "dum."
So our Malabar Chicken Biriyani is ready! Follow these steps for a delicious biriyani. Do try it and share your feedback. I'll see you in the next video. Bye!