Assalamualaikum everyone, how are you all? I hope you all are doing well. Welcome to my channel. Today again I’ve brought a very amazing recipe for you. Today I am making Chicken Bombay Biryani with Shan’s Special Bombay Biryani Masala.
It turns out very tangy, very spicy, and extremely delicious. I will share the entire procedure with you step-by-step. My recipe is a bit different from the one mentioned on the box. You can watch the video...
For the biryani, first I will soak the rice for half an hour. I’ve taken good-quality basmati rice here, about half a kilogram. I’ll wash them properly and then soak for 30 minutes.
Apart from that, the ingredients we’ll need include onions. I’ve taken three large-sized onions and finely sliced them. And we’ll need 3 tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste. I’ve also taken dry plums (alu bukhara)...
I’ve taken half a cup of cooking oil. You’ll need Shan’s Bombay Biryani Masala – a little more than half a pack. I’ve taken a handful of mint leaves and some coriander. Take 4-5 green chilies too.
I’m using two medium-sized potatoes – optional – if you like potatoes in your biryani, you can add them; otherwise, skip them. I’ve also taken half a kilogram of chicken and a bit of salt. Now first, in the pan...
(Filler audio, unclear) – repeated "aapko" phrases, possibly a glitch or loop in the video.
Don’t let the onions get too dark, otherwise, the gravy or korma will turn too dark in color. As soon as the onions are fried, I added the chicken, potatoes, and ginger-garlic paste. I added all these together, and now we’ll fry them.
Perfectly fried chicken is golden on the outside but juicy and soft on the inside. The tip is: when frying chicken in oil, fry it covered at intervals – you can keep covering and uncovering it with a lid.
Then fry it a little more and cover again. I do this 2–3 times. This way, the chicken turns out very soft and tender on the inside. Definitely try this trick. You will...
Along with the tomatoes, I added Shan’s Special Bombay Biryani Masala. I used half a pack plus one tablespoon. You can increase the quantity if you like spicier biryani. But for half a kg of rice...
Now again, I’m mixing it a little, and after mixing, I’ll cover it for 5–7 minutes so the tomatoes soften well. After that, we’ll sauté it (do the “bhunai”).
The tomatoes softened nicely, and then I fried it for 3–4 more minutes. At this stage, I’ll remove all the cardamom. Cardamom doesn’t taste good when it comes into the mouth while eating biryani.
Apart from that, I’ve added dry plums (alu bukhara). I love them in biryani. If you don’t, you can skip them or add tamarind instead. Now again we’ll add yogurt and dry plums...
...in a wide vessel so the rice turns out fluffy and separate. I added around 2 liters of water in the wide vessel. I’ve added salt. You need to add a bit more salt than usual because the rice...
So I’ve added salt. I also added one stick of cinnamon, one teaspoon of white vinegar, and a handful of mint leaves. Then I waited for it to come to a boil. Once it started boiling, I added the rice.
Now the next process is very simple – we’ll do the biryani layering. First, I added the masala in the pot, and then I added a layer of rice. On top of that goes the chicken layer. I’m doing a single layer here...
Mint, mint, mint, mint, mint, mint, mint, mint, mint. (Likely showing repeated addition of mint leaves visually.)
If the bottom of your pot is thick, you don’t need to put a tawa (griddle) under it. But if the bottom is not that thick... (repeats for emphasis or clarification)
Each grain of rice is separate and fluffy. The taste of this biryani is amazing – absolutely delicious. Just like the biryani you get at restaurants – tangy, spicy, and full of flavor – that’s how it turns out with Shan’s Special Bombay Biryani Masala.
So this was my video for today. I hope you liked it. If you did, then like, share, and subscribe to my channel. And don’t forget to give the video a thumbs-up. InshaAllah, I’ll see you in the next video. Take good care of yourself and remember me in your prayers.