This Mogalpur chicken has a crisp, sizzling sound.
This is full of love.
Sometimes, you just feel like making a rich dish at home.
This is how Mogalpur style is.
This is early morning—woke up and made chicken curry. Don’t ask why. People comment a lot, saying to make chicken biryani.
Everyone loves biryani. It's like they were born for it. Even if it’s not your birthday, biryani feels like a celebration.
Everyone celebrates with biryani like it’s a tradition.
In the market, you’ll find chickens weighing 3-4 kg, but we should buy around 2 kg for proper biryani.
When we ask in restaurants, they give small pieces because they divide the chicken into 3-4 pieces per plate.
In our region, we marinate the chicken properly. After a couple of hours, it becomes tender and full of flavor.
Add chili powder and mix well. Don’t just sprinkle it on top; coat the chicken properly.
Now, when we eat the pieces, they should taste delicious.
At home, add green chilies, mint, and a bit more spices for extra flavor.
Don't add too much garam masala. Just a little cumin and coriander powder is enough.
Use good oil. A little cumin and coriander powder is enough to bring out the taste.
Once it’s cooked well, it smells amazing.
We usually see large setups in hotels, but I’m showing you a simple homemade method using curd.
We’ll marinate it simply with curd and basic spices.
Once rice is boiled once, drain the water. It should be semi-cooked before layering.
Add salt accordingly and boil the rice until it’s 70% done.
Boil it until it's semi-soft so it finishes cooking with steam.
Once boiled, strain it well. Prepare for layering now.
Chicken should be 70% cooked before layering.
Put the chicken at the bottom of the pot. Add a small bowl of rice in layers.
Add all masalas evenly.
The pot should be heavy-bottomed.
Make sure the rice inside is also half-cooked.
Water should be in proper ratio.
Use 4 cups of water for 1 cup of rice.
That’s when it cooks perfectly.
Now, layer everything and close the lid.
Once it's 70% done, lower the flame and seal the pot.
Steam it well. That’s how biryani cooks through. Don’t overcook the rice.
Aromatic smell will spread—chicken, mint, onions, all come together beautifully.
Layer rice without breaking the grains.
Top it with mint, remaining onions, and a bit of ghee for flavor.
Don't add too much oil. Just enough to enhance the taste.
Now place a heavy lid. Some use flour paste to seal it tight. Do what suits you.
Steam builds up inside. After 10 minutes, let it come out slowly.
Don't lift the lid too early. Let the steam settle first.
Now keep the flame high for 10 minutes for final cooking.
Then reduce heat. Meanwhile, I’ll tell a story—once, I took biryani to school…
Everyone was amazed. They asked who made it. My dad said, “My son made this.”
Back then, I’d fill the house with the biryani smell. Now things have changed.
When people argue, they say, "Let’s get divorced."
Instead, I say, “Come, let’s eat biryani and talk.”
I say this often—but today, my wife isn’t around. I’ll tell her next time.
Use a flat heavy lid. Place weight on top to trap steam.
If it looks a bit raw, leave it to dry slightly. Let the water evaporate fully.
This is our homemade chicken biryani. Just look at it—perfect texture and aroma.
Don’t just eat it randomly. There's a way to eat biryani too.
See this here? That’s mace flower—called javitri.
If you eat it whole, it’s bitter. Remove it before eating.
The fragrance is amazing. We use whole spices like cloves, cardamom, peppercorns.
When you serve biryani, mix it slightly before serving. Don’t leave it tight-packed.
My mom doesn’t like this type of biryani. But whenever I eat it, I remember my hometown.
Even on Sundays, when we’d go out and have this, I would return home and make it for my family.
Now I live abroad. But I still have permission to make biryani!