Welcome to Taste of Chennai! Our channel has already tried many types of biryani. Today, we're going to see how to make Ambur Chicken Biryani. Unlike other biryanis, this one doesn't take too much time and the ingredients are quite minimal. So it's perfect for beginners and bachelors.
Here, I’ve taken 15 green chilies. You can adjust according to your spice level. Soak them in hot water for a bit and then grind them into a paste like this. I'm making half a kilo of biryani, so I’m using seeraga samba rice.
Coriander and mint leaves—just half a bunch each is enough. Now in a pan, I'm adding 2 tablespoons of ghee and 100 ml of oil. Once the oil is hot, we can add bay leaf, cloves, and cardamom—3 pieces of bay leaf, 10 cloves, and 10 cardamoms.
But don’t add all the spices now—just a small portion. We’ll add the rest at the end. Many people ask why onions are added twice in Ambur biryani. That’s the traditional method. Sauté the onions for about 5 minutes.
Once the raw smell of the ginger-garlic paste goes away, we can add the chicken. Cook the chicken for 5–10 minutes until the color changes and it starts to roast well in the ghee. At this stage, add the mint and coriander leaves and sauté them well.
Now that the chicken is well sautéed in the masala, we can add the onions. In every biryani, the onions are usually fried to a golden brown color, which takes 30 minutes. But in this recipe, we are not going to do it that way.
This is how Ambur biryani is made. Next, we’ll add tomatoes. Now let the onions and tomatoes cook down nicely. Wait until the tomatoes become soft and mushy. To help them cook faster, we’ll cover it now.
Now let’s cover and cook it for about 10 minutes. After that, we can check. The tomatoes are nicely mashed now. Next, we’ll add the red chili paste that we ground earlier. Cook this until the raw smell goes away.
Next, we’ll add about half a cup of curd. Mix it in well. Once you see the oil separating, it’s time to add water to cook the rice. I used 1¼ cups of water for every cup of rice. I’m using 3 cups of rice.
Now we can add the soaked rice. I soaked it for half an hour. Mix it all well and check that the salt is right. Cover and let it cook for 10–15 minutes before opening.
The rice is now cooked well. At this stage, we can place a pan or plate at the bottom and put the biryani pot on top of it, then place a heavy vessel on top. Now let it dum (slow cook) for 15 minutes on low heat.
Let it dum for another 20 minutes. After that, you can open and serve. Now let’s see how our Ambur Biryani has turned out. Wow! The Ambur biryani looks perfect, with a great aroma, and the rice is well separated.
You too should try making it like this. Try making it like this. Try making it like this. Just like this!
We hope everyone will love this recipe. If you liked it, hit the like button and share it with your friends. For more such great recipes, don’t forget to subscribe to our Taste of Chennai channel. Tomorrow, we’ll bring you another super recipe!