Ambur Chicken Biryani, Ambur Chicken Biryani
Before starting the recipe, a small request to all of you. Below my video, you’ll see “Subscribe” written in red—please press that. As soon as you do, you’ll see a bell icon—press that too.
To make Ambur Chicken Biryani, first wash the rice thoroughly and soak it. A special rice is used in this biryani. It's called Seeraga Samba rice. It has a very nice aroma.
You’ll find this rice in any supermarket. If it’s not available, you can also make biryani with normal Sona Masoori or Basmati rice. But if you do get this rice, the biryani turns out even better because of its fragrance.
I’ve washed the rice well. Let’s now soak it for 15 minutes. I’ve taken 500 grams, or half a kilo, of Seeraga Samba rice. After soaking the rice, next we’ll prepare red chili paste.
After 15 minutes, once the chilies are soft, grind them into a fine paste using a mixer jar. Use a small jar—if you use a big one, it won’t grind properly. Your spicy red chili paste is ready.
Now lightly sauté it. Keep the flame on high. Next, add finely chopped onions—3 large ones. Fry them until they turn golden brown. Keep the flame high. As you can see, the onions are turning golden brown.
Red chili paste, red chili paste, red chili paste, red chili paste, red chili paste, red chili paste.
Cut the chicken pieces to medium or slightly larger size. After adding the chicken, sauté it well with the spices. Keep the flame on medium. Ambur Chicken Biryani is a very famous dish in South India, especially in Tamil Nadu.
After sautéing the chicken with the masalas for 1 to 2 minutes on flame, turn the flame off. Now add 4 tablespoons of curd (yogurt). Beat the curd well before adding. We turn off the flame to avoid curdling while adding.
Add ginger paste. After adding, sauté again. Try following my method—you’ll end up with such a delicious biryani, you'll lick your fingers!
You will find all types of biryani recipes, you will find all types of biryani recipes, you will find all types of biryani recipes, you will find all types of biryani recipes, you will find all types of biryani recipes.
After adding tomatoes, continue sautéing until they become soft. Stir occasionally. Keep the flame low and cover with a lid. The tomatoes are now soft. Finally, add lemon juice.
Add 500 ml water and mix well. At this stage, check the salt—if it feels less, add a little more. Add some chopped coriander leaves too. I’ve taken slightly more than half a kilo of chicken—so you might see 1–2 extra pieces.
Once it starts cooking nicely, cover with a lid and keep the flame on low. Cook the chicken until it’s 80–90% done, then turn off the flame.
There should be a little gravy left because we’ll only boil the Seeraga Samba rice till 80–90% cooked. After boiling, we’ll mix it in and cook it on dum (steam). During dum, the masalas will blend beautifully into the rice.
Check the water—if it’s boiling well, add the soaked rice.
After adding rice, mix well. Cook until the rice is 80–90% done. As you can see, it’s almost cooked. There is extra water—so strain it.
Now layer the boiled rice on top of the chicken masala. Mix it very gently, or the rice might break.
After gently mixing, drizzle 2 teaspoons of ghee on top. Add some chopped coriander and mint leaves. Keep the flame on high. Now cover with a lid. After covering...
We will cook the biryani on low flame for 30 minutes on dum. Don’t forget to place a tawa (griddle) underneath, otherwise the bottom might burn. The tawa is essential. You can also seal the pan edges with dough so the steam doesn’t escape.
This way, the biryani will cook perfectly on dum, and the masala will infuse beautifully into the rice. Let it sit undisturbed for half an hour. It’s been 30 minutes, let’s open the lid. See, our biryani has turned out amazing.
Let’s plate it now.
If you enjoyed today’s delicious Ambur Chicken Biryani recipe, please subscribe to my channel “Cook with Fame.” Don’t forget to press the bell icon. Like this video, share it as much as possible, and don’t forget to comment. Assalamu Alaikum.