Hello Friends, Welcome to my channel Cook with Tabu. Today I’m sharing with you all the recipe of Bangalore’s famous Chicken Donne Biryani.
This biryani is quite popular in Bangalore, and in restaurants, it is served in bowls made from palm tree leaves, which are called "donne." So let’s see what ingredients we need to make this tasty and easy biryani.
Its taste is even better than basmati rice. We will use a large chopped tomato, 1 cup mint leaves, 1 cup coriander, 10–12 green chilies, ½ cup yogurt (about 100 grams). For whole spices: 1 tsp cumin, 2 bay leaves...
10 whole black peppers, and 2 star anise (also called badiyan phool). We also need 3 large onions, finely sliced, 1 cup oil, 1 tsp turmeric powder, 3½ tsp salt, and 1 tsp garam masala powder.
First, we will marinate the chicken. Wash it well and add 1 tsp salt, 1 tsp turmeric powder, 1 tsp ginger-garlic paste, and ½ cup yogurt. Mix everything well and let the chicken rest for an hour.
We’ll use the remaining salt and ginger-garlic paste while making the biryani. In a blender jar, add coriander, mint leaves, and green chilies to make a paste. In some places, fenugreek leaves are also used in this paste...
As you can see, the paste is coarse after grinding. Now add a little water and make it into a fine paste. Wash the rice well, add water, and let it soak for half an hour.
Put a pot on the stove and add 1 cup oil. Heat the oil well. Once hot, add whole spices and roast them for 10–15 seconds. Now add the sliced onions...
You can see the onions have turned golden brown. Now add ginger-garlic paste and sauté it for a minute to remove the raw smell. I have roasted the paste well for a minute. Now add the chopped...
Now add the marinated chicken and cook it on high flame for 5 minutes. After 5 minutes of cooking the chicken well, add garam masala powder, coriander powder, and the green paste we prepared. Mix everything well.
Now cover it and cook for another 5 minutes so that all the spices are cooked well. I measured the rice with this glass — two glasses — and I will measure water using the same glass.
You can see that the masala is well cooked. Now I will use 3 glasses of water, measured with the same glass I used for rice. For these rice, we need to use water in a 2:1 ratio — that is, two glasses of water for one glass of rice.
Now I’m adding 2½ tsp salt. We already used 1 tsp salt while marinating the chicken. Now add lemon juice and mix well. Cover and cook until the water comes to a boil. Meanwhile, the rice we soaked...
You can see the water is boiling. Carefully add the soaked rice and mix gently. Since the water is hot, be careful while adding rice to avoid splashes. Stir once and cover again...
After 5 minutes, I mixed the rice again so that it doesn't stick to the bottom. You can see that the rice has absorbed all the water and only about 10% water is left.
Now we’ll cook the biryani on "dum" (steam). But before that, I’ve added 2 tsp ghee for extra flavor. This is optional — you can skip it if you like. For dum, I’m using an aluminum...
For dum, place a tawa (griddle) on the stove and place the biryani pot on it. Cook on low flame for 15 minutes. After 15 minutes, turn off the flame but let it rest for another 5–10 minutes.
You can see the rice and chicken are perfectly cooked and this biryani turns out very tasty. Serve it hot with raita.
I’m serving this Donne Biryani in palm leaf bowls — just like in restaurants. Even if you don’t have these, you can serve it on any plate. You can enjoy this biryani for lunch or dinner.
Do try this Donne Biryani recipe and don’t forget to give me feedback. If you liked this recipe, please like the video, share it, and please subscribe to my channel. Also, don’t forget to press the bell icon.