Hello everyone, welcome back to our channel Kashmir Food Fusion. Click the subscribe button and press the bell icon to stay updated.
Today we'll show you how to make mutton biryani at home. This biryani tastes like restaurant-style, and you can see the vibrant colors in it. This recipe turns out very tasty.
If you're interested, I'll leave the link in the description box for where you can buy the ingredients. Sela rice is mostly used for biryani and pulao.
We’ve taken one kilogram of mutton with bones. Then we have taken five large onions, finely chopped. We've used mustard oil, crushed garlic...
Then we have green chilies, black pepper, red chili powder, and salt.
Ginger-garlic paste, or you can use only garlic. Cumin seeds, cinnamon sticks, and nutmeg. Nutmeg is essential for biryani. I’ll leave a link below.
Mace is also essential for biryani. I’ll link it below. We’re also using kewra water. All of these are used in biryani: turmeric, black cardamom...
Coriander powder, and fennel powder. We’ve used oil, but you can use ghee. Then bay leaves and saffron. First, we’ll heat mustard oil in a pan until it’s hot and smoking.
Keep some oil aside for later. We've fried the onions. In a mixer grinder, add 1 tsp cumin seeds, 2 bay leaves, 2 black cardamoms...
1 cinnamon stick, 1 nutmeg, 2 pieces of mace. Make a fine powder—this is the biryani masala we'll use for cooking.
Now let’s marinate the mutton. Place the washed meat in a large bowl. Add 1 tsp turmeric...
1 tbsp red chili powder, salt to taste, 2 tbsp of the biryani masala we just made...
Add 250 grams of thick curd (whisk it before adding). Then 3 tbsp finely chopped coriander, and mint...
Mix it well. Add one cup of the fried onions we prepared earlier. Crush them and mix into the marinade.
Cover and let it marinate for 30 minutes. Meanwhile, we’ll prepare the rice. In a pot of water, add 15 black peppercorns, 7–8 cloves, 1 tbsp of the biryani masala...
Boil the water with all these spices.
Once it starts boiling, add the washed sela rice. We didn’t soak the rice beforehand as it cooks quickly when added to boiling water.
Drain the rice and spread it out on a tray or strainer to cool. You can remove any visible whole spices.
Put the marinated meat into a pressure cooker and cook it 90% through. Add a little water, not too much. Don’t fully cook it, only 90%, as this is not raw meat-style biryani.
After 2–3 whistles, it should be ready. Cooking time depends on the quality of meat. Now in a pan, we’ll start layering.
First, a layer of cooked mutton at the bottom. Then spread a layer of rice evenly on top.
Pour some of the curry over the rice so the color and flavor spread well. Then another layer of rice goes on top.
Drizzle milk in some places for color. You can also use food coloring optionally in a few spots.
Now we’ll put it on dum (steam cook). You can seal with a cloth or dough. First cook on high flame for 3 minutes, then lower the heat.
You can see the rice grains are fluffy, not broken, and not sticking together. The color looks great. The meat is soft and well-cooked.
Let me show you how to garnish it. You can use a slicer to cut onions into rings. You can use a knife, but the slicer gives better thin rings.
You can garnish it however you like.