Hello! Welcome to Chef Dheenathayalan’s Kitchen. Today in our kitchen, we’re going to see how to make Dindigul-style Thalapakatti Biryani.
Dindigul biryani is made using seeraga samba rice. When I was in Alangulam and See Thambi, I made Dindigul biryani in a pressure cooker. Many of you have seen it and given great comments. I’ve come back with another superb biryani.
This recipe I know is in a fantastic style—truly amazing. Let’s definitely see how it’s made. I’ve ground small onions into a paste and set it aside. Then I’ve taken whole garam masala—about 30 grams. You might wonder why 30 grams?
For the Thalapakatti Dindigul Chicken Biryani, the required ingredients are: 600 grams chicken, 600 grams seeraga samba rice, 2 large onions, 35 small onions (about 100 grams), 180 grams tomato, 6–8 green chilies, 100 tablespoons ginger garlic paste.
Whole garam masala for tempering, ¾ tsp chili powder, a handful of coriander leaves, a handful of mint leaves, 100 ml curd, 1 lemon, salt as needed.
150 ml oil, 3 tablespoons ghee. Whole garam masala (30 grams) includes cinnamon, cloves, cardamom, star anise—keep 30 grams ready. These are the ingredients required. Let’s get into the preparation for the biryani.
While soaking the seeraga samba rice, many people make a mistake. This rice must always be soaked properly. Some say half an hour, some say one hour. But don’t do it randomly. When you start the preparation, soak it at the correct time, so the rice doesn’t get overcooked.
I’ve taken exactly 30 grams of whole garam masala. Why 30 grams? Because when you grind it, that amount is ideal. That’s why I’ve taken 30 grams and ground it into powder.
See this powder? When you grind it like this and keep it ready, your biryani preparation becomes perfect. As for the small onions—I've used 35 of them. You might wonder why exactly 35...
This whole garam masala—cinnamon, cloves, mace, cardamom—is added for tempering. Then add both types of onions (small and big), totaling around 200 grams. Next, add green chilies. I used green chilies...
So I’m telling you clearly—first sauté about 30% of the large onions, then add the small onions and cook until about 50–60% done. After that, add the ground ginger garlic paste. For this preparation, two tablespoons of ginger garlic paste are used.
Now I’ve added coriander and mint leaves.
After that, I’ve added 100 ml of curd. If the curd is too sour, you can reduce it slightly. Use curd depending on its sourness. I had slightly sour curd, so I used 100 ml. Then add chili powder and salt. That completes the masala base.
Now I’ve added the chicken. After adding the chicken, sauté for 2 minutes. Add just enough water depending on how much is needed, and continue the preparation.
You might ask how much water to add. For one cup of seeraga samba rice, use 1.75 cups of water. Many people have asked me not to say “just enough water”—so I’m clearly saying 1.75 cups.
Now pour the water, cover with a lid, and once it comes to a boil, add the rice. But before that, you must be cautious and attentive to ensure it cooks correctly.
After that, I’ve added the soaked rice. When to close the lid and put it on dum (slow steam cooking)? When the rice is about 50–60% cooked. Then cover it and cook on dum. At that point, squeeze lemon juice and add it.
At this stage, reduce the heat to low. After the rice is 50–60% cooked, add a little ghee, coriander, and mint again to enhance flavor.
Cook on dum for 20–25 minutes. Now look at this biryani—it has turned out amazing in this style. I’ve shown you how to make authentic Dindigul Thalapakatti-style biryani. Give it a try.
Now everyone knows how to make Dindigul biryani using seeraga samba rice. I’ve shown it clearly. Definitely try it out and don’t forget to give your feedback. Also follow me on Instagram and Facebook for more such recipes.