Hello everyone! Welcome back to another video. I'm Priscila Benjamin. When it comes to biryani, almost every region has its own variety. Today, I'm sharing a Kerala special — Thalassery Biryani. The taste is incredible, so let’s get started and check out the recipe!
For this recipe, I’ve taken 2 glasses of Jeerakasala rice, also known as Kaima rice. Wash and soak it for 10 minutes. I’ve also taken 1 kg of chicken. For better flavor, I’m going to marinate the chicken. To that, add some salt.
Add 1 tsp turmeric powder, 1 tsp chilli powder, 1 tsp pepper powder, 1 tsp ginger-garlic paste, and 2 tbsp curd. Mix it all together and let it rest for 30 minutes.
Next, for frying — in a pan, add 1 tsp ghee and 4 tbsp oil. Once it heats up, add thinly sliced onions and fry them until light golden brown. Once fried, remove and set aside. In the same oil, fry cashew nuts and raisins.
Once they are golden and puffed, remove and set aside. In a pot, add 4 glasses of water — for 2 glasses of rice. Add whole spices like bay leaf, cloves, and cardamom, plus salt and ½ tsp ghee. Let it come to a boil.
Once the water starts boiling, add the soaked rice. Mix, cover with a lid, and cook. Once the rice is done, set it aside. Now let’s prepare the chicken masala. In a kadai, add 3 tsp ghee.
Once hot, add whole spices — a small piece of cinnamon, cardamom, bay leaf, star anise, and cloves. Sauté for a few minutes. Add 3 thinly sliced onions and salt. Sauté until they turn light brown.
Add 1½ tsp ginger-garlic paste and 2 tsp green chilli paste. Adjust chillies according to your spice level. Sauté well.
Add ¼ tsp nutmeg powder, ½ tsp pepper powder, 1½ tsp chicken masala, and 1 tsp biryani masala. Sauté until the raw smell disappears. Then, add 2 sliced tomatoes and mix well.
Add a little water and cook until the tomatoes are soft and mushy.
Now, add the marinated chicken. Mix well and cook for about 10 minutes.
Once the chicken masala is ready, add some crushed fried onions and chopped coriander leaves. Mix everything together.
Now let’s dum cook the biryani. In a thick-bottomed pot, first add a little ghee. Then spread a layer of chicken masala evenly. Next, add a layer of cooked rice and spread it evenly.
On top, add some fried onions, cashew nuts, coriander leaves, and mint leaves. Sprinkle some garam masala powder and drizzle a few drops of ghee.
Repeat the layering — chicken masala, coriander and mint leaves, followed by the remaining rice. Spread it evenly.
Add another layer of fried onions, coriander, and mint leaves. Sprinkle garam masala and add a few drops of ghee. I'm adding one more layer of chicken masala now.
Top with the remaining rice. Sprinkle some garam masala and fried onions.
Add cashew nuts, coriander, and mint leaves. Finally, drizzle a few drops of ghee. Cover the pot with aluminum foil. If you don’t have foil, seal the pot using wheat flour or maida dough. Dum it for 10 minutes.
After 10 minutes, open the pot — and there you go! Delicious Thalassery Biryani is ready to serve. The taste is incredible and it’s a must-try! If you liked this recipe, like and share it. And if you haven’t subscribed yet, consider subscribing. See you in the next video. Until then, take care and bye!