Hello friends, we are at Chef Madhu's Kitchen — your Chef Martin. Today at Chef Madhu’s Kitchen, we are going to see a superb dish: Dindigul Thalappakatti Chicken Biryani. You all know how famous this biryani is in Tamil Nadu.
There are two secrets in this recipe. The first one is these bay leaves and cardamoms — roast them slowly, make it into a powder and use it. That’s the first secret. The second one, if you look at it...
...this has its own secret and specialty. I'll tell you many such things at home — watch till the end. Ingredients needed for Thalappakatti Biryani: 1 kg seeraga samba rice, 1 kg country chicken, 50g onions, small shallots...
...half a bunch of coriander leaves, 3 bay leaves, 3 cinnamon sticks, 10 cloves, 5g cardamom, 1 tbsp fennel seeds, 1 tbsp coriander powder, 1 tbsp chili powder, 1 tsp turmeric powder, 200g curd, 50g ghee...
To make the biryani masala powder: use about 10–15 cardamoms, 3 cinnamon sticks — for other biryanis just 1 stick is enough, but here we need 3, because Dindigul Biryani...
No oil should be used here. Roast it slowly like this. No other ingredients are needed. This is a simple masala. Roast it nicely — see how it’s turning out — then we'll powder it well.
Now we’ll powder it. No need to grind it too much — just a light coarse powder will do. If it's powdered too much, the taste will be too strong. This level of coarse grinding is enough.
Next is the base paste for Dindigul Thalappakatti Biryani. Take 150g of shallots, 10 green chilies, 80g of ginger, 80g of garlic. We’ll grind this into a raw paste.
I didn’t peel the garlic; I used it whole with the skin, because the skin gives a unique aroma. I’ve added mint leaves to it — that aroma is crucial.
Now we’re ready to make the biryani. Everything is ready. We’re all set to make the biryani now.
After it's well roasted, add the mint. Then the oil, a little at a time... (repeating)
Add the paste and sauté it well for about 7 minutes on medium flame. You can see the raw smell leaving and the color changing.
You can see the oil separating out — that means the masala is cooked. Once you see oil at the edges, your masala is ready.
In this biryani, we don’t use tomatoes. Other biryanis might include tomatoes, but this one doesn’t. Now mix everything well and add salt as needed. Add the ground biryani masala.
After adding the biryani masala, the aroma is amazing. Mix it well and add just 1 tsp turmeric — don’t add too much, just 1 tsp is enough.
Mix it well. Now add coriander powder — just 1 tablespoon. Then add 200 ml curd. Don't add too much curd — otherwise the gravy will become too watery.
Add chili powder — see how beautiful the color looks now. All masalas are added. Add some mint again. I often say, step-by-step mint gives flavor.
Next step is to add the rice. You know what? Add the rice, add the rice, add the rice... (repeated emphasis)
Now close and let it cook for about 10 minutes. After 10 minutes, you’ll see the boiling start — lightly mix it to check how well the chicken has cooked. It should be around 70% done.
Always make sure the water isn't too thick. Only if it's watery enough will the rice cook properly and absorb everything. If it’s too thick, it won’t work right.
After mixing, cover it and cook for 5–6 minutes. After 5 minutes, check — the rice will be about 50% cooked. You can already see it.
Why do we mix the rice now? So it doesn’t stick to the bottom. We should not open it fully either, as the steam will escape.
Now the water is almost absorbed. The texture is now just right for dum (slow cooking). Let’s now drizzle in about 50ml of ghee. Add as much as you prefer.
Coriander and mint, coriander and mint, coriander and mint... (repeated emphasis)
After 15 minutes, the rice is beautifully cooked. You can see how perfect it looks — we’re showing you a mix now. The aroma is simply amazing.
Look how fluffy and separate the rice grains are. If the water level is perfect, the rice cooks beautifully and the biryani turns out just right — like in a restaurant.
See how soft it is when we lift it. Just serve it with raita and onion salad — this will be excellent. A delicious Dindigul Thalappakatti Biryani is ready.
Friends, now you know how tasty and superb this Dindigul Thalappakatti Chicken Biryani is. Definitely try it at home and share your version with us. Earlier, I made a Mysore Biryani...