Assalamu Alaikum. Today, we’re going to share a very amazing, very easy, and colorful recipe with you — Kashmiri Biryani. I'm going to show you a style of Kashmiri Biryani you've probably never eaten or made before.
It’s going to be delicious. If you enjoy this recipe, please like and share it, subscribe to our YouTube channel, and don’t forget to press the bell icon — it’s absolutely free — so you don't miss any of my good recipes.
We’ve taken two onions. We’ll add them and lightly brown them. Once golden, we’ll add 1 kg of chicken and fry it. The chicken will also be lightly golden.
We’ll fry the chicken for about 5 to 10 minutes. Add two spoons of ginger-garlic paste. I’ve chopped three tomatoes like this, and we’ll add them too. Let the tomatoes soften.
The tomatoes are soft now. Add spices: half a teaspoon turmeric powder, one spoon red chili, two spoons biryani masala, one spoon salt, and half a teaspoon cumin seeds. Sauté the spices for 2-3 minutes.
Add half a cup of yogurt. It enhances the biryani’s taste. Cook until the water from the yogurt dries out. Then add half a liter of water so the chicken cooks well.
Cover and cook until the water evaporates and the chicken is tender. Meanwhile, we’ll boil the rice. I’ve taken 2 liters of water and 1 kg of rice, soaked for 10 minutes. Add 1 spoon cumin, 1.5...
Boil the rice up to 70%. Cover it. It took about 4-5 minutes. Now we’ll drain the water and prepare for layering the rice.
Now we’ll layer the chicken we prepared earlier. Then we’ll add a layer of rice over it.
The chicken layer is done. Now the final rice layer. I’ve cooled the rice with cold water so they don’t stick together. Add 2-3 spoons of raisins on top.
Add one spoon of chopped coconut, 10-12 almonds with skins removed, and a pinch each of yellow, red, and green food coloring.
We haven’t turned on the flame yet. We’ve boiled 4 eggs. Slice two eggs and place them on top; reserve the other two for garnish. Now turn on the flame, cover it, and let it cook for 8 to 10 minutes.
Reduce the flame to low. The steam has risen to the top. We’ve let it simmer for 10-12 minutes. Now we’ll mix it carefully and turn off the flame. Gently fold everything together.
Now we’ll plate it.
You can see how beautiful and colorful it looks. The Kashmiri Biryani turned out very tasty. Definitely try it out. If you liked the recipe, please like and share it, subscribe to our channel