As-salamu alaykum. In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. A special recipe for a special occasion. Eid is near, so let’s make a delicious original degi Sindhi Biryani, as requested.
Avoid packaged spice mixes for this Eid. We’ll make a tasty degi Sindhi Biryani with fresh spices, just like in big pots, with great aroma and flavor, using an easy method. Let’s start the recipe.
I’m using Falak brand rice, but you can also use sela rice. Wash the rice well and soak in clean water for about 15 minutes.
Since it’s Sindhi Biryani, I’ll boil the potatoes. I’ve taken 5 medium-sized potatoes, peeled, cleaned, and cut one into two pieces as per degi style.
Now moving on, either take a pressure cooker for quicker biryani or an open pot like I use. Add one cup of oil or melted ghee. Slice five medium onions.
We’ll use these fried onions while layering biryani. Add a little water to stop browning, spread on a tissue to dry, and keep aside.
Now for the meat: I’m using 1.25 kg of goat meat with bone for richer flavor. Add ginger garlic paste.
Add 5–6 green cardamoms, 1 tbsp whole white cumin, 3 black cardamoms, 2 star anise, and small cinnamon sticks.
Add 1 tbsp crushed red chili, ½ tsp turmeric, and 1 tbsp salt (adjust to taste), and ½ tbsp ground spices.
Chicken powder is essential; I use Dashi brand. Add 3 medium chopped tomatoes. Skip chicken powder if desired.
Add ½ cup yogurt and 7–8 dried plums. Add 4 chopped green chilies or 1 tbsp paste.
Fry this mixture well to enhance the aroma and taste. Frying removes any meat smell.
Add 3½ glasses of water for the meat to tenderize. Add ¼ tsp yellow food color for authentic degi biryani look.
Cover the pot and simmer on low heat for 1 to 1¼ hours until meat is soft. Prepare the fresh herb mix for layering.
Add ½ tsp homemade saffron garam masala, ¼ tsp mace powder, ¼ tsp nutmeg powder, and ½ tsp chaat masala.
Add chopped coriander and mint. Save some for the final layering. Mix well; herb mix is ready.
Set aside the herb mix. The meat has cooked well over 1.5 hours. It’s perfectly tender now.
Mix the curry and potatoes so they absorb flavor. Now add the prepared herb mix.
Move the masala to the side of the pot to avoid burning. Keep meat, potatoes, and masala to the side.
Add 1.5 tbsp oil on top of the curry. The korma is ready. Now let’s boil the rice.
In boiling water, add 1 tbsp cumin, 1 black cardamom, 6–7 cloves, 2 bay leaves, 1 small cinnamon stick, and 10–12 black pepper.
Boil the rice on high heat until slightly undercooked—only 3–5 minutes. Start the timer when water boils.
Check if rice is long and soft with a slight bite. That’s the sign to stop.
Now layer all the rice on top of the curry. Add dark yellow food color for tri-color look. Add fried onions.
Let it steam for 15 minutes. The aroma is amazing. Karachi-style degi Sindhi biryani is ready!
I used to serve biryani in this platter. Today I felt like using it again. It looks amazing!
If you’ve never succeeded before, try this recipe. You won’t even touch packet spices again.