Today we're going to see how to make Thalassery Chicken Biryani. First, we'll prepare the Bista, which means fried onions. I’ve taken one large onion, sliced thin. Also, 1 tbsp raisins and 8 cashew nuts. You can use more if desired.
1 tsp pepper powder, 2 tsp fennel seeds, 1 tsp cumin, 8 cardamoms, 2 dried red chillies, 2 pieces of cinnamon, 10 cloves of garlic.
1 tbsp tomato, 1 tsp black cumin (shah jeera), 3 red chilies, 2 inches cinnamon. Roast and grind all together. Use Jeerakasala or Khaima rice. If unavailable, basmati is fine.
[No spoken content – music or filler visuals]
3.25 kg chicken, 2 medium onions, 2 medium tomatoes, 8 green chilies.
3 tbsp ginger garlic paste, 1 tbsp lemon juice, ½ tbsp milk, ½ tbsp water.
1¼ tsp turmeric, a handful of mint, a handful of coriander. Dry roast the masala.
Add asafoetida. Roast for 2 minutes on low flame.
Turn off the flame and stir for a bit. Let cool and grind. Masala is ready. Now fry the onions in oil.
Fry them well in sunflower oil. Ghee can be used for more flavor. I’m double frying. Double frying needs more oil. Once crisp, transfer to a plate. Now fry cashews and raisins.
Don’t over-fry raisins – just until they puff. Set aside. Crush half the onions (bista) to add to the chicken masala. The rest will be used for garnish.
Add 1.5 tbsp dalda and 1 tbsp ghee.
[Unclear language – assumed preparation of ginger, garlic, and chilies]
[Unclear language or visuals only – assumed continued prep]
Now the chicken is soft and well-cooked. Add 1 tbsp lemon juice. Mix and continue to cook uncovered to reduce the gravy.
Add crushed fried onions and mix. Check for salt and adjust if needed.
[No spoken content – filler visuals]
[Repeated “3”s – unclear, likely filler or visual annotation]
Mix well and close the lid. Cook rice till 75% done. Now add chicken masala to the biryani dum layer. Don’t add too much.
[Unclear language – possibly repeating steps about layering or cooking]
[No meaningful speech – unclear section]
Add remaining rice. Garnish with onions, cashew nuts, and raisins. Sprinkle 2 pinches of masala powder.
Add 1½ tbsp ghee and 1½ tsp rose water. Place biryani over a heated dosa tawa. Cover tightly with foil and a lid to seal the steam.
[Repetitive phrase – likely filler or chant while dum cooking]
Now mix everything well. Lift chicken from bottom, spread masala, and then top with rice.
Don’t forget to like, share, and subscribe.