To make biryani, first place a pan and pour in some oil. Once the oil heats up, add about six cloves, cardamom, and six pieces of cinnamon like this. Then take about two bay leaves. Next, add about three large onions. Sauté the onions well at this stage.
Add ginger-garlic paste and sauté. Then, I’ve taken three tomatoes. Let’s cook those well. Now, I’ve taken about seven green chilies and roasted them slightly. Now we can grind them. For Ambur biryani, we grind the chilies and—
You can see the tomatoes have cooked well. Now, let’s add the ground paste. Grind them to a fine consistency like this. Add three tablespoons of curd/yogurt. After adding the curd, we need about 750 grams of chicken.
Add mint and coriander leaves as well. Take a handful of each and mix them in. Mix everything well and let it sauté for 5 minutes. Let it sauté thoroughly for 5 minutes.
For one cup of rice, I’ve added 750 grams of chicken and 1.5 cups of water. Let it come to a boil. Once it starts boiling, we’ll add the rice. It has started boiling nicely, see? At this stage, I’ve added one slit green chili.
Next, add the required amount of salt and mix well. Let the water level balance properly with the rice. Once that’s done, we can place it on "dum" (slow cooking). The water level is just right now. Let’s go ahead and place it on dum.
After placing it on dum, the flame should not be too low. It should be on a medium simmer. The pan should be nice and hot, and then you can simmer it. After about 5 minutes, that’s it. You can take the rice from the bottom and bring it to the top. Now for the dum—
We’re covering it with a banana leaf. I’ve taken a weight to place on top of it because we’re using the banana leaf, and it should be sealed tightly like this with weight.
Once that’s done, leave it on low flame for 15 minutes. Keep the flame as low as possible for 15 minutes. After that, we can check. 15 minutes are up—let’s open and check.
If it’s a small vessel, the rice will have come to the top. If it was a bigger pot, it would stay in the middle. It’s cooked really well. If the rice is aged, I added slightly more water than usual since older rice needs more water.
You might think, "Why do you say different water levels for different biryanis?" That’s because each rice is different. When I try a biryani at home for the first time, I measure the rice and water ratio and only then share it here.
As for side dishes, you can have chili chicken or chicken curry—whatever you like. I didn’t make anything extra today, just a simple raita. Definitely try this Ambur-style biryani at home and let me know how it turns out.