You won't find biryani like Hyderabad's anywhere in the world
And that's not a claim, it's a fact. So today
we’ll show you how to make chicken biryani
that too in authentic Hyderabadi style. First,
we’ll marinate the chicken with spices.
Take chicken and add lemon
juice, ginger-garlic paste, green chili, red chili,
turmeric, salt, whole spices,
black pepper, rose petals, and fried onions
which we had already prepared. Then add
yogurt, mint, coriander, and green chilies.
Mix it all thoroughly, then
add oil, mix well, and let it marinate
for an hour. Now in a pot,
take water and add coarse salt, whole
spices, squeeze a lemon and add its
peels too. Then add green chilies,
coriander, mint, and oil. After that,
bring it to a good boil. Then,
add the basmati rice that has been
soaked for an hour. Cook the rice until it's 60% done.
Now take the marinated chicken and place it
in a large pot. Add a little water from the rice
and layer 60% cooked rice on top. Then take the
remaining rice, cook it 80% through, and make a
nice top layer. Then we’ll add
fried onions on top,
mint, coriander, and this is saffron milk.
This is kewra water and rose water. Finally,
we’ll add pure ghee. Take a pan,
place it on the stove, and keep the biryani pot on it.
Wrap the lid with a cloth and seal the pot for
dum (slow cooking). First, cook for 10 minutes on high flame,
then 15 minutes on low flame. That’s it,
your biryani is ready. See how long
and separate each grain of rice is?
This was the actual recipe of Hyderabadi chicken biryani.
So do try it and comment below
how it turned out. Thank you so much
for watching! See you in a new video.