Greetings to all! I'm Mehema Supramanya and welcome to Home Cooking Telugu. Every place has its own unique biryani recipe with distinct flavors. So today, I'm making Malabar-style Talassery Biryani.
First, let’s prepare the garam masala powder. In a pan, add 4 cardamoms, 2 pieces of cinnamon, 5 cloves, 2 star anise, ½ tsp pepper, 2 small nutmegs, and 2 pieces of mace.
Dry roast these spices on a low flame for about 2 minutes until aromatic. Then switch off the stove, let it cool, and grind them into a fine powder. Set this aside.
Next, I’m frying onions. Heat some oil in a pan and once hot, add thinly sliced onions and fry them. I’ve taken about 2 large onions here.
These are called fried onions. They add a lot of flavor to the biryani. As you can see, they’ve turned brown. Once golden and crispy, take them out and keep them aside.
In the same pan, add ½ cup of white raisins. Once they're fried, transfer them to a bowl and set aside for garnish.
Now for the chicken masala: take a wide pan and add ¼ cup ghee. Add 4 finely chopped onions and sauté. The more onions, the better the taste of the biryani.
[Unclear audio section, assumed continuation of sautéing and cooking onions, possibly mentioning stirring continuously and cooking until brown.]
After sautéing for 5 minutes, add ½ tsp turmeric, 2 tsp ginger garlic paste. Sauté this well. On high flame, add chicken pieces and cook until the raw smell goes away.
[Unclear audio; likely continuing chicken cooking steps and spice additions.]
After 10 minutes, I’m adding ½ cup thick curd. Stir it well so the curd doesn't split and gives a smooth texture. Continue cooking the chicken on high flame.
Add 2-3 handfuls of the fried onions to enhance the flavor. Finally, add fresh coconut milk and give it a good mix.
With that, the chicken masala for the biryani is ready.
Now for the rice: I’m using 2 cups of Jeera Samba rice (short-grain aromatic rice). Wash and soak the rice before cooking.
Add cinnamon, cloves, cardamom, bay leaf, and star anise. I’ve added about 3–4 cups of water and 1 tsp of salt. Stir well and let it come to a boil.
Once the water boils, add the soaked rice. Mix everything well. Cook until the rice is 90% done. Drain the rice and set aside. Now the biryani rice is ready.
To layer the biryani, take a large pot and first spread the cooked chicken masala at the bottom evenly. Arrange the cooked chicken pieces neatly.
On top of the chicken, drizzle 1 tsp ghee, add chopped coriander and mint leaves, some fried onions, raisins, and cashews. This gives extra flavor and richness.
Now add all the cooked rice on top and gently spread it. Add 1 tsp ghee, coriander, mint, fried onions, raisins, and cashews over the top.
Sprinkle some garam masala powder and saffron milk. Cover with aluminum foil tightly so no steam escapes.
Place a lid on top. Heat a pan and place the biryani pot on top. Let it cook on medium flame. Now the biryani will cook on dum for 20 minutes.
Once done, gently scoop from the bottom to serve the chicken pieces and rice together. Garnish with fried onions, cashews, and coriander.
The second edition of our Home Cooking book is now available at 21frames.in. Link in description. Currently shipping only in India. Order now!