Today, we are going to make a famous biryani from Tamil Nadu using a pressure cooker.
This biryani is a specialty at many famous restaurants in Tamil Nadu and is known for its unique flavor.
First, we add 1 tsp turmeric powder, 1 tsp Kashmiri chili powder, and a bit of salt to yogurt and mix well.
Then add ginger-garlic paste and marinate the chicken. Let it rest for a while.
Now mix everything together thoroughly with the chicken.
We’re going to make a special masala now. For that, we’ll use mint leaves, coriander leaves, onions, and green chilies.
Grind the mixture well. Now we’ll cook this in a pressure cooker along with the marinated chicken and rice.
Add some dry spices and chopped onions to enhance the flavor.
Stir everything together to get a good mix.
The aroma starts coming through as we sauté the onions.
Add tomatoes and cook until soft and blended.
Now add the ground masala paste and stir it into the mixture.
Let it cook well with the masala.
Continue stirring until oil separates from the masala.
Now add the marinated chicken into this mixture.
Along with that, add freshly ground garam masala and sauté everything together.
This is the biryani masala base.
Add chili powder and garam masala. Mix it all well.
Once the masala is cooked, you’ll notice the oil rising. That’s when you know it’s ready.
You can see the color and texture change, indicating it’s cooked properly.
Add soaked rice and stir gently to combine it with the masala.
Now add 3 cups of water, adjust salt, and mix everything again.
Close the pressure cooker and cook for about 1 whistle on medium heat.
Once done, allow the pressure to release naturally before opening the lid.
Fluff the rice gently. The chicken is cooked perfectly and the biryani has a rich aroma and flavor.
Serve hot with raita or boiled eggs. Enjoy your delicious pressure cooker biryani!