In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. Assalamualaikum! Welcome to my channel, Roshni Cooking. How are you all, viewers? I hope you're all doing well. Today I'm going to teach you how to make very delicious Mutton Biryani.
This was requested by one of my sisters—I forgot her name—who had asked me to teach how to make Mutton Biryani using Shan Masala. So today, I’m going to show you how. Mutton Biryani made with Shan Masala turns out extremely delicious.
If you’re new to my channel, then do subscribe, and also click the bell icon so you’ll get notifications of my upcoming videos for free, before anyone else. So, dear viewers, my previous video was on Sindhi Biryani...
Inside the Shan masala box, there are two packets. One packet is for about one kilo of Biryani. I will use one packet for one kilo. So let’s start the preparation quickly.
I’ve placed a large pot on the stove and into it I’ve added half a cup... half a cup... half a cup... (repeated unintelligibly due to error or editing)...
I’ll later tell you why I took out half of the onions. Now into the remaining half, we’ll add the boiled mutton—about half a kilo. I had already boiled it simply in water. We'll add that in.
Now mix it all properly, viewers. After mixing, we’ll sauté the meat for about 5 to 6 minutes on medium flame. While sautéing, you can sprinkle some water if the masala is sticking to the bottom.
The meat is now nicely sautéed, and the smell is gone. Now we’ll add 1 tablespoon of ginger paste. Along with that, we’ll add chopped potatoes—I’ve taken two large-sized potatoes.
Mix everything thoroughly again. Now we’ll add the **Shan Sindhi Biryani Masala**. I’ll add the entire packet; this masala is meant for one kilo of meat. Along with it, I’ll also add a little bit of...
I’ve added all the masala and mixed it well. Now we’ll sauté everything for about 3 to 4 minutes on medium flame. So I’ll sauté everything nicely now.
I’ve added half a cup of water. After adding water, mix it again and close the lid of the pot. Let it cook on medium flame for about 5 minutes.
After 5 minutes, I’ve opened the pot lid. Now we’ll add 1 cup of whisked yogurt. Be sure to whisk the yogurt well with a spoon so that there are no lumps in it.
It’s been about 5–6 minutes. I’ve opened the lid again and mashallah, the aroma is amazing! I can’t describe it, viewers. Our delicious korma masala is now ready. After this...
Now we’ll add a little chopped coriander and mint leaves as well.
After this... after this... after this... after this... (repeated or incomplete sentence, possibly a transition or cut)
Now I’ve layered the korma. On top of that, we’ll place the fried onions we had reserved earlier. I also have yellow food color, to which I’ve added some milk...
And now I’ll sprinkle some chopped coriander on top. After that, some mint leaves. Then I’ll place 4–5 julienned green chilies on top.
First, we’ll cook it on high flame for 5 minutes. Then, we’ll lower the flame completely and put it on **dum** (slow cooking) just like we steam rice. Let it cook for 15–20 minutes. 20 minutes have passed...
Now I’m dishing it out.
Mutton Sindhi Biryani is ready, and it’s turned out very delicious. I can’t even explain how tasty it is! Definitely try this recipe, viewers. I hope you liked today’s video...
See you in the next video, Insha'Allah. Thanks for watching. Allah Hafiz!