Assalamu Alaikum, my name is Chef Abssal, and today I’ll share with you a recipe for Chicken Bombay Biryani for 10 people, along with an excellent method of making biryani. Insha’Allah, you’ll enjoy it a lot after watching this video. So let’s get started.
Bismillahir Rahmanir Rahim. First of all, we need to soak the rice. I am using 1200 grams of Basmati rice, which is about six cups. Wash the rice thoroughly two to three times in water beforehand, because washing them after soaking can break the grains—especially Basmati rice. So wash it properly from the start.
Now let’s prepare the setup. I’ve taken a bowl of yogurt, and I’m adding a special aromatic biryani spice mix. Insha’Allah, I will soon launch this spice mix on my online store, and you’ll be able to order it from anywhere in Pakistan, just like people are ordering my handmade panjiri. I've also added yellow food color and four...
...saffron kewra powder. If you have kewra essence instead, just add 5–6 drops—not a spoonful—because it has a very strong flavor. Mix the yogurt, color, and biryani masala thoroughly and keep it aside. Now let me show you the next step.
I’ve fried 4 large onions and added 8–10 dried plums, a bit of ginger, coriander, and about 8–10 green chilies. Mix these green spices well and keep them ready. As I guide you step-by-step, follow along. Now take a pot in which we’ll make the korma. For the korma, I’m using the same oil in which we fried the onions...
The biryani turns out tastier this way. For whole spices, I’m using green cardamom, cloves, cinnamon, and black cardamom. I’ve added two bay leaves, 3 teaspoons of ginger garlic paste, and 2 tablespoons of green chili paste made from spicy green chilies. Add 1.5 tsp crushed red chili, and chopped coriander...
Add 1 tablespoon red chili powder, 1 tablespoon salt—check the salt later too—1 tablespoon turmeric powder, and 1 tablespoon Kashmiri red chili powder. If you don’t have Kashmiri chili, increase the red chili powder by half a spoon. Add half a tablespoon of fennel powder and 1 tablespoon whole cumin seeds.
Add about 1.25 kg (1250g) of chicken—always use at least the same amount of chicken as rice. You can even add more for better results. I’ve taken about 600g of potatoes (a bit over half a kilo), dipped them in water mixed with a little yellow food color for a light tint.
Now turn the flame on and sauté for 2–3 minutes on high heat. Then add a bit of water and cook the chicken and potatoes for 5–7 minutes to soften them. I always mention in my biryani videos: don’t overcook the korma. If you do, it turns into a curry and loses that biryani-style flavor.
That classic biryani flavor won’t come if overcooked. Just 2–3 minutes on high heat is enough for sautéing. The spices won’t remain raw. Again, sauté briefly on high. The masala is now cooked. I’m adding about 1 cup of water now, then covering it so the potatoes can fully cook.
The potatoes need to be cooked—at least 60–70% now, the rest will cook during the steam step (dum). I’m adding a bit of Chinese salt (optional). If you don’t like it or don’t have it, just skip it. After covering, let the chicken and potatoes cook for 5–7 minutes, then uncover and check if the potatoes are tender.
Proper steam will soften the potatoes. Don’t let the korma dry out too much. There should still be about a cup of water remaining. I’ve turned off the heat. Now we add yogurt on top. One note: I’ve placed both the chicken and potatoes in the pot as a base. Follow this recipe exactly.
This method I’m showing you is exactly how large quantities (5–10 kg biryani) are prepared commercially. If you follow it properly, using the same masalas, you’ll always remember this biryani. I’ll soon show you how to order the biryani spice mix from my online store.
Now add the green masala on top. If you’re preparing the biryani 4–5 hours later, you can still make the korma now and leave it prepped. Just boil the rice 30 minutes before serving. I already boiled water with the lid on. The water should be well-salted—I'm using around 10–12...
...and do taste the salt—it should be slightly strong. If the water is salty, the biryani rice will be well balanced. Also, add a little salt to the korma. No matter how many spices you use, if there’s not enough salt, it won’t taste right. The true test of good food is balanced salt.
The water has now come to a boil. Let’s uncover it. Basmati rice needs quick handling—don't take too much time with it.
After boiling, cook the rice for 5–6 minutes. That’s enough. Cook them only 50–60%. The rice has expanded in length. Now I’ll remove about half of them. These partially cooked rice (60%) will be layered into the korma. It’s simple—don’t overthink it.
I know my home-cook sisters and mothers may not understand terms like “1 string” or “2 string” stages—that’s more for commercial or professional chefs.
So just remember this simple rule: After boiling starts, give it 4–5 boils, then remove slightly more than half the rice and put it into the korma. Increase the flame now. The remaining 30–40% of the rice will be cooked for another minute, and reserve 1–2 cups of the starchy water—we’ll need that.
Now I’ve increased the flame under the pot. Whenever you add the second layer of rice, turn up the heat. Don’t spread the rice with a steel spoon—use a cloth or a napkin to settle the rice.
Now take that cup of reserved starchy rice water and gently sprinkle it over the rice so that all the rice is moistened. This is because some rice is still firm, and the water will help them steam perfectly.
I’ve lowered the heat. Once you start seeing steam, like this, it means it's time for dum (steaming). Do this for exactly 12 minutes using a timer. If your pot is lightweight, place a griddle underneath. If it’s heavy, you don’t need it.
So friends, after exactly 12 minutes of dum cooking, I’m removing the lid to show you the final look. Always reduce the flame when putting on dum. If using a griddle, increase the flame for 1 minute to heat it, then reduce it so the pot gets heat evenly.
Finally, I’m adding a cup of the oil used for frying onions on top. This gives shine and prevents the rice from sticking. Remember: biryani needs oil to taste good. You can’t diet and expect restaurant-style biryani. Either choose diet food or make real biryani.
For 1.25 kg rice, use 2.5 cups (around 400g) of oil. For 1 kg rice, 250–300g oil is ideal. For 10 kg rice pots, 2.5–3 kg of oil is used. You can use oil or ghee. And here’s our final look—just look how amazing it turned out, Masha’Allah.
And one more thing: I’ve started my online store where you’ll find delicious panjiri made from pure desi cow ghee. You can order it anywhere in Pakistan. The number showing on your screen right now—just contact that for cash-on-delivery orders.
That’s all for today’s video. If you liked it, see you in the next one. Take care of yourself and your parents. Allah Hafiz!