Biryani is a constant battle over whose biryani is the best. And not just that—how it's made too. In fact, every state, every community has its own version of biryani. So the one that's made at your home might not be the same as the one made at mine.
But biryani is one such dish that, whenever it's made, fills the whole house with fragrance. And if you make a little extra, even the neighborhood will smell it. Today we are going to make Hyderabadi cooked meat (pakke gosht) biryani. We'll take the meat—
Red chili powder, whole spices including royal cumin (shahi jeera), cardamom, and cinnamon. A generous amount of garlic paste and ginger paste. We’ll add yogurt, a lot of mint leaves, and this is our fried onions,
which we have fried in oil and taken out. This is also called "barista." These are green chilies, add according to how spicy you want it.
I have this oil, in which I had fried the onions—this same oil will go in here. And now we’ll mix it all well. One special thing is, whenever we make Hyderabadi biryani, we never use kewra (screw pine essence) or rose water in it.
We’ll now put this into the pot.
Now we have to cook this. While that’s cooking, we’ll boil water for the rice. Along with that, here is basmati rice. This rice needs to be soaked in water for about 30 to 45 minutes. Soak it well.
Cover and cook this until the meat is almost 80-90% done. You want that. The bottom has cooked really well.
There’s a bit of juice in this—perfect! We'll turn it off now. Next, we go to the rice. This is the soaked rice, and we will blanch it. But before that, we’ll add lots of salt, a bit of cardamom, and one green chili.
Now the rice will go in. I think a good measurement is to use the same weight of rice as meat. While the rice is blanching, we roll out this dough. This will be used for sealing the pot, the "dum" method.
Perfect! The lid is ready. The rice is ready. We’ll turn off the gas. Now we’ll strain it. Before adding rice to the pot, we’ll layer some mint leaves and fried onions. Now we’ll add all of the rice. This rice water—
—we’ll pour over this. That’s set. On top of that goes saffron soaked in milk. Add the remaining fried onion oil—it gives an amazing flavor. You can also add ghee if you want. Not necessary—
Once again on high flame, for about one to one-and-a-half minutes so it starts cooking again. Then reduce the flame. Biryani is ready. Turn it off and let it rest for 10 minutes, without opening the lid. After that, we’ll open it.
Even opening biryani is an art. Use a spoon with a thin edge, or a plate—rotate it from one edge to fluff it gently. Then scoop and serve. If you just shove a spoon in, the layers will break.
Look at that—every grain is separate. Beautiful! First, we’ll serve the spiced rice from the bottom with the meat, and then the saffron rice from the top.
And a sign of a good biryani—obviously—the rice shouldn’t be lumpy, shouldn't be undercooked. Each grain should be separate. That’s the hallmark of a great biryani, again and again.
And our Hyderabadi meat biryani is ready.