Today we’ll see a superb Kerala-style mutton biryani recipe. In this Malabar-style biryani, first the mutton is well cooked with a gravy, then the rice is fried, and finally both are layered and cooked on dum to make a delicious mutton biryani.
Let’s see how tasty Malabar biryani is made. First, we take a pressure cooker and add 750 grams of mutton. Then we add whole spices, pepper powder, garam masala, and salt. Mix everything well and cook the mutton.
We also prepare a gravy like a yakhni base. For that, take a pot, add oil and ghee. Once it heats up, add onions and sauté until they turn soft.
We sauté this well for a couple of minutes. Then add tomatoes, some fresh coriander leaves, mint leaves, and curd. Also add a little salt.
Add garam masala and some pepper powder. Mix well. Cook the tomatoes until they soften completely. After cooking for a couple of minutes, the tomatoes become soft and the gravy thickens.
While the gravy is cooking, the mutton will also be done. Release the pressure and add the mutton to the gravy. Squeeze in half a lemon for tanginess. Mix the cooked mutton into the gravy.
The mutton is already nicely tender. We won’t cook it further, just simmer it in the gravy for a couple of minutes. Then, we’ll prepare the rice. Mix the mutton in the gravy once again before that.
We had fried some onions earlier for garnish, so now we’ll add those birista onions. Since we pressure-cooked the mutton earlier, it’s already soft. We won’t cook it more, just mix and let it rest.
To prepare the rice, heat a pot, add ghee and oil, then add half an onion and sauté well. Add cumin seeds, and now add the jeerakasala rice (small-grain aromatic rice), about half a kilogram.
Add the rice and sauté it for 2–3 minutes. In Malabar biryani, the rice is also lightly fried first. After frying for 2–3 minutes, add hot water to cook the rice.
Now we’ve added hot water along with some coriander leaves, mint leaves, and a couple of green chilies. Cook the rice fully, 100%. As you can see, the rice is nicely cooked now.
Once the rice is fully cooked, layer it over the mutton gravy. Top it with fried onions, coriander and mint leaves for garnish, and add a few dry fruits like cashews and raisins.
After 5 minutes of dum cooking, a superb Malabar mutton biryani will be ready. It tastes absolutely amazing, especially when made with jeerakasala rice. The yakhni is also prepared differently, giving it a unique taste.
It’s really enjoyable to eat. The mutton is super soft. And since we first fried the rice and then cooked and layered it on the yakhni and gave it a dum, the rice has absorbed all the flavors perfectly.
Don’t forget to subscribe to our channel and hit the bell icon. See you again with another recipe. Till then, take care and bye!