In the same way, we also need to add green masala to this. Sindhi biryani. It uses more coriander and mint. I've added it. There should be enough water in it. This is how you know it's time to let the water release.
So that the top rice softens and this becomes a juicy biryani. I've added it. Now let me show you — our Sindhi biryani is ready, by the grace of God. Very fragrant and flavorful — look at this.
Hello Swanik friend, I hope everyone is doing well. Today I'm going to show you how to make Sindhi biryani. We have garlic paste, cinnamon, star anise, cloves, black pepper, small cardamoms, and green chilies...
...garam masala powder, salt, onions — which we browned but kept whole. There's also cumin, dried plums, lemon, tomatoes, 2 kg of meat which we already boiled — it's goat meat — and potatoes, coriander...
We added it to the oil — about two tablespoons of ginger garlic paste went in. It'll fry slightly. Let me explain — it should become a bit brown.
I added about half a kg of finely chopped tomatoes. This is our ground garam masala — two tablespoons. Two tablespoons of salt. Two tablespoons of red chili powder. Adding it all here.
I added all the tomatoes to the tempering. Let it cook a little so the flavors blend in.
Water, water, water, water, water, water, water, water.
Now I'm adding the potatoes. I covered it and will cook it for about 5 minutes so the potatoes soften. After that, we’ll add the meat. These are the potatoes I added at the end.
I've added the boiled meat into it. Now I’m covering it and cooking for 5 more minutes. Then I’ll set it aside so the meat absorbs the masala. I kept water with the meat while boiling.
These are 2 kg sela rice, which I soaked for 1.5 to 2 hours and changed the water four times. Now I'm adding them. I also added 3–4 sticks of cinnamon and 4–5 star anise pods.
While the rice boils, I’m preparing the green masala for Sindhi biryani. I took about half a kg of tomatoes and added around 50g of stock into them. These are around 300g tomatoes. Adding them to the same pot.
I also added 3–4 sliced lemons. 10–12 dried plums too. These are the fried onions — I kept them whole — adding those too. Approximately...
The green masala for the Sindhi biryani is ready. The rice is also boiled. I’m lifting the hard-cooked bottom rice. Let me show you — I’ve taken the rice from the bottom...
Added the coloring — absolutely beautiful! When you get this color, it means the salt is perfectly set. Now I’m adding the oil on top. The oil is added. Now I’m adding food coloring.
I’ve added about 3 tablespoons of yogurt. This green masala that we prepared — I’m mixing and adding it in. It needs to be added like this. Sindhi biryani — with lots of coriander and mint.
I’ve added the masala on top. There should be this much water in it. From this, you’ll know when it starts releasing water. I added it over two layers of rice. It leaves a mark like this when it’s ready. Half of the water gets absorbed.
Now I’m layering the softened rice on top. I already added the oil. I’d saved 3 cups of water — adding them now. This is so the top layer of rice also softens nicely.
Look, it’s started to cook. Now I’ll seal it a bit. I’ll give it two ‘dum’ (steam cooking) — first one now, final one later. I’ll put a lid on top so the steam circulates well. One dum is done...
I took about 200g oil, in which I sliced and fried onions. Initially we used about half a kg of oil — and from that, I used 200g for the fried onions. Now...
Our Sindhi biryani is ready — this is for 2 kg quantity. Do comment below how it turned out after trying it. For more such delicious recipes, subscribe to Ustad Salman. Like and see you in the next video, Inshallah. Take care!