Assalamu Alaikum everyone, welcome to Nazia Food Hub. Today I have made Bombay Biryani, which tastes absolutely delicious and has turned out really well. Just look at the rice — each grain is perfectly separated. So I thought I should share this recipe with you as well.
We'll heat the oil properly. Now that the oil is hot, we’ll add three medium-sized onions which I’ve roughly chopped. We’ll fry the onions until golden brown. The onions will turn golden quickly, and then we’ll add...
It took about 5 to 7 minutes to fry the onions. We’ll take them out onto a plate and make a nice paste using four tablespoons of yogurt. Keep a little of the fried onion in the pot. Now here I have taken around 1 kg of chicken.
I sautéed it for 10 minutes. Now we’ll add three tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste and one tablespoon of salt. We'll sauté this well until the raw smell of the ginger-garlic is gone, which will take about 10 minutes.
Now we’ll add some spices. I’ve taken half a tablespoon of coriander powder, half a tablespoon of red chili powder, a pinch of turmeric, half a tablespoon of garam masala, a bit less than half a tablespoon of cumin, and two cinnamon sticks — all of these are for the Bombay biryani.
I mixed and sautéed everything well. Now we’ll add the onion and yogurt paste that I had blended earlier. Mix this thoroughly and cook it well again. After that, we’ll add...
So I’ve sautéed everything for a while, and it has cooked nicely. I sautéed it for 15 minutes. At this point, we’ll add a little water, mix it well, and cover it until it’s cooked.
I cooked it on low flame for 10 minutes. The chicken is nicely tender now. We’ll remove this pot from the stove. Now we’ll prepare the water for cooking the rice. I’ve taken another pot with ample water in it, and into it we’ll add...
Always use a large pot for cooking rice. The water has come to a nice boil. Now we’ll add about 1 kg of Basmati rice, which I had soaked beforehand. The rice is of very good quality.
Now we’ll add the juice of half a lemon. This adds a wonderful aroma and a great flavor. We’ll also add one tablespoon of desi ghee. Ghee prevents the rice from sticking and gives it a lovely aroma.
The rice is 80% cooked. We’ll drain the water and make a layer of rice. On top of this, we’ll add the chicken masala layer. Even now, the aroma is so amazing — I can’t even describe it!
When the biryani is cooked on ‘dum’ (steam), the rice cooks fully, which is why it’s important to keep it a bit undercooked beforehand. Lastly, we’ll add another layer of rice on top. I had 1 kg of chicken and 1 kg of rice, so we’ll balance it out.
Now on top of this we will add… (repeats) — this part seems like repetition or filler and may have been cut off or misrecorded.
Now we’ll take a cotton cloth. I had washed it well; it’s damp.
We’ll place a lid on top of the cloth. Cook it on high flame for 5 minutes, then on low flame for 10 minutes. So I gave it 15 minutes of dum cooking. It came out perfectly cooked in dum. Now we’ll gently mix it...
Serve it with mint raita, salad, and green coriander-mint chutney. Enjoy it with your family. Just look at how amazing the biryani looks — Bombay Biryani! So friends, how did you like this recipe?