Kolkata’s very famous Aloo Dum Biryani—this biryani is just as tasty and flavorful as mutton or chicken biryani. To make this biryani, first we extract ginger-garlic water. Take two tablespoons full of ginger-garlic paste.
So, this is the ginger-garlic water. In Kolkata biryani, ginger-garlic water is used instead of the paste. Keep it aside. Now, peel and prep the potatoes. Since they were large, I’ve cut them into two pieces.
After adding oil, add the chopped potatoes. Fry them on medium flame until they get a light golden color. They will also be about 15–20% cooked. Now let’s move on.
In the same oil, add two medium-sized onions, thinly sliced. Fry until they get a nice golden color. Then remove half the fried onions for garnishing and leave the rest in the pan. Now add—
Add the fried potatoes back. Add two tablespoons of Kolkata biryani masala. The recipe for this masala is uploaded on our channel—you can check it out. Add salt according to the broth and potatoes. Then add one cup of hot water to create the broth.
Once the broth starts boiling and the oil begins to separate, reduce the flame to low. Now add half a cup of well-whisked curd. Mix everything on low flame only, since we’ve added yogurt.
Cook the potatoes well in the broth for 7–8 minutes. While the potatoes cook, prepare the rice. Bring 3–4 liters of water to a boil. Add 2–3 slit green chilies, 2 bay leaves, and 2–3 pieces of cinnamon.
Squeeze the juice of half a lemon into it. Add two heaping teaspoons of salt. Let it come to a full boil on high flame. Then add 4 cups of soaked and washed basmati rice. Cook the rice only up to 70%.
Now turn off the flame and remove the potatoes. (Note: This line contains a long sequence of filler words, “yeh yeh yeh,” likely a glitch or repetition, so it has been skipped.)
Our broth (yakhni) is now ready. Now let’s set up the biryani for dum (steam cooking). In the same pot where we prepared the broth, first layer the cooked potatoes. Spread them out evenly.
Pour all the broth over the potatoes. Then add the fried onions we had set aside, spreading them evenly. The rice is about 75% cooked—drain all the water and layer the rice on top. Now—
The spice flavor in Kolkata biryani is intense, without the use of whole spices. After layering the rice properly, sprinkle a bit of yellow food color on top. You can also use saffron soaked in milk if preferred.
Now cover it and cook on high flame for about 5 minutes. Once the biryani pot is nice and hot, lower the flame completely and cook on dum for 25–30 minutes. The rice cooks beautifully this way.
And there you have it—our simple and easy Kolkata-style Aloo Dum Biryani is ready. Flip and gently mix the rice from bottom to top, and it’s ready to serve. Enjoy it with raita or chutney as you like.