Hello food lovers! You've been requesting this for a while — here's the Srikanth-style Chicken Mughlai Biryani recipe.
Add Mughlai masala paste in your usual quantity.
Add two tablespoons of red chili powder.
Add about two tablespoons of ginger garlic paste.
Squeeze lemon juice and massage the mixture well into the meat.
Make sure the meat pieces are all of even size.
Soak saffron in milk for about 30 minutes and set it aside.
Now add some ghee, and it’s time for the Mughlai biryani's royal ingredients — about 20 pistachios, and more.
Pour in about half a cup of oil. It's okay to use the oil left from frying onions.
Mix everything really well so that the oil blends evenly.
Stir well to make sure the oil and masala are well combined.
Next, in a separate vessel, pour three liters of water — one liter per glass.
Add 5 cloves, 4 cardamoms, 1 inch cinnamon stick, a mace flower, a star anise, and a cup of coriander.
Squeeze the juice of one lemon into this and cover with a lid. Let it come to a boil on high flame for 6 minutes.
Once the rice is partially cooked, layer the first half at the bottom of the biryani vessel.
Top it with some crispy fried onions.
Add fresh coriander and mint leaves evenly.
Sprinkle more coriander and mint — add as per your preference.
Repeat layering with coriander and mint again.
Add some more layers with the same herbs.
Add the final touches with fresh herbs on top.
Sprinkle a bit more if you'd like the flavor to be intense.
Final herb garnishing — and you're done!