Hey everyone, Assalamu Alaikum. I hope you all are doing great in your life. This is me, Fatima Malik, and you are watching FM's Kitchen YouTube channel. So guys, today I will be sharing one of the most requested recipe videos — Shan Bombay Biryani. This recipe is extremely easy to make and perfect for beginners. Actually, I uploaded this recipe on my main channel in Urdu. I’ll leave the link to that video in the description box and also in the comments section.
If you really want to read the reviews about this recipe, then don’t forget to check out that video. Okay, so without wasting any time, let’s get started. First of all, to make this yummy and delicious Chicken Bombay Biryani, you need one cup of yogurt. And into this one cup of yogurt, I’m going to add half a packet of Shan Bombay Biryani Masala. Since I’m making half a kilogram of biryani today, I’m using half the packet.
If you’re making one kilogram of biryani, then use the full packet. Okay guys, now I’m going to mix the biryani masala with the yogurt really well. This is the very first step in making biryani. And let me tell you, this recipe is very easy to make. Because I’m not going to add any extra spices or masalas. I’m keeping this recipe simple.
Easy and delicious. Okay guys, let’s move on to the second step. In the second step, take a wok and add half a cup of oil. Then add 3 large onions. Now cook these onions on medium heat until they become translucent. Once the onions are translucent, add bone-in chicken. Here I’m using half a kilogram of chicken.
You can make this biryani with boneless chicken, or you can use mutton or beef instead. But with chicken, it tastes amazing. Now after adding all the chicken pieces, cook the chicken with the onions for five minutes. After five minutes, add two medium-sized potatoes. As you all know, this is Bombay Biryani. And let me tell you, Bombay Biryani is actually incomplete without potatoes.
If you don’t like potatoes in your biryani, you can skip them. So after adding the two medium-sized potatoes, fry the chicken pieces with the potatoes for 10 minutes. After 10 minutes, you’ll notice that the color of the chicken has completely changed. So our chicken and potatoes are well-fried. At this stage, add one tablespoon of garlic paste and one tablespoon of ginger paste.
Mix it really well and cook for 1–2 minutes. Make sure your flame is on medium at this stage. After 1–2 minutes, add 4 medium-sized chopped tomatoes. Mix all the ingredients really well. Once that’s done, add some spices. Here I’m adding 1 teaspoon of salt and 1 teaspoon of red chili powder.
And now give it a good mix. You might be wondering why I added salt and red chili powder. Let me tell you — the answer is simple and easy.
Guys, biryani masala is made with many different spices, and all of them are added in small quantities. That’s why, to make it more delicious, you need to add some basic spices. Okay guys, after adding tomatoes, cover the lid and cook on medium heat for 5–10 minutes. Once the water from the tomatoes dries up, add the yogurt and biryani masala mixture.
Mix it really well and then cover again and cook on medium heat for 10 minutes. Meanwhile, I’m going to boil my rice. Take some water in a large pot and add 2 teaspoons of salt because I’m making 2 glasses of rice. After adding the salt, add 1 teaspoon of cumin and 1 tablespoon of white vinegar. Now wait until the water starts boiling.
When the water starts boiling, add the soaked rice. You need to clean and wash the rice, then soak them in water for 30 minutes. Now I’m going to cook the rice until they are 75% done. Meanwhile, I’m going to mix the gravy. 10 minutes have passed and now I’m going to add half a cup of turmeric water.
You can also add a bit of turmeric if you want. If you have dry plums at home, you can add those as well. Now after adding turmeric water and turmeric, I’ve added some green chilies. Mix it well, cover, and cook for another 5–7 minutes. Meanwhile, I checked and our rice is 75% done. I’ve now strained them, so our boiled rice is ready.
Okay guys, so 5 to 10 minutes have passed. Now I’m going to add 1 teaspoon of coriander powder and half a teaspoon of garam masala powder to our chicken gravy. Garam masala powder is basically a mix of dry spices. And now I’m not going to add anything else. I’ll cook the gravy for another 5 minutes until the oil separates. When your gravy releases oil, it means it’s ready.
Okay guys, our chicken masala for biryani is ready. Now I’m going to move on to the layering process. To layer your biryani, first add some chicken masala and oil at the bottom of a large pot. Once you’ve done that, add a layer of boiled rice. Cover the base with rice. After adding the rice layer, add a layer of chicken masala.
Now cover all the boiled rice with this chicken masala. Once that’s done, add some green chilies, mint leaves, and coriander. You can also add fried onions if you want, but I skipped them because I try my best to keep the recipe simple and easy for you.
So after adding the green chilies, coriander, and mint, add another layer of boiled rice. Guys, if you like this video, please give it a thumbs up. And if you’re new to my channel, do subscribe and don’t forget to click the bell icon so you get notified whenever I upload a video.
So I’ve added all the boiled rice in this layer. Now I’m going to add some green chilies, mint leaves, and coriander leaves. To give this biryani a beautiful color, I’m going to add some orange food coloring. Once you’re done with the layering process, place a griddle (tava) on the stove, and place your large pot on top of it.
Cover it and let it cook on low heat for 5 minutes. After 5 minutes, uncover and mix your biryani well. Just look at this beauty. It looks so good. And let me tell you guys, it tastes delicious.
After mixing your biryani, cover it again and cook on low heat for 10 minutes. After 10 minutes, serve it and enjoy. You guys will definitely love it. Do give it a try and let me know your feedback in the comments section. Hope you liked this video. Thank you so much for watching. Take care. Allah Hafiz. Allah ni Gebaan.