1 tbsp soya chunks
Add sunflower oil, one medium-sized onion, and 2 cardamoms.
Add the soya chunks.
Use 1 kg Jeerakasala rice to make this biryani. This is the ideal variety used. Wash it thoroughly. Let it soak for 15 minutes. Then in a hot pan, add 2 tablespoons of ghee.
Add 1 tbsp lime juice, mix well, and boil on a high flame.
Boil the water until it bubbles. Add vegetables carefully and mix well. These vegetables are for mixing with the rice while making the dum. You need to cook them in the same pan.
Add 4 tbsp oil. Add 100 gm cauliflower and 100 gm rice.
Add green beans.
80-90% of the rice will be cooked with the lid closed. The remaining will be cooked during dum. Make sure the vegetables don’t get overcooked. If there’s excess water in the pan, increase the flame and let it evaporate. Then, add half of the cooked rice to the pan.
If you prepare the dum this way, you’ll get a tasty and fragrant vegetable biryani. Mix all ingredients well from the bottom. If you want smaller soya chunks, cut them in half and fry. Even though it’s a vegetable biryani, with Jeerakasala rice, it tastes as good as chicken biryani.
Serve with curd salad or chutney for a complete meal.