Today, I’m going to share with you the perfect recipe for Afghani Chicken Biryani. Do try it—it's a very flavorful biryani and really easy to make. So without delay, let’s start the recipe.
We’ll begin the biryani preparation with the rice. For that, I’ve kept water to heat. Into it, I’ve added...
Let the flavors of the spices we added infuse into the water. Now I’m adding the rice. I’ve used 1 kg of long grain biryani rice which I had soaked 20–25 minutes earlier.
Let’s keep the rice aside and move on to the next step. Here, I’ve taken a mortar and pestle. Into it, I’m adding one big piece of cinnamon, 3–4 cloves, one black cardamom, and two star anise.
Now I’m frying onions which will be used in the biryani. I’ll make them crispy and golden. I used 1 cup (about 125 ml) of oil to fry the onions. I’ve used one large onion for this.
In the same oil, I’ve left a little of the fried onions and added the coarsely ground whole spices. I crushed them just enough to break the cinnamon and lightly crack the pepper.
All the whole spices are now added. I’m also adding two bay leaves. Let the flavor of these whole spices, all of which are aromatic garam masala, infuse into the oil to enhance the dish’s flavor.
As the chicken is sautéing, I’m adding salt to it—just the right amount needed for the chicken. I’ll roast the chicken well. As it cooks, its juices will release and mix with the spices.
Make sure you cook the ginger and garlic properly until the raw smell goes away completely. Keep the flame on high and sauté the chicken with the ginger-garlic paste well again.
I’ve set aside half the quantity of the paste. I’ve used 7–8 green chilies and lightly crushed them. Now back to the chicken—it’s cooking well with the ginger-garlic and has developed a great aroma.
This gives the biryani a nice spicy kick. Afghani biryani is usually mild yet very flavorful and light, but the spices bring out a very rich flavor.
The chicken is looking great and roasting well with the spices. Its color is changing too. I’m now adding 200 grams of thick, full-fat yogurt. It should be well-whisked and smooth.
Once the yogurt is added, it releases a lot of moisture. So you have to roast the chicken until the yogurt fully blends and cooks with it. Only then it will be perfect.
I had taken 12 almonds and 12 cashews—peeled the almonds and made a paste with half a cup of milk. The paste should be smooth and white. I’ve added this to the chicken now.
Now we will cover the chicken and let it cook for 5 to 7 minutes.
It’s been 7 minutes of cooking, and I’m checking again. The aroma is amazing due to the spices. The chicken is fully infused with flavor now.
I had soaked 12–15 strands of saffron in half a cup of milk. The saffron has started releasing its color. I’ve also added a bit of orange food color to enhance the look.
Now we’ll start layering. We’ll layer everything—chicken, rice, fried onions, saffron milk, food color, and aromatic waters.
To enhance the fragrance of the biryani, I’ve used kewra water and rose water. I had kept the cooked chicken aside to cool a bit before layering.
Now we’ll start layering—first a layer of rice, then the chicken, then more rice, and so on.
Add some of the remaining biryani oil, fried onions, and some saffron milk over each layer.
I’m saving a little for the top layer. I’m also adding orange food color again—it’s optional, but it enhances the look. You can just use saffron if you prefer.
This brings a wonderful aroma and flavor to the rice. It enhances the overall experience of the biryani.
Add 2 to 3 tablespoons of fried onions on top of the final rice layer. Then, add a layer of the chicken again and cover it with the remaining rice.
I’ve finished all the layering. I added fried onions on top, and the remaining oil or gravy which carries all the flavors. This brings deep flavor and ensures the biryani is moist and aromatic.
For better aroma and dum, I’ve also added saffron-infused milk and food color. Both give fragrance and vibrant color to the biryani.
You can seal the pot with dough. I’m using a clean kitchen towel to cover it. I’ve preheated a tawa (griddle), placed it on high heat, then put the biryani pot on it.
Cook it on dum (slow steam) for 25 to 30 minutes. After that, your biryani will be perfectly ready.
After waiting half an hour, the biryani has been beautifully steamed. Let me show you the final result—it's aromatic, flavorful, and looks absolutely amazing.
In just a few minutes, this delicious Lucknowi or Awadhi-style biryani is completely ready.
Just a little prep work and you’ll have an irresistible biryani. It’s very flavorful and fragrant. Do try this once, friends—you and your family will love it.
And if you’re new to the channel, please make sure to subscribe. I’ll see you all next time with another amazing new recipe. Until then, take good care of yourself and your family. Bye!