Let’s make Mughlai Chicken Dum Biryani. As royal as its name, this recipe turns out rich and flavorful. For this, take 1 kg of chicken, add 2 tbsp ginger-garlic paste and half a cup of...
...spice powders: 1 tsp coriander powder, 1 tsp cumin powder, 1 tsp hot red chili powder, 2 tsp Kashmiri red chili powder, and ½ tsp white pepper powder.
Add 5–6 green chilies, slit in the middle. For whole spices, add cinnamon, cloves, star anise, and 2 bay leaves. Add 1 tsp black cumin and 2 tbsp roughly chopped pistachios and almonds.
Add some mint and finely chopped coriander leaves. Then add ½ cup fresh cream, or use thick milk cream (malai). Add salt as per the chicken quantity.
Mix everything thoroughly, pressing spices into the chicken. If using bone-in chicken, marinate for 2–3 hours to make it juicy and tender. Cover and refrigerate.
Now for the rice: in boiling water, add whole spices and 5–6 mild green chilies, some chopped coriander, juice of half a lemon, and 1 heaped tbsp salt.
Add 1 kg basmati rice, pre-soaked for 30 minutes and drained. Cook it 50–60% on high flame. Let it boil for 2–3 minutes after adding rice.
Once 50–60% cooked, layer the rice over the marinated chicken. Spread the rice evenly. Pour ½ cup melted ghee on top for rich flavor and non-sticky grains.
To cook on dum, seal the pot tightly to trap steam and soften the chicken. I’m using dough to seal the lid; alternatively, use aluminum foil and a heavy lid.
Cook the biryani on very low flame for 40–45 minutes. After that, turn off the heat and let it sit for 10 minutes before opening the lid. Fragrant and incredibly tasty biryani is ready!