Hello everyone, welcome to Home Cooking with me, Hema Subramanian. Chicken biryani is a go-to dish for most chicken lovers. There are several varieties, and today I'm sharing a special one — Mughlai Chicken Dum Biryani. It’s mild, rich, and very tasty. So let's get started!
There are three main steps: marination (the key), cooking the basmati rice, and finally layering everything together and placing it on dum. I’ll show you everything in detail — follow along closely.
For this biryani, I've taken 2 kilos of chicken cut into large biryani pieces. First step — marinate the chicken. I've taken the juice of 3 small lemons.
Add 3 tbsp ginger garlic paste, 300 g curd, and 3 tsp salt (adjust to taste). Mix the chicken pieces well. Now add the spice powders: 1 tsp turmeric, 4 tsp chili powder,
1 tsp pepper, 3 tsp coriander powder, 3 tsp cumin powder, and 2 tsp garam masala. Mix everything step by step to ensure the chicken is coated well with the masala.
Add whole spices: cinnamon, 12 cloves, 7 green cardamom, 3 black cardamom, 3 pieces of mace (javitri), 3 star anise, 3 marathi moggu, 1.5 tsp shahi jeera, and 3 bay leaves.
Add 2 tbsp onion-fried oil, 2 tbsp ghee, and 4 large chopped green chilies. Add one large bowl of fried onions (crispy). Add a small bunch of mint leaves.
Mint and coriander are essential for flavor. Massage the masala well into the chicken so it absorbs everything. Now add 2 tbsp fresh cream.
Add saffron milk with saffron strands, 1/4 cup sliced almonds, 1/4 cup chopped cashews, and 1/4 cup chopped pistachios. This enriches the Mughlai biryani and gives it a royal touch.
The marinade looks rich and beautiful. Cover and let it sit for at least 2 hours (or overnight). For rice, take 1 kg whole grain basmati rice. Wash well and soak for 1 hour.
Boil a large pot of water. Add cinnamon, cloves, 5 cardamom, 2 star anise, 2 bay leaves, 1 tsp shahi jeera, coriander leaves, and mint leaves. Let the water absorb the flavors.
After 2–3 minutes, add the soaked rice gradually.
Add 3 tsp salt and the juice of 1 small lemon. This prevents the rice from breaking and keeps it fluffy. Cook the rice in two stages: remove some at 60% doneness for layering.
60% cooked rice will feel slightly crunchy. Remove it and set aside. Continue cooking the rest until 80% done, then strain and set it aside.
You can see the 60% rice — just firm enough. The 80% rice will cook fully on dum. Avoid overcooking.
Now for the final step — layering. Heat a large pot on a tawa. Add 2 tbsp ghee and 2 tbsp onion-fried oil.
Once heated, add the marinated chicken pieces. Keep the flame high. Close the pot for 2–3 minutes to get the heat going. The chicken is starting to cook.
Now add the first layer: 60% cooked rice. Spread evenly. Add fried onions, coriander, mint, and 1 tsp ghee.
Drizzle saffron water. Add the second layer: 80% cooked rice. Spread evenly. Add 2 tsp ghee, more saffron water, and fried onions on top.
Add coriander and mint. Cover with foil. If no foil, seal edges with dough. Keep the flame high and place a lid. Let it cook on dum for 45 minutes.
After 45 minutes, remove the foil. The aroma is incredible! Look at that beautiful biryani — chicken is soft and perfectly cooked.
Before serving, mix gently from the bottom without breaking the rice. Look at the color, texture, and perfectly cooked rice and chicken. Serve with raita and boiled eggs.
This is a must-try recipe! I’ve shown you all the steps. It’s perfect for family feasts, get-togethers, and special occasions. The chicken is tender and flavorful.
We’ve made this rich, royal Mughlai Chicken Dum Biryani — a complete feast. Pair it with raita, chicken salna, or a simple salad. Try it, enjoy it, and share with loved ones.
The second edition of our Home Cooking book is now available on 21frames.in. Link is in the description. Currently available only in India.