Today, I have one rice recipe for you from the Western Ghats. So let's see the recipe for Malabar Aloo Biryani. I'm going to start with making a masala paste. In a blender, add ¼ cup grated coconut, 2 Kashmiri chillies (boiled for 10 minutes), and ½ tsp coriander-cumin powder.
Add ¼ tsp hing, ½ tsp amchur (dry mango powder), and salt to taste. Grind all these ingredients together. The masala paste is ready. Now I’ll do two processes at once. First, cooking the potatoes: take 1½ tbsp oil and turn on the flame. I have 250 g baby potatoes, pressure-cooked and peeled. Toss them.
On medium heat, cook till they get some colour. In another pan, heat 2 tbsp oil. Add 1 piece of cinnamon, 4 cloves, 1 bay leaf, 3 cardamoms, 7-8 peppercorns, and 3 shredded onions. Sauté the onions until golden brown.
The potatoes have browned. Now add the masala paste. Sauté the potatoes and paste for 2-3 minutes. Add a little more salt too.
This is ready—turn off the flame. Remove 2 tbsp of onions and keep aside for garnish. Add 1 tbsp ginger paste, 1 tbsp garlic paste, and 2 broken green chillies. Sauté for a couple of minutes. Add 1½ cups finely chopped spinach (optional).
Add 2 roughly chopped tomatoes, 2 tbsp cashews, and 2 tbsp raisins. Lightly mash the tomatoes.
Now add 1 tsp Kashmiri red chilli powder, 1 tsp garam masala, 1 tsp sugar, salt to taste, and juice of half a lemon. Mix well and cook for 2–3 minutes. Add ½ cup water and let it simmer.
This is the consistency I need. Now let’s layer everything. First layer: the potatoes. I also have 1 cup of rice, boiled in salted water. Spread the potatoes evenly, don’t mix. Then top with the boiled rice.
Drizzle some ghee. Add the fried onions. Then 1 grated carrot—for beautiful colour. Open this. Final garnish: fresh coriander leaves.
Toss all the layers lightly—just don't overmix. Done! Time to plate. Serve this Malabar Aloo Biryani with your favourite raita and some papadums. I can’t wait to dig in. Do try this recipe at home. Comment below and I’ll see you soon. Bye-bye.