Hello Pichakista Crazy Food Lovers, Namaskaram, Vanakkam, Namaskara. This time, for Pichakista Bobby, another crazy peak-level recipe – he made Ambur Biryani. I can’t describe how amazing the taste is in just words. Just by looking at it, it makes you drool, like…
When we go to Tamil Nadu, this Ambur Biryani is very famous. The moment you see it, you’ll understand. The color, the layers – everything looks spot on. What a flavor!
Seriously, it’s so mild, but when you eat it, the aroma… aroma… aroma… (repeats many times) fills your mouth and mind completely.
If you’re watching the Pichakista channel, please subscribe. For more such crazy peak-level recipes, I’m bringing them to you one by one from my kitchen with all my heart.
Let’s take 1 kg Jeera rice, 1 kg Chittimuthyalu rice, and 1 kg chicken. Let’s take the rice and chicken in two bowls.
100 grams garlic (₹40), 10 dry red chillies, 3 medium-sized tomatoes, 10 cardamoms, 10 cloves, 2 inches cinnamon, 2 green chillies.
We will make ginger paste, and garlic paste, green chilli paste, and onion paste.
Take a heavy-bottomed vessel for making biryani. Add nearly 100 ml of oil. (repetitive sounds follow)
Now I’m adding onions. After mixing the onions, keep them on medium flame for around 5 minutes and fry till they become golden brown.
Add ginger paste. Cook it slowly… slowly… (repeats slowly)
Add green chilli paste. (repeated)
1 tbsp garam masala… (repeated multiple times in Telugu: మాపిస్త్లు)
Tomatoes… (stretched out pronunciation)
Let it cook for 1 minute… (repeated: మిట్స్ = minutes)
After hearing the sizzling sound, mix everything, and cook for 5 minutes on low to medium flame, shifting between both. Every piece will get perfectly fried. Tomatoes…
3.5 glasses of hot water for 4 glasses of rice.
3 liters water, 6 tablespoons salt, for 30 minutes.
Rice… we will cook it 70% for dum biryani. Yes. Yes. Rice.
Now the chicken… (unclear murmuring and repetitive babbling while cooking)
6–7 minutes… (repeated babble)
5 minutes… (repeated babble)
After turning off the stove, you must rest it for only 15 minutes. What else? This is it! If you serve this Ambur Biryani with love, it’s truly amazing! The rice is perfectly cooked, each grain full of juicy, juicy flavor!
We also made prawns in Bheemavaram style, and prawn pakora in Kakinada style. I’ll share those recipe videos in about a week. Stay tuned! Alright? Okay!
No problem, no, no, no… (babble/cheer)
Thank you! Please subscribe. I love you all, my 3-lakh strong Pichakista family! I often see comments like “Bobby, my whole family loves you,” “We love your cooking, Bobby!” Family, family – I feel like I’m floating with happiness reading them!
The immense love you all are showing me – from brothers, sisters, cousins, and in-laws – to my entire extended family – I love you all! Amma, love you! Sister, love you! Brother, love you all!
To the one behind the camera and the one in front of it – to all my mega-crazy supporters… (Kannada: ಪಾತಾಗಾರಿಗಿ ಪಾತಾಲಿಯಂತಿ ಮಹಾಪಿಚಿಯಂದಿ)
So do try all of this! Okay Pichakista fam, I’ll meet you again with the next recipe. See you, bye! I can still feel the fragrance in the breeze…
Right now, it feels like you’re right beside me. I can feel your love in the air. Someday, someone searched for you all day. Someone smiled for you. Look, I’m your shadow. I love you – do you know that?
My dear darling, wherever I look, whatever I do, wherever I am…