[Music]
Hello everyone, welcome to home cooking
with Nihima Subramanian
My all‑time favorite meal is biryani. Now
I've tried several varieties of biryani
and made many biryani recipes.
Today I'm adding another special
biryani to the list: this is done biryani.
“Done” actually refers to a bowl
made from palm leaves, and since this
biryani is served in a ‘done’, hence the
name.
You can make this biryani either
with chicken or mutton, but I personally
love mutton. I enjoy mutton biryani, so I
am going to share this wonderful mutton
biryani recipe. I’ll also give you a couple
of tips on how to make it with chicken.
This involves a lot of steps, so make
sure you follow them perfectly
to get a beautiful outcome. So why wait? Let’s
get started and check out the recipe!
For this recipe, I’ve taken
two kilos of bone‑in mutton. This is
nice, fresh mutton. First we’re
going to marinate it. So I’m adding
two teaspoons of salt,
about one teaspoon turmeric powder,
four teaspoons of red chili powder,
one tablespoon ginger‑garlic paste,
and two tablespoons fresh curd.
Mix everything well,
rubbing the pieces with the marinade.
This will infuse lots of flavor into the meat.
You can follow these same
steps for chicken biryani too.
Now that it’s marinated, I’m
letting it rest for about 1 hour.
Meanwhile, I’ll prepare
the other masalas for the biryani.
First I’m making the onion‑green‑
chili masala paste. In a pan,
add two teaspoons oil—
I’m using gingelly oil, but any vegetable
or sunflower oil works. Add a few
pieces of cinnamon, some cardamom, cloves,
one teaspoon whole peppercorns.
If you have thick cinnamon, two pieces
will do. Then add five large thinly‑sliced
onions. Sauté for 2 minutes, then
add 10 large green chilies.
Traditional biryanis are hotter,
so you can adjust chili quantity
based on rice and meat amount.
Once onions turn translucent,
turn off heat and cool the mix.
When cool, grind it with a little water
to a fine paste. Set aside.
Next, for the green masala paste:
in the pan, add one teaspoon oil,
one bowl fresh mint leaves, one bowl chopped
coriander leaves, and a handful of fenugreek—
just enough for flavor. Sauté for 2–3 minutes
until wilted, cool completely,
then grind with a little water to a fine paste.
Now to cook the mutton:
in a pressure cooker, add
two teaspoons gingelly oil and
three tablespoons ghee—for richness. Or reduce ghee
and use more oil if preferred.
Add whole spices: one cinnamon, cloves,
cardamom pods, three star anise,
bay leaf, three mace pieces,
one teaspoon black salt? (stone flour),
one teaspoon shahi jeera, one teaspoon fennel—
keep flame low so spices don’t burn.
Add one medium thinly‑sliced onion,
saute until golden brown.
Then add one teaspoon ginger paste
and three teaspoons garlic paste—
this biryani is garlic‑rich.
Add one medium chopped tomato (optional),
it adds a lovely tanginess.
Now add the marinated mutton pieces.
For chicken, you could do it all in one pot.
But mutton takes longer, so I
pressure‑cook mutton separately, then cook rice in another.
As the meat cooks, it releases lots of juice.
Stir in onion paste, then green paste,
and mix well with the mutton.
Water ratio is very important for this biryani.
I measured one kilo of rice (about
4.75 cups, 250 ml per cup),
and used five-and-a-half cups of water.
Also scrape mixer jars with water to use all masala.
Add about two teaspoons salt (adjust to taste).
Pressure‑cook the mutton for ~20 minutes on medium‑low.
Specialty: this biryani uses short‑grain Zeeraga Sambar (Kaima) rice—
be sure to get that rice.
Wash rice, soak for 20 minutes.
The cooked mutton is rich dark green from the paste.
Transfer mutton and gravy to a large pot.
Add the soaked rice, cook
on medium‑low flame; gently mix rice and gravy.
Taste for salt, adjust for balanced flavor.
Close pot, cook 25 minutes on medium.
After 10 minutes, open the pot and gently mix
so everything blends evenly. After 25 min, rice is cooked
and moisture absorbed. Close and let sit for 10 minutes before serving.
Here is the absolutely flavorful and fragrant done biryani.
I’m serving it in a done, with chicken salna, eggs, and raita on the side.
This is a delightful biryani—I really enjoyed
sharing it with you. Hope you try
it and enjoy.
[Music]
So there you go—here is this incredible done biryani.
The flavors are just fantastic. Follow all
the steps to get it right. You can make it
with chicken or mutton. It’s best served
with raita, and you can also enjoy it
with salad or gravy. Do try the recipe,
enjoy and share with your family and friends.