In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. Peace be upon you. After a long time, I’m here to share a recipe. It's a quick and perfect biryani recipe. You can...
Always use this type of rice for biryani. It’s called Sella rice or Double Chawal rice, a type of Basmati. We measured it using this cup — we used four cups.
Sella rice is slightly hard and doesn’t break easily. We washed it well and soaked it for one hour. Then we took 1.5 kg of chicken and...
Added 1 tsp turmeric, ½ tsp cumin, ½ tsp fennel powder, and 1½ tsp Kashmiri red chili powder. Then we added yogurt — around 250 grams — and mixed everything well.
We'll crush whole biryani spices: nutmeg, mace, star anise — coarsely. Then we’ll prepare onions.
Fry the onions well until golden and crispy. Once done, remove them to a plate so they stay crisp.
Remove half the oil, leaving about 4–5 tablespoons in the pot. Then add the marinated chicken.
Add the crushed spices. We're not using any store-bought powdered masala. Using whole spices gives a very rich flavor.
We’ve taken peeled tomatoes.
Crush the tomatoes and add them to the pot. Cook until the gravy is no longer watery and oil starts separating. Stir occasionally.
Once oil separates, the chicken is well cooked. Add water, bring it to a boil, then turn off the flame.
Now for the rice water preparation...
To the water, add 5–6 green cardamoms, 2 black cardamoms, and 7–8 black peppercorns.
Add one stick of cinnamon and 5 tablespoons of salt. The salt should taste slightly more than normal. Boil until the water turns a darker shade.
Cook the rice until 80–90% done. If needed, add more salt. Some rice grains cook faster than others, so check as you go.
Strain the rice and discard the water. Now layer the cooked chicken in the same pot.
Add the rice over the chicken. Then add the fried onions on top. We are not layering multiple times — this method is simpler and results are the same.
First, add the chicken layer, then all the rice, followed by fried onions. Then add some more rice and...
Add 2–3 tablespoons of desi ghee and a bit of orange-red food color. This is optional but gives a market-style look and makes it more presentable.
Check the moisture level — when you insert a spoon, it should come out dry. That means it's ready for the final step.
Cover and let it simmer on low flame for 5 minutes. This helps stabilize the rice as the temperature gradually lowers. And there you have it — delicious biryani is ready.
Until the next recipe, Allah Hafiz.