Hello Foodies, Welcome to Whiz My Food. Today’s recipe is everyone’s favorite – Chicken Biryani. It’s a very special and flavorful dish. Let’s make this delicious recipe today.
It’s a very simple recipe, but if you follow it carefully, you’ll definitely enjoy the best biryani. So let’s start. First, in a bowl, add half a teaspoon of turmeric, half a teaspoon of red chili powder, and half a teaspoon of salt.
Then add two cups of basmati rice and mix well. If you stir it too much, the rice might break. It gives off a great aroma. Soak the rice for one hour in water.
Now to prepare the biryani masala paste, take 3 tablespoons of oil and heat it.
There’s still oil left, so in that remaining oil, add chopped green chilies and sauté for a minute. Once the green chilies slightly change color, add a handful of mint leaves, a handful of chopped coriander leaves, and a little bit of fenugreek.
Now for the biryani spices, heat 60 ml (1/4 cup) of oil. In that, add 1 star anise, 6–7 cloves, a small piece of mace, 2 bay leaves, 4–5 black peppercorns, 1-inch cinnamon stick, 1 teaspoon of black cumin, and a bit of stone flower (kalpasi).
Once the onions turn golden brown, add freshly ground ginger-garlic paste and fry. Now add the marinated chicken and cook it on high flame for 5 minutes. After that, reduce to medium flame and cook until the chicken turns light golden brown.
After 12 minutes, the chicken has turned light golden brown and is almost cooked. Then add ground paste of 20 cashews and cook it for just 30 seconds. Don’t cook it too long—just sauté the paste lightly.
Now add 3.5 cups of hot water to the mixture. Into that, add the ground mint and coriander paste. Make sure to use only hot water—this ensures the flavors are well absorbed.
After 10 minutes, remove the lid and stir gently. Don’t mash the rice, as the masala paste is already thick. As you can see, after 10 minutes, the rice is 70% cooked. At this stage, cover with a lid and cook on low flame for another 10 minutes.
After cooking for 10 minutes on low flame, open the lid and the aroma will fill your entire home—so delightful! Check it out, the biryani is perfectly cooked. It looks fluffy and soft.
The rice is perfectly cooked—it looks so soft and tender. The grains are separate and not sticky. After turning off the stove, let it rest for 15 minutes. And here it is—doesn’t it look great? Such a simple recipe!
Did you like it? Will you try it? For the detailed written recipe, visit the Whiz My Food website. And don’t forget to follow us on Instagram and share your biryani pictures with us!