Welcome to Telugu Ruchi! On this channel, we show you various flavored rice recipes like biryani, pulao, fried rice, khichdi, and more. Today, let’s look at a traditional and tasty one.
Today, we’ll see how to make flavorful Thalassery Chicken Biryani. For the masala: 10g cinnamon, 5g cloves, 10g cardamom, 10g pepper, 5g black cumin, 5g fennel, 5g star anise.
[No transcript; assumed silence or background action]
Also add: 15g cashews, 15g raisins, 75g onions, salt to taste, 2 bay leaves, 5g turmeric, half kg chicken, enough water, 50g tomatoes, 50g shallots.
75g curd, hot water as needed, 10ml oil, ½ kg Jeera Samba rice, 1g saffron, ghee as needed, 10ml lemon juice. To start, heat a pan and dry roast the cinnamon and cloves.
Add black cumin, fennel, star anise and roast lightly. Then add poppy seeds and roast briefly. Transfer to a plate and let cool.
Grind into a fine powder and set aside.
In the same pan, add ginger, garlic, green chili, coriander, mint, and salt. Grind it into a smooth paste and keep it aside.
In a clay pot, heat ghee. Fry the cashews and raisins, and set them aside. Then fry onions.
Add bay leaves and turmeric. Then add the earlier ground chicken masala paste.
Add chopped tomatoes, mix well, cover and cook for 15 minutes. Then add the chopped shallots.
Add the fried onions, the masala powder we made earlier, and curd. Mix thoroughly.
Cover and cook for 5 minutes, then set aside. In another clay pot, boil water with black cumin, salt, and oil.
Add Jeera Samba rice. Cook till 70% done. Drain the rice completely.
Layer the cooked chicken masala at the bottom. Add lemon juice, saffron water, ghee. Cover and cook on dum (steam) for 15 minutes.
Finally, garnish with the fried cashews, raisins, coriander, and onions. The delicious Thalassery Chicken Biryani is ready!
If you like our recipes, hit the like button, share it, and please subscribe to Telugu Ruchi.