Welcome! Today we are going to make Kerala's special Malabar Biryani. First, soak 1.5 cups of Seeraga Samba rice for 30 minutes. For this, I’ve taken 400 grams of chicken. Add 1 tsp chilli powder, ¼ tsp turmeric powder,
1 tsp salt and 1 tsp lemon juice. Mix it well, close and set aside for 30 minutes. Now for the biryani masala powder: take a 2-inch cinnamon stick,
1 mace, 1 tsp fennel seeds, 1 tsp poppy seeds, 1 star anise, 1 tsp cloves, and 4 cardamoms. Dry roast all the ingredients for 2 minutes.
Let it cool to room temperature. Transfer to a blender jar and grind into a fine powder. Now heat a frying pan. Pour ¾ cup oil. Add 20 cashew nuts and fry until golden brown.
Take them out and set aside. Now fry 20 raisins until they puff up. Remove and set aside. Add 3 sliced onions and sauté until deep golden brown.
It will take about 10 minutes to get this color. Remove and set aside. In the same oil, add 1 bay leaf, and 1 sliced onion. Sauté until translucent. Then add 2 tsp ginger garlic paste and 2 finely chopped green chillies.
Add ¼ tsp salt, ¼ tsp turmeric powder, ¼ tsp garam masala, and ¼ tsp red chilli powder. Mix and sauté for a few minutes. Now add 2 chopped tomatoes and cook until soft.
Add the marinated chicken and mix well. Add ½ cup mint leaves and ½ cup coriander leaves. Mix well. Add ¼ cup curd, 1.5 tsp of the biryani masala, and ¼ cup coconut milk.
Mix well, close the lid, and cook for 10 minutes. After 10 minutes, crush some roasted onions into the masala. The biryani masala is now ready. Heat a pressure cooker and add 2 tsp ghee.
Once hot, add ½ tsp cumin seeds, ½ tsp pepper, 4 cardamoms, 1 star anise, 1 mace, 2-inch cinnamon stick, 1 sprig curry leaves, and ½ bay leaf. Sauté for 1–2 minutes.
Now add the soaked rice and mix well. Pour 2½ cups water for 1½ cups rice.
Add ½ tsp salt, mix, close the lid and cook for 10 minutes. Once the rice is ready, take a thick-bottomed vessel and grease it with 2 tsp ghee.
For the first layer, add the cooked chicken masala. Sprinkle coriander leaves and optionally some mint leaves. Then sprinkle some of the roasted onions.
Now layer the cooked rice on top. Again, sprinkle coriander leaves, mint leaves, and roasted onions.
Add a few pineapple chunks, a little biryani masala, ½ tsp rose water, and ½ tsp milk with a pinch of turmeric.
Add roasted cashew nuts and raisins. Finally, drizzle 1 tsp ghee. Heat a dosa pan and place the biryani pot on top.
Seal the lid with all-purpose flour dough. Close tightly so there's no gap. Let it cook on dum for 15 minutes. Now the biryani is ready! Try this delicious recipe at home. Subscribe, like, comment, and share. Thanks for watching!