Welcome to T-South Chennai! Today, as many of you requested, I’m going to show you my favorite – Kerala-style Thalassery Chicken Biryani. This biryani is very flavorful and has a rich, traditional taste.
If you have nutmeg, take a small piece. I’m using nutmeg powder here and will add it as powder. Now we can dry roast everything.
Once it's roasted, you’ll immediately get a great aroma. Now just sauté it until it's nice and aromatic.
Take around 8 pieces of green chili – you can adjust based on how spicy you want it. This amount was perfect for us. Don’t grind these – use them as is.
Once the oil is hot, add three sliced onions. Sauté well. No need to brown completely – just soften them enough.
Sauté until the raw smell goes. Now we can add the chicken. I’m using a whole chicken weighing around 800 grams. Cook until it changes color slightly.
Add 1/4 tsp of turmeric powder. Then add 1 tbsp of the biryani masala paste. In this biryani, only green chilies are used for heat.
Add about half a cup each of mint and coriander leaves. Sauté for a while. The tomatoes should soften. Add half a cup of curd at this stage and mix well.
Add the juice of one lemon. Cover and cook. Don’t add any water – chicken releases enough juices. Cook on low flame for about 10 minutes.
Once it turns light golden, stop frying. Don't over-fry or it’ll darken and not taste good. This is the perfect color. Heat 2 tbsp of ghee in a new pan.
Once onions turn golden, remove them. Fry some raisins. In the same ghee, fry 2 pieces of cinnamon, 4 cloves, and 4 cardamoms.
We had soaked the jeera samba rice earlier. You don’t have to soak too long, but a little is good.
We already added salt to the masala. Now add required salt for the rice. Mix well, close the lid, and let it sit like you would for ghee rice.
Let’s open and check the chicken. I kept it on low flame. See how thick the masala is? Now add the fried onions and mix well. That’s it – masala is ready.
After 5 minutes, rice is ready. Mix with the masala and prepare for dum. Turn the gas back on low flame. Add mint and coriander on top again.
Top it with some fried onions and raisins. Keep layering as needed.
Sprinkle a bit more of the biryani masala. Again, add mint, coriander, and fried raisins. Optionally add some saffron milk too.
Now close the pan and dum for 15–20 minutes. First 5 minutes on high, then 10 minutes low. Then place a dosa tawa under the pot and dum another 10 minutes on low.
Wow, it looks amazing! Perfectly layered and cooked with flavorful masala at the bottom.
Tastes just like Kerala restaurant biryani. I really loved it.
Serve it with raita, boiled egg, and chicken fry. It’s super delicious. Now hot Thalassery Chicken Biryani is ready! I’m going to enjoy it now. The payasam is also yummy!
Hope you all loved this video! If yes, like and share it with your friends. Don’t miss such great recipes – keep watching! Don’t forget to subscribe to T-South Chennai!