Hello friends! Welcome to Suna Saapi Kitchen. How are you all? I hope you're doing well. Today on our channel, we're going to see how to make Dindigul Thalappakatti-style mutton biryani just like in restaurants.
Not only that, but I’ve uploaded many types of biryani recipes on our channel. I've already uploaded the Dindigul Thalappakatti mutton biryani. All the links are in the description. Make sure to check them out.
The measurements I'm using for this Thalappakatti biryani are perfect. Please measure accurately. For this video, I’ve taken meat sufficient for three servings. You can see the meat I’ve used has nice fat marbling.
Maratti mokku is a very important ingredient for this biryani, so don’t skip it. Just one star anise, a little bit of nutmeg, two pieces of kalpasi (stone flower), and a quarter piece of mace – these are essential.
These are the main ingredients. Don't reduce or skip them. We’re going to grind this masala fresh. Keep the masala aside for now, and later we’ll make it into a paste.
For this mutton biryani, I’ve taken 1.3 kg of mutton. Wash the mutton thoroughly. We'll pressure cook it, so use a cooker that's suitable for the quantity.
Cook it for about 5-6 whistles. Only mutton is needed here for tempering. Mutton is all we need. Mutton is all we need. (repeated unintelligibly)
I’ve used only a quarter piece of nutmeg – don't add more, or the biryani will become bitter. Now we’ll add our ground masala with cashews. Keep it ready.
This biryani has a traditional and authentic appearance.
Jeeraga samba rice is typically used – it gives the best taste. I’ve also used that here. Wash and soak the rice well before use. I’ve taken 1.3 kg of rice.
Now that the biryani setup is ready, let’s start tempering it. I’m using a heavy-bottomed pan. I’ve added groundnut oil instead of sunflower oil. It gives better flavor.
After adding water, cover with a lid. When the water boils, it can splash up and cause issues, so covering it prevents mess and lets it cook evenly and quietly.
You might wonder how much water to add – break the dried red chilies and add water (repeats phrase multiple times).
Now add the paste we prepared – ginger-garlic paste, coriander, mint, green chili, and shallots. If you have big onions, chop them and add too.
After adding the ginger-garlic paste, sauté it for 5-7 minutes until the oil separates – that’s the right consistency. Then add ¾ bunch each of coriander and mint.
After sautéing the herbs, add the cooked mutton (without any water). Sauté the mutton for 5 minutes until it slightly changes color.
After sautéing for about 5 minutes, now it’s time to add the ground masala paste. I’ve added around two tablespoons of the entire ground paste.
If you’ve ground a lot, just add 2 tablespoons and save the rest. As soon as you add it, you’ll get an amazing aroma.
According to your spice level, adjust the red chili powder. I’ve added 1 teaspoon chili powder, 1 teaspoon coriander powder.
Let everything cook well and blend. Now, we’ll add yogurt. I’ve added about 2 cups of yogurt.
Add the yogurt (repeats several times).
Add coriander and mint again (repeats several times).
Now we’ve added yogurt, chili, tomato – everything is mixed well. You’ll know it’s ready when the oil separates and it smells amazing.
I’ve added enough water for 2 cups of rice. Since the masala doesn’t have much liquid, I added extra water accordingly. The rice-to-water ratio is 1:1.
If you're using old rice, it absorbs more water. If you're using new rice, it doesn't need as much. Adjust water accordingly.
Even after adding the rice, keep adjusting and checking the water level (repeats several times).
Stir everything and mix well (repeats "water" multiple times again).
Again, mix it all well. The water level should be appropriate. But if you're using basmati rice, don’t mix like this – be gentle.
The water is just right now. Time to put it on *dum* (slow steam cooking). I’ve added 3 tablespoons of ghee. Cover with banana leaf if available, then seal with foil.
Preheat an old dosa tawa (griddle), place the biryani pot on top, and cook on medium-low flame for 20 minutes. Then turn off the flame and leave it for another 10 minutes.
After 10 minutes, turn off the stove. It will stay warm for some time.
Now I’m mixing the rice gently. I’m placing it on banana leaves again to finish off the dum process. Thalappakatti mutton biryani gets its real flavor from this.
Again, seal and leave it like this for another half an hour. Place a heavy utensil on top. After 30 minutes, you can open it. You’ll see the rice is perfectly cooked.
The rice is fluffy, perfectly cooked and separate. It looks amazing and is perfect to serve. You can pair it with mango pickle, brinjal curry, fried chilies, and dalcha.
I’ve also made banana stem salad, rasagulla, mango, onion raita, and payasam. When served together, it tastes just like wedding biryani. Dindigul Thalappakatti mutton biryani is absolutely delicious.
If you liked this video, don’t forget to like and share it with your friends and family. Thank you so much!