Today we are going to do a chicken dum biriyani. Its a very easy recipe. All of you might be knowing how to make biriyani. Those who are studying will need some tips. We are going to do a video like that. My video might be very long. So I shall try to make it as much as possible. We are going to do it with 1kg chicken. We have to marinate the chicken first. Then we shall do the rest.
1½tsp to ¾tsp turmeric pdr 1½tsp pepper pdr 1½ tbsp curd Salt to taste
Mix well and keep aside. We are adding curd at this stage to make the chicken soft. Lets keep this aside for 30mts. You can do this before making the biriyani. So keep it aside for 30mts.
Now we are going to make a special biriyani masala for this biriyani. Always be careful while making biriyani. The taste should not be less when making garam masala.
If you are using coriander leaves or mint leaves, use fresh ones. If you are using ginger garlic, use local ones. That way you will get the correct taste and smell of the biriyani. I have taken 14 pieces of this biriyani masala here. 4 cardamoms, 4 cloves, 1 small piece of cashew nuts. Never add more when taking cashew nuts. 1.25tsp will be enough.
1.25tsp coriander seeds, 1tsp pepper, 1 piece bay leaf, 1.5tsp sajeera
1.25tsp fennel seeds 1tsp fennel seeds 2 pieces of cinnamon 1tsp white cashews 1 piece of cashew nuts 2 red chillies These are the ingredients for our biriyani masala
Now we have to heat it well and then grind it. We shall heat the rest of the cashew nuts and then grind it.
Do not let it burn while frying. If you add the cashew nuts, it will get burnt fast. Once it becomes hot, we shall keep it aside in this pan. Once it cools down, we shall grind it in the mixi. Do not keep it in the same pan after frying. Since it is hot, it may get burnt.
Next we are going to fry some onions for this biriyani. For that I have cut 2 onions into thin slices. If you have a slicer, you can grate it and make it thin. Only then you can fry it well. If you want to avoid this stage, you can do it. You can even add 2 onions to the masala. But for this you can make a tastier biriyani. Heat 2-3 batches of oil and fry it.
When you fry the shallots,the shallots will turn into this colour and get fried fast. Do not wait for it to get burnt. When it reaches a golden colour,we can remove it from the oil. Then it will turn into a crispy colour. When we remove it from the oil,if we remove it to a strainer,it won't be crispy. Its better to remove it to a tissue.
The onions are fried well. Keep this aside. Now we shall fry some cashew nuts and raisins in the same oil. You can take the cashew nuts and raisins as you like.
Our cashew and raisins have been fried. Keep it aside. Now lets begin to make our biriyani masala. Heat a pan and add 2tbsp ghee to it. I have taken vegetable ghee here. If you dont like ghee, you can add some of the oil we had fried earlier.
When the oil is hot add 1 1⁄4 cup crushed ginger,1⁄4 cup crushed garlic and 5-6 green chillies. You can adjust the spice according to your taste. If the chillies are very spicy, 5 will be enough. We dont need more spice for biriyani. Now add this to the oil.
This is our 1.25 cup of ginger. We are going to crush it in this. We dont need more than 1kg of ginger and garlic. Add it to the oil.
We don't have to grind the ginger and garlic. I don't think it tastes good when it is very paste. You can crush it. If you can't crush it in Kerala, its better to do it that way. I have crushed it in the mixi. When the raw smell of ginger and garlic goes, add 2 onions cut lengthwise. These are big onions. If you are using small onions, take 3 of them. Add little salt to this.
We have to be careful while adding salt to the biriyadi. We have already added some salt while marinating the chicken. When we make rice, it will have salt in it. So the salt required for the masala will be sufficient. Let this get cooked well. It shouldnt get golden brown in colour. When the onions are well cooked, add 2 small chopped tomatoes to it.
A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful of chopped coriander leaves A handful
Saute the chicken for 2 minutes on high flame. Now the chicken is sauted well. Now add 1.75tbsp of the biriyani masala that we had prepared earlier. We shall add 1.5tbsp more later. We shall use it when we make dum. The masala that we had roasted earlier is perfect for 1kg biriyani.
When we make biriyani masala,it is always better to make more and store it. If you powder it while making biriyani,it will give a fresh smell. Saute it well with this. Even if you are powdering biriyani masala,keep it closed well. So that the smell doesn't go.
Now add 1tbsp of lemon juice to this. We have added 1.5tbsp of curd. Now check the salt needed for the chicken. If you want you can add more salt to the masala and cook it. You dont have to add water to this. The chicken will take 10-12mts to get cooked. Cook this on medium to low flame.
The chicken has been cooked well. We haven't added any water to it. We need to dry it well. Before that we shall add 3tbsp grated coconut and 8-10 cashew nuts to the mixi and grind it. If you soak it in water for a while, it will be easy to grind it. Do not add more coconut while grinding. If you add more, the masala will be more.
Mix all these well. You can use this tip for any biriyani. You can add cashew nuts or coconut as per your taste. Never add more when adding coconut.
Add all these and cook the chicken well. The masala should thicken more. The chicken should be cooked well. If the chicken is not cooked well, the biriyani wont taste good. The chicken should be cooked well. So let's wait till then.
Now the gravy is ready. We need this much of gravy for this biriyani. Lets garnish this biriyani with some coriander leaves and mint leaves. Not much. Just for the flavour. Add 2 pinches of biriyani masala at this time. Close this well and keep aside. Now lets make the ghee rice for the biriyani. Dont forget to close it well. It will lose its smell.
Now lets begin to make the rice. We are going to make this biriyani with 3.5 cups of Jeerakashala rice. This biriyani is always good with Jeerakashala rice. You can make it with Basmati rice too. But it will be tastier. Many have asked me which brand I am using when making Jeerakashala rice. I am using Nirapara Wayanadan Kaima Jeerakashala.
This is the rice that I have chosen.Its a good smell and I think its a good rice The rice of Golden Chef is also good.You can use any rice you want When we take this type of rice,we need to soak it for some time before making the ghee rice If you dont soak it for some time,the rice will be hard to chew We can use the rice that we get in Kerala directly in ghee rice
I have used the golden chef of Neerabara and our Natchez Joshi. We have to soak this for 20-25mts. We need 3.5 cups of rice. Wash it well and then soak it for 20-25mts or maximum 30mts. Then we shall make soft ghee rice. When we soak it and wash it, add little salt and wash it well. Then we will get a good rice.
Heat a pan for making ghee rice. Add 2-3tbsp ghee to it. You can add ghee as per your taste. If you add more ghee, the ghee rice will get a tasty glising. We are not making biriyani daily. So add ghee as per your taste.
When the ghee is hot add 6 cloves,4-5 cardamoms,2 pieces of cinnamon,2 pinches of fennel seeds. If you want you can add more fennel seeds. Now add 1tbsp of finely chopped onions. You can adjust the amount of onions according to your taste.
3 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1
When the water comes to a boil,add the required salt into it. When adding the salt,add it carefully because we need more salt for the rice to absorb the water. Now add the washed rice into it.
Once the rice is boiled, close the lid and cook it for 10-12mts. It may vary according to the rice. At this time cook it on low flame. Do not cook it on high flame. It may get cooked fast. Stir it often.
Now our ghee rice is ready. Do not wait for the water to dry up. If the rice is not cooked enough, you can sprinkle some water over it and close it again. Then you will get the correct rice. Our biriyani is ready. Now we shall add the rice over the masala and cook it.
Add the fried onions and mix well. This will give a good taste to the biriyani masala. Mix well.
We are going to make the dum in this vessel itself. If you are afraid of it sticking to the bottom, you can remove the masala and add 2-3tbsp of rice over it. But if you do it the way we do it, it will not stick to the bottom.
Now to get a good colour and smell of the biriyani,take 2-3 tbsp of cow's milk or coconut milk. Add 1.25 tsp of turmeric powder. If you have saffron in your hand,you can add 2-3 of it to the milk. It will give a good smell and taste to the biriyani. To get a good smell to the milk,add 1 tsp of rose water.
It gives a special taste and smell to our biriyani. Mix well and transfer it to a plate. Add little by little while adding the rice. It doesnt look very good when you see it like this. But it will turn yellowish when the rice is done.
Now we shall add rice over the chicken masala. We should always add rice when the ghee rice is hot. At that time we should take all the necessary ingredients and keep it ready. If the rice is not hot enough we wont get the dum. So we shall add 2-3 layers of rice over it.
After adding a layer of rice,we can pour the milk and turmeric powder mix over it.We can add little here and there. We can add some coriander leaves and mint leaves over it.We don't need much when adding coriander leaves and mint leaves.Because if we add lots of biriyani,we won't get the taste we want.So we can add as per our taste.We need to add more coriander leaves and mint leaves over it.
If you want you can add some cashew nuts and raisins. You can add as per your taste. Next add some fried onions. When you smoke you can add little ghee. You can adjust the amount of ghee as per your taste.
Add little bit of the rest of the biriyani masala to this. Now add little lemon juice over this. This helps to get rid of the sourness of the rice. Make sure to add lemon juice according to the sourness of the masala.
These are the ingredients to be added in the 1st layer. Now we shall add the rice and the rest of the ingredients in the 1st layer. Its very tasty to have biriyani with dum after preparing all the ingredients. I liked it very much. Some people may not like coriander leaves and mint leaves. So I am not telling the exact measurements. It depends on your taste.
Now the ghee rice and the rest of the ingredients are well mixed. Now we shall do the dum. I am sticking some maida dough on the bottom of the vessel.
So that the smell of the biriyani doesn't go out. You can cover it well. Its difficult to stick it with maida flour. Some people find it difficult to stick it in a non stick pan. If it is like that, you can cover it with a foil paper. Its easy to use when you are in Kerala. It will be easy to stick it on the outside of the stove. Lets cover it with some maida.
Now we have to dum the biriyani properly. After that heat a pan and place the biriyani on top of it.
First put it on medium flame for 2 minutes. Then cook it on low flame for 10-12 minutes. It shouldnt stick to the bottom. Reduce the flame to the lowest. By the time it becomes dry, the biriyani will be done.
When you keep it on a low flame for 10-12 minutes,the steam will spread all over the biriyani and the sides will become dry. At that time switch off the gas. After 15-20 minutes we can break the dum. Now the biriyani has become a good dum. The steam has spread all over the biriyani. Now lets break the dum. It will be difficult to break it with your hands. So just hold the sides with a knife.
The smell of rose water in the biriyani will be very good. The biriyani will have a very good smell. Now we have to mix the rice on top of the biriyani. Mix only the rice with the masala and then transfer it to another bowl. We can serve the biriyani with the masala and rice. Mix all these well.
Mix well and keep aside. Now lets see how to serve this biriyani. This biriyani is served with chicken masala and rice over it. I have taken a bowl for a shape. Take 1-2 pieces of biriyani and place it over it.
If you want you can add an egg to it. Its optional. Now add the rice over it. When serving biriyani, its better to remove the cinnamon, cardamom and cardamom. Those who have it can have it easily.
When we make masala dum,there is no problem of it sticking to the bottom See,there is no such problem.We can serve it in another bowl This is a tasty biriyani without any masala lumps You can see the rice here.It is not sticking to the bottom.It has a white and yellowish colour.It is a tasty biriyani It tastes almost the same as the biriyani we have from outside So definitely you can try it out As I said in the beginning,our video is a bit long
I have explained it to those who are learning to make biriyani. Those who are good at making biriyani may feel bored. But it will be useful for those who are learning. Do try it out and let me know your feedback. If you liked the video, dont forget to like and share it. Those who havent subscribed, do subscribe. Thank you.