Hello everyone, hello! I'm Nahima Subramaniyan, welcome to Tamil! Hello Tamil, hello Tamil, hello Tamil, hello Tamil, hello Tamil, hello Tamil, hello!
Today I'm going to make Ambur Chicken Biryani. I'm using Seeraga Samba rice. I've taken 500 ml of it. Wash the rice well and soak it for 20 minutes. Next, in a wide pan, add 4 teaspoons of ghee.
Next, add 1 tablespoon of oil. Add cinnamon, cloves, and cardamom. Add 3 sliced onions and sauté until golden brown. Then add 2 teaspoons of ginger paste and 2 teaspoons of garlic paste.
After sautéing for a minute, add 3 chopped tomatoes and continue sautéing.
Add salt to taste, then add 2 teaspoons of turmeric powder and chili powder. Mix well. I'm using chili powder in this recipe, but you can also use chili paste if you prefer.
Add the chicken pieces and mix well. Then add 1 cup of hot water and the juice of one lemon. Add 1 tablespoon of yogurt and a handful of mint leaves.
Add a handful of coriander leaves. Mix everything well, cover, and cook on medium flame for 10 minutes. Meanwhile, in another pot, boil water with a little salt. Now add the soaked rice.
Cook the rice until it's 75% done. Once it's three-fourths cooked, turn off the heat, drain the water, and set the rice aside. The chicken has cooked for 10 minutes. Next, heat a dosa tawa (griddle), place the pot on it, and add the rice on top.
Spread the rice gently and evenly. Add 2–3 teaspoons of ghee. Finally, sprinkle some mint and coriander leaves. Cover the pot and seal the edges with dough like this, and cook on medium heat.
The biryani has come out perfectly! Mix it lightly and serve hot.
You’ve just seen how to make delicious Ambur-style chicken biryani. If you follow this method, it’ll definitely turn out amazing. Serve hot right after cooking, maybe with some yogurt raita. Everyone will love it, for sure!