Hello Foodies, welcome to Wish My Food. Today’s special is Mughlai Chicken Dum Biryani. Compared to regular dum biryani, this one is much more aromatic, tastier, and rich in flavors. It’s also very easy and uses readily available ingredients.
Enjoy happily, let's start! First, take medium-sized chicken pieces. Add 2 tbsp cashew paste, 2 tbsp...
...green chili paste, 1 tsp coriander powder, 1 tsp roasted cumin powder, 1 tsp garam masala, and 2 tsp red chili powder.
Add 1/4 tsp turmeric, 1/4 tsp cardamom powder, 1/4 tsp pepper powder, 1 star anise, 1-inch cinnamon, 5–6 cloves, 1 tsp shahi jeera, 1 marathi moggu (kapok bud), and a biryani leaf. Add everything to the chicken as marinade.
Also add 1 tsp ghee, 1/4 cup fried onions, and a pinch of saffron soaked in water. Massage the chicken well with the marinade 1–2 times.
In a wide pot, add 1-inch cinnamon, 4 cardamoms, 4 cloves, 1 marathi moggu, 1 tsp shahi jeera, 1 star anise, 2 biryani leaves, 1 mace, and 2 green chilies.
When the water starts to boil well, add 1.5 cups aged basmati rice. Also add 2 tbsp chopped mint, chopped coriander, and half a lemon’s juice.
Now cook the rice up to 60% on high flame. In about 10 minutes it reaches this stage. It should still have a slight bite, not fully cooked.
Spread the rice evenly on top of the chicken. Sprinkle 1/4 cup ghee, and pour in the chicken juices collected during marination or pre-cooking.
Fry some onions in 1/4 cup oil; I had about that much oil left, and I’m using it here. Cover the pot and cook on high flame for 8 minutes, then on low for 7 minutes.
The cooking is complete, and the aroma is amazing. See how perfect it looks? The fragrance should last till the very last bite. So flavorful and aromatic.
Do try this recipe and share how it turned out. Don’t forget to tag us on Instagram at WishMyFood and visit wishmyfood.com.