Greetings to everyone
We’re going to see how to make a biryani using Seeraga Samba rice and masala. It’s called Dindigul Chicken Biryani. I’ve explained everything step-by-step in this video, so be sure to watch the whole video.
For this, I’ve taken 750 grams of chicken with bone, cut into small pieces and kept ready. I’ve washed 1 kg of Seeraga Samba rice twice and soaked it. Now, we’ll prepare the masala first, starting with a ground paste.
You can put everything in a mixer jar: about 12 green chilies, 5 small pieces of ginger, garlic cloves — grind it all with a little water. Next, let’s make a spice powder: about 12 cardamoms, 10 cloves, 3 pieces of cinnamon, 5–7 mace strands…
Add all of that to a mixer jar along with half a piece of nutmeg, 3 bay leaves, about 10 black stone flowers (kalpasi). Grind everything well into a biryani masala powder and keep it aside.
We need to sauté everything well in oil until the raw smell goes away. Add 1/4 tsp of turmeric powder. Since the onion is ground raw, the raw smell will still be there — sauté it well to remove that.
After it’s sautéed well like this, add 1 tbsp red chili powder, 6 tbsp cumin powder, and 1 tbsp coriander powder.
Next, add salt as needed and sauté all the masalas thoroughly. Then add about 350 ml of curd and cook well with the masala. Add a handful of chopped coriander and mint leaves.
Now add the marinated chicken (cut with bone). Add the 750g chicken to the masala and sauté it well until the masala coats the chicken. Cover and cook.
Once it's half cooked, squeeze in juice from 2 large or 3 small lemons. This adds a nice tangy flavor and balances the taste.
After adding lemon juice, add another handful of coriander and mint. Then add 1 liter of water (for 1 kg of rice). This ratio is perfect for cooking the chicken and balancing the gravy consistency.
Once the water comes to a boil, add the soaked Seeraga Samba rice. We are going to cook this on dum (steam). Stir occasionally; otherwise, the rice might stick to the bottom.
Keep stirring now and then. Then close the lid and don’t leave it open for too long. Otherwise, the water will evaporate and there won't be enough moisture. So keep it closed and cook on dum, checking occasionally.
Now we’ll put it on dum (steam cooking). I’ve kept a tawa (griddle) heated separately. Place the biryani pot on top of it. For the first 6–7 minutes, cook on high flame so that steam builds up properly inside.
Let it steam for 15 minutes. After that, turn off the stove and let it rest for 15 more minutes. Don’t open immediately, or the rice won’t fluff up properly. Resting helps the rice settle and become soft.
The aroma of the garam masala and Seeraga Samba rice is amazing. This Dindigul-style chicken biryani can be made grandly at home. It’s best enjoyed hot, and the taste lingers for hours!
Serve it with a little ghee on top and some onion raita. Kids and adults alike will love this biryani. If you liked this video, please like and share it.
With the love of mother’s milk and the tang of tamarind — thank you!