Hello foodies, welcome to Wish My Food! Today’s special is Tamil Nadu’s famous Ambur Chicken Dum Biryani. This is a traditional Muslim recipe from Ambur, a town in Tamil Nadu. It’s rich in flavor and very spicy and tasty. The best part is that both the chicken and rice are cooked together in dum (steam). So, there’s no issue like undercooked chicken or hard rice.
Every time, it turns out to be a super hit recipe. Let’s start. First, take 2 cups (approx. 185g per cup) of Jeera rice. Add fennel seeds along with the rice. Wash the rice thoroughly once and soak it for some time, so that the aroma is retained.
In Ambur Chicken Biryani, the spice comes from red chilies alone. You need to use dried red chilies. Break them and soak them slightly. If you don’t have stone mortar, you can use a mixer.
Grind into a smooth paste. Now take a biryani pot and heat 1/3 cup (approx. 80 ml) of oil. Once it’s hot, add 4 pieces of cinnamon stick and 4 cloves.
Avoid using pre-ground spices. Whole spices give a better taste. Fry until the onions turn light golden brown. Then add 2 tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste.
Once it starts frying well, add 2 teaspoons of coriander powder. When the oil starts separating, add 1 kg of chicken cut into medium pieces. Cook until the chicken turns golden brown on medium flame.
It takes about 15 minutes for the chicken to get half-cooked. Always remember, after cleaning the chicken, it should remain inside the marinade for at least 30 minutes. That’s when chicken cooks perfectly during dum. Even chicken shop people know this.
Once cooked, add 3 chopped tomatoes, 3 slit green chilies, enough salt, ½ cup (about 125 ml) whisked curd, 1½ tablespoons garam masala, and 1 cup (250 ml) water. Mix everything well.
When chicken is 90% cooked, take one cup of gravy out. Add 1 tablespoon lemon juice, a little chopped coriander and mint leaves, mix well, turn off the stove, and set it aside.
Into another pot, add 3 tablespoons of salt. Add the soaked rice into boiling water. Also, add 2 teaspoons of oil. Cook the rice up to 80% only. Everyone knows what 80% cooked rice looks like.
Now, take the 80% cooked rice and cook it until it reaches 90%. (Note: This line seems to have some repeated and jumbled words, likely due to subtitle OCR issues.)
After that, pour the reserved gravy over the rice. Then add the leftover rice water (starch water) over the biryani. Seal the pot with a lid and cook on low flame for 20 minutes.
After 20 minutes, check – it will look perfect. No need to do anything else. This is the perfect texture. At this stage, add 2 tablespoons of ghee, a little chopped coriander and mint, mix gently, and fluff the biryani slowly.
If it's crumbly, it’s like Hyderabadi biryani. But in Tamil Nadu biryani, the rice is softer. It should be soft enough to hold in a spoon without breaking. That’s the texture expected here.
Serve it with a side of boiled egg, chicken sherva (gravy), and chilled raita for the next-level combination. Did you like it? Will you try it? If so, don’t forget to check the detailed recipe and subscribe!