HELLO, PICHUKISTA CRAZY FOOD LOVERS! ICAR RACHAR RAMBULE is here! First, greetings to all Kannadigas! How are you all? I hope everyone is always doing well on this Earth!
Original Biryani - Picchekista Bobby Style
Happy, happy — did you eat? Let’s make it spicy again!
This is Dunne Biryani from Shivaji Military Hotel, Bangalore – very famous! They make it with mutton and chicken. Nearby, they cook chicken separately. When you see it, your mouth starts watering. The combination is just extraordinary!
The taste is amazing! They use a 50-50 mix of oil and ghee with Chitti Mutyala rice. That’s why it’s super special. And the combination of spices used is mind-blowing. Truly makes you go crazy with delight!
Every part of my tongue is activated! So much flavor, it’s overwhelming!
You can't eat this daily. It’s rare and rich. But when you do get a chance, don’t miss trying it! Bobby bro... wow! What a biryani this is! How did I miss this all these days?
Watch the recipe till the end, no skipping!
Let’s start making Dunne Biryani. It serves a big group. For 1.5 kg of chicken, add enough salt. Add about 200 grams of yogurt.
[Repetitive syllables — unintelligible chanting or filler]
Once you've seen the video, measure out the ingredients accordingly. If something is not available at home, ask a neighbor or order from BigBasket!
Add 2 bunches of coriander (about 2 full cups). Also, 20 dark green chilies – absolutely necessary.
Another important ingredient is ghee, ghee, ghee, ghee... [repeatedly said for emphasis]
This water infused with rose petals is very beneficial. Let me show my love that way. Rose... rose...
Finely chop onions and tomatoes like this.
Now we prepare the masala powder: 1.5-inch cinnamon, 1 mace flower, 1.5 Marathi moggu, 4 cardamoms, 4 cloves, 2 tablespoons fennel, 1 tablespoon black pepper, 1 bay leaf — all blended.
Once it’s fresh, add all of it and lightly fry on medium flame for 1 minute, then 3 more minutes on low flame.
Remove and cool it on a plate, and apply oil thoroughly. Now, to make the biryani, take a large vessel, add 2 cups of oil (around 8 tablespoons).
Add 3 bay leaves and fry them for 2 minutes. Add the chopped onions and sauté for 3 minutes on medium flam