You.
Assalamu Alaikum! Hello everyone! Welcome to Taste of Chennai. Today we are going to see how to make the famous Ambur Mutton Biriyani at home.
I have taken Jeera Samba rice to make Ambur Mutton Biriyani. If you want, you can use Basmati rice too, but traditionally Jeera Samba rice is used. I’ve taken about 600 grams. You can adjust the quantity of mutton based on how much rice you’re using. I’ve taken 800 grams of mutton for 600 grams of rice. Take 100 grams of ginger garlic paste—that’s about 4-5 tablespoons.
I’ve taken around 20 red chillies. Soak them in hot water for a while and grind into a fine paste. Use around 20 chillies for the rice quantity I mentioned—you’ll get the right level of spice. If you take fewer, it won’t be spicy enough. If you like it spicy, you can use around 25. I’m adding 3 tablespoons of ghee to the pan, followed by about half a cup of oil.
Once the oil is hot, add 2 pieces of cinnamon, 10 cardamoms, and 10 cloves. I’ve taken 350 grams of onion—slice and keep them aside. We will be adding the onions in two batches. Let’s add a bit first and the remaining half later.
Sauté the onions for a while. You don’t need to sauté them too much like in other biriyanis—just until they turn a light pink. Once it’s sautéed to that level, add the ginger garlic paste and fry until the raw smell goes away.
After the ginger garlic paste is cooked, add the red chilli paste we prepared. Fry well until the oil separates.
Frying it in oil like this gives the biriyani a natural color. If you don’t want to use red chilli paste, you can use red chilli powder instead. Both will work well.
At this stage, add the mutton and fry it for 10 minutes. You can also add pressure-cooked mutton directly. Now add salt as needed for the rice.
At this stage, add the remaining onions and mix well.
Now I’m adding half a cup of thick curd.
Mix it well. We’ve used very few ingredients in this biriyani, so it's easier to make compared to other biriyanis. In other types, each ingredient must be cooked thoroughly. That’s not the case here—just add them one by one and it comes together quickly. The biriyani will be ready in about an hour.
Next, add the tomatoes. I’ve taken 300 grams. Mix well and wait until they are mashed. Along with this, add half a cup of mint and coriander leaves. Mix everything well and let it cook.
Cover and cook for 10 minutes. The tomato must mash well and oil should separate—wait till that happens. Stir occasionally to prevent sticking. After the oil has separated, add the juice of half a lemon.
Now let’s measure the water. Use hot water since the mutton is raw—it will cook faster. Add 2 cups of water for every 1 cup of rice. I’ve taken 3 cups of rice, so that’s 6 cups of water, plus 3 cups extra for cooking the mutton—total 9 cups. Add water as you normally do for rice, with 3 extra cups for the mutton.
If the mutton is good quality, it will cook in 30 minutes. Now let’s mix it and close the lid. We’ll check after half an hour. It’s been 20 minutes—let’s open it and check a piece.
The mutton is only 50% cooked, it needs more time. Let’s close the lid and wait 15 more minutes. Check again—if it's cooked well, then we can add the rice.
Mix it well and close the lid. Keep the flame at medium. I’ll open it after 10 minutes.
Once the water has dried out well, we’ll place it on dum (steam cook). I added a little ghee on top. I placed an old dosa stone below and left it on dum for 10 to 15 minutes, then turned off the heat. After switching off, let it rest for 10 minutes. Now the hot and delicious Ambur Mutton Biriyani is ready!
Now let’s serve it hot.
It looks very yummy and amazing. Try making biriyani in different ways—everyone at home will definitely love it. When you make this biriyani, the aroma will fill the whole house. The taste is excellent—try it and let me know how it turned out!
I hope you all liked this video. If you did, please like and share it with your friends and family. There are more interesting recipes like this coming on our channel. If you want to keep watching them, don’t forget to subscribe to our channel, Taste of Chennai. I’ll see you in another exciting video tomorrow. Thank you so much for watching.