Hello foodies, welcome to Ismail Food Evality! Today we’re making the world-famous Malabar Chicken Dum Biryani. You may have eaten many chicken dum biryanis, but this Malabar version is unique — its method, ingredients, and flavors are all different. Try it once — you’ll definitely love it. Let’s start!
Add 1/4 nutmeg and two mace blades.
About half a tablespoon of black pepper. [unintelligible due to long stretch]
This turns into a powder like this. You can store it in airtight jars and preserve it easily for 2–3 months. Now, for chicken masala, take 1-inch ginger and 5–6 garlic cloves.
For the chicken gravy, heat ¼ cup oil in a pan. Add 150g thinly sliced onions and fry until golden brown.
Once the onions begin to fry, add some salt to speed up the process. Once they turn golden brown, add 2 curry leaves and continue frying.
Once the masala paste rises to the top in the oil, add 1 tsp coriander powder, ⅛ tsp turmeric powder, and ½ tsp of the homemade garam masala. Cook the masala until it thickens.
After cooking for 3–4 minutes, finely chop 2 tomatoes and add them. Mix well. Once they soften, add curd and mix thoroughly. After 7–8 minutes of cooking, you’ll see oil rising to the top.
After 12 minutes, the chicken is about 80% cooked. The rest will cook on dum. Add some chopped mint and coriander on top.
Now, for biryani rice, take 2 cups of short-grain “Chitti Muthyalu” rice. I'm using the Sudhanya brand short rice for this recipe.
Once rice is 80% cooked, in a separate pan, melt ¼ cup ghee. Add ¼ cup cashews and fry until golden. When they change color, add 10–15 raisins and fry lightly.
In the remaining ghee, add 2 medium sliced onions and fry till golden brown. While onions are frying, add 2-inch cinnamon sticks, 10 cloves, 10 cardamoms, and salt to taste.
In about 6–7 minutes, everything will turn golden brown. The rice must be cooked to that light golden color. Once done, for every 2 cups of rice, double the water is used.
As you can see, after about 12–14 minutes, my rice is about 80% cooked.
Now for dum cooking, take a large handi, add 50% of the prepared chicken gravy along with the chicken pieces and spread evenly. Then layer 50% of the cooked ghee rice on top.
Now add the remaining rice on top of the chicken. Over the rice, sprinkle chopped mint, coriander, all the fried dry fruits, and 2 pinches of garam masala.
Turn off the flame and let it rest for 20 minutes. After 20 minutes, open the lid — look at how beautiful it is! Steaming hot and fragrant Malabar Chicken Dum Biryani is ready!
Usually, Keralites enjoy biryani with pappadam and pickle, followed by Suleimani tea — a great digestive. This is a very simple recipe. How is this Kerala special Malabar Chicken Dum Biryani? Like it? Want to try it? For the detailed recipe, visit www.wismyfood.com and tag me on Instagram if you try it!