Assalamu Alaikum everyone! I hope you all are doing absolutely fine. My name is Fatima, and today I will teach you how to make Shan Bombay Biryani — that is, how you can prepare delicious Bombay Biryani at home. This method...
I’ve added the oil, and now I’m adding 6–7 medium-sized onions. I'm making biryani with one kilogram of rice here, so I’m preparing everything in that proportion. If you're making biryani with two cups of rice...
Here I’m making it with four cups of rice, so I’ve added 6–7 onions. I’m frying the onions until golden. I have about one cup of yogurt here, which I will now mix with the Shan Bombay Biryani spice mix.
So we’ll open the entire spice packet and mix it into the yogurt. After adding the Bombay Biryani spice mix, gently stir it with a spoon so that the masala blends well into the yogurt. You can see here...
I’m adding 2 to 3 spoonfuls of tamarind into water and letting it soak for 15 minutes. Now we’ll move to the next step — I’ve already soaked the tamarind.
We've also mixed the yogurt with the biryani masala and soaked the tamarind. You can see the onions here — I'm frying them on medium heat so they don't burn. You can see how their color is changing...
Now I’m adding the chicken. These are not very large pieces. You can use whichever cut of chicken you prefer — even boneless. After adding the chicken, mix it well so that...
...the chicken gets properly fried. It took around 5–6 minutes to fry well. After frying for 5–6 minutes, I’ll now tell you what the next step is. So our chicken is nicely fried...
After adding all of that, I’m now adding tomatoes. I’ve taken 6–7 tomatoes, since this is for 1 kg of rice. If you're using 2 cups of rice, then take 3–4 tomatoes. I’ve used fresh tomatoes.
Next, I’m adding red chili powder — about 2 tablespoons. Add salt according to your taste. I’m also adding turmeric powder...
As you can see, it’s been cooking for around 5 minutes and continues to cook. Keep stirring it occasionally. After 5 minutes, you’ll notice the tomatoes have started to soften and break down.
After adding the tomatoes, now I’m adding the yogurt and Shan Bombay Biryani masala mixture that we made earlier. After adding this, you need to cook it for about 10 minutes...
After adding cumin, now I’m adding one bay leaf. I’ve taken a large bay leaf and broken it into 3 pieces, but you can also add it whole. Then I’m adding coriander powder...
I’ve added one spoon of it. If you have separate spice powders, then add 1 teaspoon each. After adding these, mix them well. I cooked this for 10 minutes, and as you can see, the color of the masala has turned a beautiful red.
I crushed the soaked tamarind a little with my hands to extract the pulp into the water. I’ve added that tamarind water into the mixture — about one glass of water was used for soaking. I’ll add a bit more if needed.
After mixing that in, I’m also adding whole coriander seeds — about 1 tablespoon. Mix everything well again, and as you can see...
Now I’m adding green chilies. I have two chopped green chilies — I’ve added one now, and I’ll add the other during the layering. Mix this well. Now I’ll add...
If you like more heat, you can add 1 teaspoon of chili flakes, but I’ve added only half a teaspoon here. After adding that, I mixed it, and you can see the color of the spices and oil...
If you haven’t subscribed to my channel yet, please do so now! Click the bell icon and enable all notifications so that you’ll be the first to know when I upload a new video.
Now take a large pot, and add 3–4 liters of water (about 12–16 glasses). I’m making biryani with 4 cups of rice, so I’ve added 4 tablespoons of salt, 1 teaspoon of...
After mixing, cover and let it boil on high heat.
You can see here how it looks — the slight reddish color is from the cumin. Once the water starts boiling, add the rice. Pour all of it in once the water is boiling. Then...
You can see how beautifully the rice has cooked — nice and fluffy. Now we’ll do the layering. I’ve poured some of the cooked masala with oil into the same pot. Then I’ll add a layer of rice on top...
Taste the masala once — if it needs more salt or spice, you can adjust. But with this ratio, your biryani will turn out perfect for 1 kg of rice. After the first layer, I’ll add...
Now I’m adding another layer of rice and repeating the same steps. Add the remaining chicken masala on top, followed by fresh coriander, green chilies...
The little masala and rice left at the end, I mixed together and poured on top. Finally, sprinkle some mint leaves, coriander, and green chilies...
Now I’m adding orange food color — about one small spoon, without mixing it in water. Just sprinkle it directly. Then cover it and let it steam (dum) on low heat...
After 15 minutes of steaming, mix the biryani well and serve. You can see how fluffy the rice looks — it turned out so delicious, and the color came out beautifully. In the same way...
So I thought I’d also teach you how to make National (brand) Biryani. Just look at this color — how beautifully it turned out! Be sure to try this biryani at home. If you liked the video, give it a like, share it, and comment below...