Assalamu Alaikum. Welcome to Banal Poor’s Secret. Today, I’ll teach you a different recipe – a different kind of biryani that is very delicious and I’m sure you’ll love it. Let’s start making it together.
Bismillahir Rahmanir Rahim. First, we’ll grind the spices for marination. I’m using 15-20 green chilies since I’m making biryani with around 1.5–2 kg of meat, so I’ve added extra chilies.
As you can see, I’ve made a paste with green chilies, coriander, mint, and lemon juice. Now moving to the next step. In a bowl, I’ll add about one cup of yogurt since, as mentioned, we are using over a kilo of meat.
Next, I’ll add salt as needed. I have 1 tablespoon of red chili powder – quantity according to the amount of meat. I’m also adding 1 tablespoon of garam masala powder.
Next, I’ll add 1 tablespoon of dry fenugreek (kasuri methi). I have 1 teaspoon of whole black pepper, and 1 teaspoon of turmeric powder. These are a few bay leaves, about four to five pieces.
I’ll add coriander powder as well. All of these ingredients will go into the same bowl.
Mix everything very well. Make sure all the spices and ingredients are thoroughly combined.
We’re using beef with bone because as the meat cooks, juices come out from the bones which enhance the flavor. Be sure to include at least one or two pieces with bone.
As you can see, the meat is well coated with the marinade. At this point, you can store it in different containers and freeze it for up to one month. Whenever you need to make biryani urgently, just defrost and use it.
A'udhu Billahi min ash-shaytan ir-rajim. Bismillahir Rahmanir Rahim. The Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) said, “Use black seeds regularly, because they are a cure for all diseases except death.”
Bismillahir Rahmanir Rahim. First, I’ll add oil to the pan. The amount of oil depends on your preference. Since I’m making beef biryani, I’ve added around 1.5 cups of oil.
Add bay leaves and two large cardamoms to the pan. Now add the marinated beef that we kept for one hour. Put it directly into the oil.
Keep stirring the beef gently as it cooks.
Continue cooking and stirring until the beef is evenly browned and the spices are well blended.
I’ve mixed in tomatoes now. I’ll cover the pan and let it cook on low heat so the meat becomes tender. Let’s check – the meat is well cooked and the masala is ready.
Now we’ll put the rice on dum (steam cook). I have pre-boiled rice here which I’ll layer over the meat curry. No need to add extra oil – just layer the rice directly onto the masala.
Now I’ll cover the pan and let it steam until the rice is fully cooked. Let’s check – MashaAllah, the rice is perfectly done.
Hope you enjoy this recipe. May you find it as delicious as we do.