Hyderabadi Chicken Dum Biriyani
This is a bit easier than the biriyani we make in Kannur. It's easier to prepare. This isn’t made with ghee rice. It’s made using water and rice. Basmati rice is used here. In Kannur biriyani, regular rice is used. That’s the difference. Let's see how to make Hyderabadi Chicken Dum Biriyani at home.
For making biriyani, I’ve taken basmati rice here. This brand is called Davat. I mostly use it when I’m in Abu Dhabi. I’m in Abu Dhabi now, so I always buy this rice here. It’s a good rice. When you cook it, the grains won’t stick to each other. It's a long grain and very good. So, if you get it, try buying this brand.
I’ve taken 4 cups of basmati rice. Let’s wash it thoroughly. After that, soak it in water. If we soak it for at least 1 hour, the rice will cook better. Cover it and keep aside after soaking.
I’ve taken 4 medium-sized onions here. Slice and fry them until golden brown. This is what we call "Bista" in our Thalassery biriyani. I’ve cut 4 onions like this. Now let’s fry them well. For that, I’m heating oil in a pan.
Once the oil is hot, fry the onions until golden brown. With this amount of oil, you can fry 4 onions in 4 batches. If you use more oil, you can fry all at once, but it wastes oil. So this way is better. Fry them well.
Sauté until onions turn golden brown.
Let’s transfer the fried onions to a plate. Let them cool a bit so they become crisp. Don’t keep them piled up; spread them out slightly. Place all the fried onions onto a plate like this.
Now crush the rest of the onions with your hands. All the onions are crushed and ready. Set them aside. I’ve washed 1.5 kg of chicken, cut into big pieces.
Now add more than half of the crushed onions to the chicken. Keep the remaining aside. Add 3 tablespoons of crushed ginger, garlic, and green chili – about 12–14 large garlic cloves, a small piece of ginger, and 10 green chilies.
1½ tbsp chili powder
1½ tsp turmeric powder
1 tsp garam masala powder
½ handful of mint leaves
1 handful of coriander leaves
1¼ cups of curd
Now mix all the ingredients thoroughly.
Close the lid and let it marinate for half an hour. If you have more time, marinate for 1 hour.
Let’s start making the masala. I’ve placed a pan on the stove. Once hot, add 3 tablespoons of cow ghee.
Add 3 tablespoons of sunflower oil.
After adding chicken and masala to the pan, cook for 3 minutes on high flame. Chicken tastes better when cooked on high flame.
I’ve cooked the chicken for 3 minutes on high. Now close the lid and cook on low to medium flame. Chicken will be ready in 10 minutes. So I’m closing the lid now.
If you haven’t subscribed to Kannur Kitchen yet, please press the Subscribe button and the bell icon next to it.
4L water for cooking rice
Water is slightly hot now. Add 2 large cinnamon sticks, 4 cardamoms, 4–5 cloves, 2 tablespoons sunflower oil, and salt to taste.
Wait till the water boils before adding rice. Now that the water is boiling, add the soaked rice after draining all water.
Add the rice to the water and stir with a spoon.
After adding rice, water has started boiling again. (Repeated many times – likely an editing error.)
If rice is overcooked, the biriyani won’t taste good. So be careful. Now let’s check the masala. Chicken is well-cooked and masala is ready, but there's too much water in it. So we need to reduce it.
Cook on high flame without closing the lid so the water evaporates. Don’t dry it out fully; make it a thick gravy. Now check the rice – it’s done in 5 minutes.
Remove rice from stove and drain the water. I’ve used a clip for draining – use whatever way is easier for you. The masala has thickened and is ready.
After mixing, remove the masala from the stove. Rice is nicely cooked and fluffy. This is how it should look. Now let’s start layering the biriyani in a big vessel placed on the stove. The vessel should be hot.
Add a little ghee to the vessel – about 1.5 tablespoons. Don’t add too much. (Incomplete sentence due to mixed language.)
Add half of the fried onions. Don’t add all. Then add half of the chicken masala. Include some of the gravy as well.
Now add a layer of rice. We did 1 of 3 layers earlier. Add the remaining rice in the second layer.
Now add color. I’m using turmeric mixed in water. You can use saffron in milk or food color – yellow, orange, or red as you prefer. Now sprinkle mint and coriander leaves.
(Unintelligible – possibly unrelated or background speech)
Add chicken masala over the rice layer. Then add another layer of rice.
Now we can add yellow color on top again. (Repeated multiple times for emphasis.)
Close the lid and cook on low flame for 10 minutes. Otherwise, the bottom may burn. If you're using a non-stick pan, an old one is better.
(Unintelligible or background noise)
10 minutes are up. The biriyani should be ready. Let’s open and check. Smells great. Biriyani is ready. Remove from stove and serve hot. If you add orange color, it will look more vibrant. I haven’t added much.
If you want a colorful look, you can do so, but for home cooking, it’s better not to. I’ve served it. The biriyani is ready. It’s tasty and easy to make. You’ve seen it’s very simple. Everyone, try it and let me know. If you liked it, don’t forget to like and share. And if you haven’t subscribed yet, please do. Thank you.