Hey guys, how are you, my friends? I hope you're all doing well. First, if you haven't subscribed to my channel, please do it quickly and hit the bell icon so that you don't miss any of my fun recipe videos.
I’ve added 150 gm of oil, heated it, and now added 3 tbsp of ginger garlic paste. Sauté this for 2–3 minutes to remove the raw smell. We're preparing the biryani masala — it turns out very delicious and is super quick to make.
Add slit green chilies, curry leaves, and finely chopped onions. For whole spices, add 1 cinnamon stick, 1 black cardamom, 5–6 cloves, and 4–5 black peppercorns. Add 2 tsp coriander powder.
Add 1 tsp red chili powder and whole cumin seeds. Sauté everything well. Cook it until the tomatoes soften completely and form a fine paste. As you can see, we’ve just added the tomatoes, so…
Cook until tomatoes are nicely mashed. Stir in between so the masala doesn’t stick to the bottom. Then cover and cook for another 2–3 minutes until the oil rises to the surface.
Now cook it for 1–2 more minutes covered. As you can see, the tomatoes are soft and the oil has come up — that means the masala is ready. Now I’ll turn off the flame and start boiling the rice.
I’ve taken about 1 kg of basmati rice because biryani tastes best with basmati. We’ll boil it in water with salt and whole spices. You can add a bay leaf too. I’ve added a black cardamom here...
In the pot where we’ll cook the biryani, add 1 kg chicken and the prepared masala. This is a superb recipe and trust me, it comes together really fast with minimal effort.
You can make it fresh at home or use readymade masala. Add 1 tsp garam masala powder.
Mix everything well. After mixing, marinate it for 30 minutes. If you're short on time, you can cook it right away. But marinating makes the chicken more flavorful.
Now our rice is almost done. Check it — it shouldn't be 100% cooked, just about 75%, because the remaining 25% will cook during the dum process. So keep it slightly undercooked. We’ll drain it in 2 minutes.
After 2 minutes, strain the rice. Now we’ll layer the boiled rice over the chicken and masala.
I usually do it this way — keep all the masala at the bottom and layer the rice on top. If you like, you can do it in layers — a layer of masala, then rice, and so on. I prefer doing it my way...
The aroma and flavor of desi ghee is amazing in biryani. I haven’t used any food color here. Instead, I soaked saffron in water and added that. It gives a lovely color and taste...
For garnishing, use fried onions, cashews, coriander, mint — whatever you prefer. I’ll put it on dum for 45 minutes.
Now let’s check if the biryani is done. Make some space in the middle and see if there’s water on the sides. If only oil is visible, it means the biryani has cooked perfectly on dum.
If you liked my recipe, please give it a like. Do subscribe to my channel and share it. Comment and let me know how it turned out for you. And always remember — homemade is the healthiest! Thank you! Bye-bye! Take care!