Today I’m sharing the Arsalan-style Mutton Dum Biryani recipe. If you’re from Kolkata, you already know how rich and exceptional this biryani is.
So today I’m showing you how to prepare it at home. I previously shared the restaurant-style Arsalan Chicken Biryani, and you loved it—thank you so much! Now I bring this special recipe on this occasion—please do try it at home.
With some simple ingredients and easy steps, you can recreate this restaurant-style biryani in your kitchen—very easy and delicious.
Let's start with the potatoes. In the Kolkata-style biryani, potatoes are included. I took half a kilo of large potatoes, cut into bits.
I’m adding orange food color—liquid type—for a lovely hue. Then I add spices: 1 heaped tablespoon red chili powder, 1 heaped tablespoon salt, half a teaspoon cumin, and a cinnamon stick piece.
Adding yogurt adds great flavor to the potatoes—so definitely add it. Also adding half a teaspoon of kewra essence, and one drop of sweet mughlai perfume—it’s strong, so just a drop.
Now I’ll pour water—about half a cup. I’ll pressure cook it until 2–3 whistles on medium-high flame.
The potatoes are perfectly cooked after 2–3 whistles. I let the pressure release naturally. The potatoes are cooked just right.
Now for the rice: I’m making a large batch (2.5 kg). I took 4 cups of rice—a good brand. Wash thoroughly, changing water until it runs clear, then soak.
Soak as mentioned. Once done, sauté the onions until golden—they need to be well fried for a fragrant aroma that enhances biryani.
That little amount of oil is enough for the biryani—just what’s needed. I'm making mutton biryani, so I’ll walk you through next steps.
Now I’ll add the mutton: 1 kg, with about 25% fat and bone-in. Wash well. Yogurt is essential—200 g for 1 kg mutton. Now let’s continue.
I’m using the same oil (used for frying onions and potatoes) to cook the meat—adds that nice aroma. Add everything to the pressure cooker and heat until hot.
Add whole spices once oil is hot. When they crackle, add washed and drained meat pieces. Sauté well.
Now add yogurt. Adjust salt and chili to taste. Then add the crispy fried onions we set aside earlier.
Now I’m adding Arsalan’s special biryani masala (see my chicken biryani recipe for details). Mix well. Next, add water—don't add too much, about 1–1¼ cups is plenty.
I added about 300 ml water. Stir and level it. Cover with lid and cook until meat is almost fully tender—about 5–6 whistles on medium flame.
Mutton doesn't take long to cook—after 5–6 whistles, I allowed pressure to release naturally. See, the meat is fully tender.
Remove meat, then scoop out the excess fat (rogan) from the broth—the Kolkata biryani style is light, with aroma but not heavy spices.
So here I’m separating the meat from the broth, and straining the broth to remove all spices and residues—that’s the key to Kolkata biryani: aroma without heavy masala.
Now check your soaked rice—it’s fluffy and plump, and water is hot. I'm preparing to cook rice in it.
I also added rock salt alum (fitkari), which kills bacteria and gives shine and fluffiness to rice.
Cook rice until 80% done. I've prepared all ingredients for layering.
For layering: first, heat warm milk (lukewarm) and add 1 tbsp saffron; mix well so rice grains take on the color.
I also have homemade khoya (milk solids)—some of you asked earlier, so I prepared it—plus a teaspoon sugar for slight sweetness. Then I added 1 heaped tbsp Arsalan biryani masala (works for chicken or mutton).
Mix the saffron milk—it’s turned a lovely golden color. Now for layering: I have 500 ml broth juice from the meat (strained), and rice is 80% done.
For the first layer: add meat with potatoes on the base, then on top sprinkle saffron milk, rose water, sugar, mild mughlai essence, and homemade khoya.
I add a bit of rogan (fat/oil) from the meat but only half, to keep the biryani light while preserving flavor. Distribute evenly.
Then add the remaining rice layer. Sprinkle a little orange food color and the remaining rogan on top. Do NOT add leftover spices or broth particles on top.
Add 2 tablespoons of broth juice evenly. Layering is now complete—this is how beautifully it looks.
Now cover the vessel: first with aluminum foil, then with lid (or clean kitchen towel) for good sealing. The pot is ready for dum.
For dum: place a heavy-bottomed tawa on flame, then place the biryani pot on the tawa. Top it with a heavy weight (e.g. tava) to seal heat.
Once it suffocates, reduce flame to the lowest and cook dum for 15–20 minutes. After that, your perfect, aromatic, flavorful biryani will be ready.
Make sure your lid is good and sealed.
This is the authentic restaurant-style Arsalan mutton biryani—a recipe I crafted for you with high standards. Please definitely try it.
The aroma... I can't express it enough. See, the bottom has no sticking, especially if you're using a heavy-bottomed pan.
The results are amazing—please do try this recipe. Here’s the freshly served biryani—look at those flavours and aromas. Do try it!
I hope you enjoyed my recipe. Follow these steps well and you'll get absolutely amazing results. Please do try it. If you liked the recipe...
See you next time with another interesting and explosive recipe. Until then, take care of yourself and your family. Goodbye!