Hi guys, welcome back to our channel, Sauté at Site. Today, we’re going to make the famous Talassery Chicken Biryani. This is an easy one-pot recipe without the hassle of layering or extra steps. So let's get started! First, we’ll prepare the biryani masala using common household spices.
I’ve taken 1½ tsp fennel seeds, 1 tsp cumin seeds, 2 pieces of star anise, 1 cinnamon stick, 8–10 peppercorns, 4 cloves, and 4 green cardamoms. I’ll add them to a pan and dry roast until aromatic.
The masala is now fragrant. I’ll let it cool and grind it into a fine powder. Next, we pre-cook the rice. I’ve taken water in a deep vessel and added 1 tbsp ghee along with whole spices — cardamom, cloves, pepper, star anise, cinnamon,
and fennel seeds. Add them to the water. These spices will infuse great flavor into the rice. Give it a stir and add salt to taste.
Bring the water to a boil before adding the rice for best results. I’ve taken 2 cups of Jeerakasala rice, also called Kaima rice — traditionally used for Talassery biryani. If you don’t have it, you can use basmati rice, but soak it for 30 minutes. I’ve also taken 1 kg chicken, marinated with ¾ tsp turmeric, salt, lemon juice, and 1 tsp ginger-garlic paste.
Let the chicken marinate for about an hour. Now that the water is boiling, it’s time to add the rice.
Stir the rice well. Cook until it’s al dente — about 75% done. It shouldn’t take more than 10–12 minutes. This is the perfect texture. Turn off the heat, strain the rice using a colander,
and rinse it with cold water so the grains don’t stick together. Now, heat a pan with a mix of ghee and oil. It’s time to fry onions. I’ve taken 3 large onions, thinly sliced.
Continue frying the onions until golden brown. They’ve started to change color — this is what you want. Don’t over-fry them, or they’ll burn. Once golden, remove some and set aside for garnishing.
Reduce the heat and add 1 tbsp ginger-garlic paste. Stir well, then add 2 small chopped tomatoes.
Sauté for a minute. Add 1 tsp coriander powder, a pinch of nutmeg powder, and the freshly ground biryani masala. Add the whole masala and give it a good mix.
Add roughly chopped green chillies. Stir them in with the tomato and onion. Now add 3 tbsp of whisked yogurt.
Mix everything well. Sauté for a minute until the oil starts to separate. Add salt to taste. Now, add the marinated chicken.
Mix well and sauté for 2 minutes. Then add chopped coriander and mint leaves. Stir again. Add just half a cup of water.
Cover with a lid and cook for about 15 minutes. After 15 minutes, let’s check the chicken.
There’s still some water, which is perfect. This will help finish cooking the biryani, since we’re doing it on direct flame. No layering is needed. Just add the rice on top. Lower the heat and add the rice.
This is a great recipe when you want a quick biryani with common ingredients. It doesn’t require layering or complex steps. Cover the pot and cook on low flame for another 15 minutes. Let’s check it now.
The rice is cooked and fluffy. Time to garnish with fried onions, mint, coriander leaves, and some fried nuts.
Switch off the flame. Let it cool slightly before serving. I hope you enjoyed the video. Please like and subscribe to our channel. Follow us on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter. See you next time!