Namaste everyone, I am Hema Subramanyam. Welcome to Home Cooking Telugu.
Today we're going to make a favorite—Dindigul Biryani. I'm going to show you how to prepare this special Dindigul-style mutton biryani. So what is Dindigul...
Take 2 coconuts first...
2 tablespoons coriander seeds, 10 cashew nuts, 1 tablespoon cumin seeds, 1.5 tablespoons black gram, 6 cardamoms, 1 tablespoon black pepper, 2 bay leaves, 2 cashew nuts, 1 cinnamon stick, 2 small cashew nuts, 10 cloves, 2 small cashew nuts, 1 tablespoon fennel seeds
Roast all these ingredients.
15 small onions...
To make Dindigul biryani, take a large pot and add 3 tablespoons oil and 2 tablespoons ghee. First, add the ground masala paste and sauté until the color changes.
3 tablespoons masala powder, 1 teaspoon turmeric powder, 1 tablespoon dry red chilli powder, 2 teaspoons rock salt (you can use regular salt too). Adjust salt to taste.  Keep on low flame and sauté well, or it may burn.  Now add the boiled mutton pieces to this mixture.
After mixing this well, squeeze some lemon juice and add 200 grams curd. Mix again thoroughly. Now add a handful of mint leaves and coriander leaves and mix again.
Now add the mutton stock. You can use mutton stock without compromising flavor. After mixing everything well, cover with a lid and cook on medium flame for 25 minutes until the mutton is done.
This rice won’t be like basmati, but shorter in length and a bit sticky. It looks like jeera rice. This rice is called seeraga samba rice. Wash it well and soak in water for 20 minutes.
Now add the soaked rice into the mixture. Then pour 2 cups of hot water. Cover with a lid and cook the mutton and rice together on medium flame for 10 minutes.
Now the rice is half cooked. Take the biryani pot and place it beside. Now place a large pan on the stove. Once the pan is hot, place the biryani pot on top of it.
Top the biryani with mint leaves and cover tightly. Seal the pot with foil. Then place a plate on top and put it on dum (slow cook) on low flame for 20 minutes.
And that’s how the Dindigul mutton biryani is prepared... Dindigul mutton biryani is ready.
You can get a copy of our 1st edition of the home cooking book on 21st May.