Have you heard of the Bangalore Special Donne Biryani? It has a very unique taste. Let’s see how to prepare it step-by-step.
Greetings to everyone, I’m Hema Subramanyam. Welcome to Home Cooking Telugu. I’ve shown many varieties of biryani before. Today, I’ll show you Karnataka’s special mutton biryani. This is very popular in Bangalore.
Take 2 kg of mutton...
...and chop it into medium-sized pieces.
First, to prepare the onion masala paste, I’m adding 2 tsp of sesame oil in a pan. You can also use regular oil if you prefer. To that, add a few pieces of cinnamon stick, four...
...cloves (2 pieces), and continue sautéing.
If the biryani is spicy, it tastes really good, so don’t hesitate to use good quality spices.
Sauté them slightly in a little water and grind to a fine paste. I’m adding the onion masala paste into a bowl and setting it aside. It gives a great aroma. When used in biryani, it adds nice fragrance to the rice too.
Take 1 handful of fresh mint leaves.
Adding fenugreek leaves gives a lovely flavor to biryani. A handful is enough—too much might make it bitter. Wash and clean them properly.
The green masala paste is now ready. I’ve kept it aside in a bowl.
Now, for cooking the mutton, add 2 tsp of sesame oil in a pressure cooker. Add 3 tablespoons of ghee as well—this enhances the flavor. Don’t add too much, just a little is enough.
Add 1 tsp of shajeera (caraway seeds), 1 tsp of fennel seeds, 1 tsp of chopped onion, 1 tsp of ginger paste, and 3 tsp of garlic paste.
Since the proportion of ginger and garlic is different in this recipe, I’m using separate pastes. After mixing everything once, add one medium-sized tomato chopped finely.
The tangy flavor adds a nice touch to the biryani. That’s why I’m showing you this Bangalore-style method. Now add the marinated mutton pieces directly into this mixture.
Add 6 types of spices...
You’ll see the juices start coming out of the mutton. At this point, add the previously prepared onion masala paste. Mix it thoroughly so it coats the mutton well.
Add 1 kg of biryani rice...
Add 2 tsp of ground spices...
Mix everything well and place it in the pressure cooker. Cook on medium flame for at least 20 minutes. For this biryani, use only jeeraga samba rice for authenticity. This rice variety is commonly used in Andhra Pradesh and Tamil Nadu.
Wash the rice thoroughly with water and soak it for at least 20 minutes.
Cook it on a medium flame for the best results. After everything is mixed well, adjust salt as needed.
After 25 minutes, the moisture will be gone and you’ll see perfectly cooked biryani. After turning off the heat, let it rest for 10 minutes before serving. This allows the flavors to settle.
So, that’s how you make mutton donne biryani. I used 1 kg of jeeraga samba rice. This special biryani is traditionally made with this rice. You can also make it with chicken. I’ve explained the full process clearly in the video. Just follow the steps and you’ll get it right. Definitely try this tasty donne biryani at home and enjoy!