Welcome, welcome, welcome.
Assalamualaikum. Whenever I share a recipe with Shan mixes, you all really love it. So today, I’ve brought a different recipe from Shan’s biryani range. I’m going to make Shan Sindhi Biryani.
Before starting the video, I have a small request. If you haven’t subscribed to my channel yet, please do so and also click the notification bell so you never miss a video.
Let’s start the recipe. I’ve taken three medium-sized potatoes, peeled and sliced them in the middle. I added about 1.25 tsp of orange food color and mixed well.
I will fry them for about 10 to 12 minutes. This softens them about 50-60%, and when we steam the biryani, they’ll be fully cooked.
I’ve kept the fried potatoes aside. Now we’ll start making the korma. I added about half a cup of oil to a pan and four medium-sized onions, finely sliced.
Now I’ll add some whole spices: a 1-inch cinnamon stick, 4–5 cloves, 1 black cardamom pod, and about 1 tsp cumin seeds. These are enough.
Cook the spices for about a minute. Then I added around 750g of chicken (with bones, but you can use boneless too). I’ll now cook the chicken thoroughly.
Here’s a tip I often share: I cook the chicken covered in intervals. I cover it for a while, then fry it, then cover again. This cooks it well without burning.
Now I’ve added a full packet of Shan Sindhi Biryani masala and 3–4 tbsp of water so that the masala doesn’t burn. This also helps soften the tomatoes.
I’ve covered it again. As you can see, the tomatoes have softened and dissolved well, and the gravy is ready. I sautéed it for just 4–5 minutes more.
Now I’m adding about 1 cup of fresh yogurt. Beat the yogurt well and add it to the gravy. Cook for another 4–5 minutes. Then cover and remove it from heat.
Set this aside. Now we’ll start boiling the rice.
I took 750g of long grain basmati rice, washed and soaked them for 30 minutes. Now take a large pot and add plenty of water (around 4–5 liters).
Add salt: 1 heaped tbsp per 1 cup of rice. If not heaped, then about 4 tbsp for 3 cups. Then boil the rice.
The fried potatoes will now go in. Take 1 medium tomato, thinly sliced. Also, 4–5 green chilies, a handful of mint leaves, and 1 lemon.
I took a little extra color because we’ll use some in the layers and dissolve the rest in water. Now we’ll start layering. First, a layer of rice.
After that, all the toppings go in. Again a layer of rice, then chicken, and now I’m adding some dry food color. I’ll dissolve some more in water and pour that too.
That way we get both light yellow and orange-tinted rice, which looks beautiful. This technique gives a nice effect. Now I’ll add more food color on top.
First, cook on medium flame for 5 minutes, then reduce to very low flame. If your pot is heavy-bottomed, no need for a tawa below. If it’s not, place one.
I’ve served this with raita and salad. This Shan Sindhi Biryani turns out delicious—definitely try it and let me know in the comments. I’ll wait for your feedback. I will see you in the next video.