NAMASKARAM. Today's recipe is one of the favourite dishes of non-veg eaters — Chicken Biryani. I'm preparing Chicken Biryani using Basmati rice. Guys, my name is Shan Gio and welcome to the video.
Chicken Biryani is made using half of 1 chicken, around 600 grams. This serves 3 people. From 20 pieces of a full chicken, 10 are used. In hotels, 1 chicken is usually cut into 12 pieces. At home, chicken takes longer to cook. Add 1 tsp of ginger-garlic paste.
¼ tsp Turmeric Powder. Beginners, be careful not to confuse tsp with tbsp. 1 tsp Coriander Powder. 1 tsp Chilli Powder. 1 tsp Garam Masala. (Garam Masala recipe is linked in the description.) 1 tsp Salt. 1 tsp Lime Juice.
Now mix well so the masala coats the chicken pieces evenly. Refrigerate for 1 hour to let it marinate. Meanwhile, slice 4 medium-sized onions. Fry 2 of them.
Heat some oil for frying — preferably sunflower oil. You may not need this much, you can fry in two batches. Once hot, add the onions and fry them.
[Untranslated - regional language: most likely Malayalam or Telugu cooking instructions]
[Untranslated - background music or ambient scene]
Now fry some cashew nuts and raisins (optional). Heat 1 tbsp ghee. Fry cashews until golden, then add raisins. Once raisins change color, transfer immediately to a bowl to prevent burning.
These are the spices for cooking the chicken: 1½ inch piece of curry leaves.
4 gms, 2 cardamoms (slightly cracked), 1 tomato, a bit of coriander seeds — not too much, half a pinch is enough. Lastly, a bay leaf — it gives great flavour to the biryani. We'll cook the chicken with these in a non-stick pan with a lid, which will also be used to dum (steam) the biryani.
Heat 3 tbsp oil (same oil used for frying onions — it adds flavour). Add the whole spices and roast on medium flame for 15–20 seconds. Add 1 chopped green chilli.
[Untranslated - regional language: ingredients being added, onion frying, ginger-garlic paste sautéed till golden]
1½ tsp Chilli Powder (adjust to taste). 1 tsp Garam Masala. 1½ tsp Crushed Pepper. Stir till raw smell of masala disappears. Then add the marinated chicken.
[Untranslated - regional language: possibly talking about stirring or cooking method]
While chicken cooks for 10–12 minutes, start cooking rice. Use 2¼ cups water for 2 cups rice. To this, add 1 bay leaf, a 1½ inch curry leaf piece, 4 cloves, 2 cardamoms (cracked), and 1 tbsp fried onion.
Add 1½ tsp lime juice to prevent rice from sticking. Add 1 tbsp of the fried onion oil for flavour. Add 1 tsp salt (measure properly). Wait for the water to boil. By now, the chicken will be half-cooked. Add half of the fried onion to it.
[Untranslated - regional language: likely instructions for checking the chicken/rice]
Once the water in rice is absorbed, turn off the flame immediately — this ensures the rice isn't sticky or overcooked. Now layer the rice over the chicken.
[Untranslated - regional language: cautioning about not leaving too much gravy or water, for best dum results]
Layer the rice gently. Just spread it — don't press it down hard.
For biryani's yellow colour, you can use saffron milk, or a mix of turmeric and milk, or edible yellow food colouring. Add it randomly over the rice for a Mughal-style look.
Now cover with a lid and dum cook it. Use your stove’s smallest burner and cook on low flame for 10 minutes. After 10 minutes, turn off the stove and leave it closed for another 15 minutes.
When serving, ensure the biryani is hot. Let it rest before serving — that’s when the real flavour settles in. When hot, you get maximum flavour and aroma from the spices. After that, you can serve with...
Salad, pickle, and pappadam. Ingredients list is in the description box. Leave your feedback in the comments!