Hi friends, welcome back to my video! Today we’ll make Kolkata’s famous dish—Dada-Boudi Biryani. Just look at how amazing it looks! So let’s get started. For this, I’ve taken…
…and we’ll set this aside. I’ve taken a big bowl, placed a strainer on top, and added around two heaping tablespoons of ginger and garlic paste. By adding water to it, we’ll extract the juice. This is for one kilo of biryani.
Keep adding a little water while stirring to extract the juice. Once done, discard the ginger-garlic residue. You can see I’ve extracted about 3 cups of juice here in total.
Let this sizzle for a bit. Add a little fried onion from earlier—just a bit. Now add the juice we prepared. Take a pinch of food color—just a pinch, because…
Now add 1 teaspoon of red chili powder and 1 kg of potatoes, cut and washed well. Add them in and 1 teaspoon of salt. Cover and cook on low flame for 8–9 minutes. Look at this…
Don’t overcook them—only about 80%, because we’ll also steam them later (dum). The centers of the potatoes should be slightly firm. Remove all the potatoes once done.
Mix everything well. Now add 1 teaspoon of red chili powder again—we already added 1 teaspoon to the potatoes earlier, so keep that in mind. I’ve added 1 teaspoon of salt, but adjust to your taste.
Now here’s a secret ingredient: I added around 3 drops of sweet attar (aromatic essence). It’s easily available in the market. Ask any grocer for "meetha attar" and they’ll give it to you. I used 100g of yogurt…
Mix it all well, then cover and cook on low flame for 25–30 minutes. Now look—the meat has softened well. It took about 30 minutes to cook, and you can see how nicely it turned out.
You can’t make biryani without oil—don’t believe anyone who says otherwise. If your meat already has enough fat, you don’t need to add extra oil. I won’t show unnecessary steps if they’re not needed.
Separate the meat and strain the gravy. This step is crucial—chefs at Dada-Boudi always do this. Discard all the remaining whole spices from the gravy. Now add bay leaves…
I’ll definitely share the secret biryani masala recipe too. Mix everything well and set it aside. Now in the pot you’ll use for dum, arrange the meat you just strained.
The strained gravy measures around 2 cups. Now add the well-cooked potatoes in the pot. If you’re enjoying the video, please like it, and if you’re new to the channel, don’t forget to subscribe.
I’ve taken about 50g of mawa (khoya)—mix it in well. If you don’t have mawa, no worries—you can just use onions. Adding mawa gives Dada-Boudi biryani its unique richness and taste.
Add dried plums (aloo bukhara).
Now we’ll add rice that I’ve cooked to 80%. If you’re unsure how to make perfect biryani rice, I’ve added the link in the description. Go check it out.
Wash your hands thoroughly before touching the rice.
Spread the rice evenly. Look at how beautiful it looks. Now cover the pot, place it on dum. Take a heavy-bottomed iron tawa, preheat it, then place the biryani pot on it, lower the flame, and place a heavy object on top.
Let it steam (dum) on low flame for 25–30 minutes. Once that time is up, open the pot. It’s been about 30 minutes now—look at this delicious biryani!
Dada-Boudi Biryani is very famous in Kolkata. People line up to eat it. Even I waited in line during Eid to taste it.
I thought I’d share this recipe with my viewers. You all loved my previous Kolkata-style biryani recipe—if you haven’t seen it yet, go check it out. It shows how easily you can make biryani at home.