Hi. Namaskar. How are you? Hope all are doing good and staying safe. Here all of us are fine. Today I am here with the easiest biriyani recipe of a special biriyani. Our Indian special Thalappakatti biriyani.
Many requests had come for this recipe. I had studied engineering in India for 4 years. But it wasn't very tasty. We went and tasted it and came to know the taste. I did my first experiment and it came out well. I got the taste I had. All of you do try it out. It's a very easy biriyani that can be done by bachelors.
You shouldn't compare it with Kerala biriyani. It's a totally different taste. Tamil Nadu biriyani is a different taste. I had made Ambur biriyani before. It's a tasty biriyani. Many have not seen the Onathaila curry I had made the other day. Many have requested for it. I am posting videos on it. I had not eaten it before. It was in the middle of the video. So don't forget to see it. So without any delay, let's see how to make our tasty chicken biriyani.
Now let's begin to make our biriyani. For that, we need a masala powder. I have kept all the ingredients ready here. I shall tell you how to do it. All these can be powdered and kept aside in a small bowl. I have taken 1 tsp cumin seeds, 1 tsp fennel seeds and 1 tsp cumin seeds.
Next add 1 tsp whole pepper, 3 tsp coriander seeds, 3 sticks cinnamon,
Now we need bay leaf. It is available in two types. Indian bay leaf and Indian bay leaf. This is Indian bay leaf. Indian bay leaf is dried curry leaves. Let's add this to this. Cut it to small pieces and add. Next, add a star anise to this. Next, add cashew nuts.
3 cardamoms, 10 cloves, 10 cloves... (repeats for emphasis).
Now let's add the kalpasi to this. Only then you will get the correct flavour. You can make it without kalpasi. It's ok. But if you want the perfect taste of the biriyani, you will get this. Now let's add this.
I have taken 7 cashew nuts. Let's powder all these well. I have powdered the masala well. Let's keep this aside. I have taken 1 kg fresh chicken. I have cut it into medium pieces. I have cut it into small pieces and ground it to a fine paste. This is how we roast the fish.
After that, I have washed it well and kept it aside. I have taken 1 kg chicken here. I have soaked the rice in water for 30 mins. I have washed it 3–4 times and soaked it in water for 30 mins. After that, I have kept it in a strainer to drain the water. Do not forget to soak it for at least 30 mins. Only then it will soak well.
Then the rice will be well cooked. Usually, they call it Jeerakasamba rice. But here I have used Jeerakasala rice. If you make this biriyani with basmati rice, it won't be tasty. It will get mashed up. If it gets mashed up, it won't be tasty. But if it gets well cooked, it will be tasty.
Either you can use Jeerakasamba rice or Kaima rice. Only if you use Jeerakasala rice will you get the desired taste. Next, we need shallots for this particular biriyani. If you don't have shallots, you can use 2 big or 3 small onions. I have taken 250g of shallots here.
If you don't get shallots you can use only onions. I always recommend shallots. Now let's make a paste out of all these. Add shallots to a mixer jar. I have added shallots to this. Next, we need a piece of ginger. Not much. Just a medium piece like this. Cut it into small pieces and add to the jar.
Now let's add 5 green chillies to this. Next add garlic. I have taken little more garlic here. This biriyani needs a bit more garlic. I have taken 2 garlic bulbs here. Let's cut them into small pieces and add them to the jar. Now let's add some coriander leaves. I have taken some asafoetida here.
I have taken half of the mint leaves and half of the coriander leaves. Only the leaves. Make sure to wash the leaves well. There will be lots of dirt in it. Let's grind this now. Try to grind it without adding water. If needed, add a little water. I have ground it now.
I have ground it well. I haven't added any water to it. Now let's begin to make the biriyani. Heat a kadai on medium flame. I am going to add peanut oil to it. This is mostly made in peanut oil. I am using it here. If you don't have peanut oil,
You can use sunflower oil or any other oil. But don't use coconut oil. If you use coconut oil, you won't get the taste and flavour of biriyani. I have added 3 tbsp peanut oil.
It will have a sour smell. We have to get rid of that smell. I shall add a little water and close it after it has become hot. When you break it, the smell will go. It's not necessary. You can avoid that part if you want. Close it. When you close it, the smell will go. Let this become hot.
Now the peanut oil is hot. We'll pour a little water and close it. Otherwise it will burst out. Make sure of that. You should open it only after the sound has gone. You can do this only in peanut oil. No need in other oils. Just pour oil, ghee and sauté.
Next add ghee as per your taste. If you don't like ghee, you can use any oil. Since I am making biriyani here, I am adding 2 tbsp ghee.
2 tbsp ghee has been added. Keep the flame on medium. Let the ghee melt well. Now add the ground paste. Sauté well. Then add the masala powder. We don't add tomatoes. We add lemon juice at the end.
If you want, you can grind a tomato and add it. I'm not adding it. Add 1.5 tsp salt. We'll need more salt later. Now add the masala powders.
Mix well and sauté till raw smell goes. Many ask if coriander and mint are must. If you don't have those, don't make biriyani. Once the masala powder is added, the colour changes. Sauté for 2–3 mins on medium.
I've sautéed for 2–3 mins. Now add 1.5 tsp turmeric and 1 tsp chilli powder.
Now sauté well. I had biriyani at a hotel and it wasn't spicy. We already added green chilli and pepper. If it’s too spicy, kids won’t eat. Sauté for 2–3 mins.
Raw smell is gone. Now add 4 tbsp curd. Mix well. Now add the chicken and mix.
Sauté for 5 mins. Then cover and cook chicken. I’m not adding water now. Chicken will cook in its own water. After 5 mins, cover and cook for 10–15 mins.
Open and see if you need water. I cook the chicken well and then add the rice. Some cook it for 10 mins. But I didn't like it that way. I am going to cook the chicken well and then add the rice. Cooking time varies with the chicken.
After 15 mins water has come out from the chicken. As I said, don't forget to check in between. If the water hasn't come, add water and cook. Now check if the chicken is cooked. If not, cook it a bit more. I have cooked it 15 mins, so total 20 mins.
20 mins are over. Now we have to add 3 glasses of rice. 1 glass of rice uses 2 glasses of water. For 3 glasses of rice, total water is 6 glasses. We have to measure the gravy and then decide how much water we need.
I have taken 6 glasses of gravy. I have transferred the chicken pieces to another bowl. Measure the water in the same glass. I'm going to cook in the same vessel. I have switched it off.
Even after a while you can measure it. It's not necessary while hot. I have measured 1.5 glasses of gravy. Now pour 5 glasses of water. You need 6 glasses for 3 glasses rice. If using 4 glasses rice, use 8 glasses of water.
I have measured rice in this glass. I poured 5 glasses of water. You can use hot or cold water. I mixed gravy and water.
It's correct. To confirm, I added 1 glass gravy + 5 glasses water = 6 glasses total. Now let's turn on flame. First check salt of gravy. We had added only 1.5 tsp salt.
I added 1.5 tsp first and now another 1.5 tsp = 3 tsp total. Adjust as per taste. Now add rice. Mix well. Add chicken too. Mix again.
This should boil on medium. When it boils we shall add lemon juice and mint leaves. It should boil well then we will close and cook. I got cooking time from kannammacooks.com. I checked 2-3 recipes and felt this time was good.
Once it has boiled well, cook 4 mins on medium. It has begun to boil. Let's add 1 tbsp lemon juice. I’ll add 1 tbsp and taste. If needed, we can add more. Otherwise too sour.
This is enough. I added just 1 tbsp. Cook 4 mins on medium. Close and cook 4 mins.
Stir the chicken slowly so rice doesn’t stick to bottom. Now on low flame for 10 mins. After 10 mins it’s cooked well. Now I am switching it off. Keep it closed for 20 mins, then serve.
Do not stress. We stirred twice and kept on low flame. It varies per rice. If not cooked, cook on low flame a bit more then rest. Let it rest 20 mins then serve.
Our biriyani has been closed for 20 mins. It's perfectly cooked. This is how rice should be. If you ask if it’s cooked well, yes. But it hasn’t stuck to bottom. I’ll take it slowly. It hasn’t stuck. No need to stress.
If you want you can let it rest then mix. I’m going to keep the chicken aside. If you don’t, it’s okay. But mixing well with chicken will break it. Now let’s mix. The rice is super. Perfect cook. Just be careful with time.
4 mins on medium and then 10 mins on low. Then switch off flame and close for 20 mins. Then put on another stove. Our super tasty Dindigul biriyani is ready.
All of you do try it out. It's super tasty and easy. I felt this is one of the easiest biriyanis I’ve made. I am serving it with raita. I haven’t made it before. If you have raita or lemon-date pickle, that's fine. It’s a perfect biriyani. I shall take photos and come. Avi is waiting.
I have brought biriyani for you. I have taken 2 boiled eggs. I went to a hotel and kept an egg with me. I shall have one for you. If you want it more tender, add little more water. It should be well tendered. It is tender but not too sticky.
Superb. It's perfect. Same flavour and texture of the biriyani I had the other day. Jeerakasala rice has slightly different texture. Taste is the same. Try it and don’t forget to send feedback. If you liked the video, like, share and support us. Until my next recipe, thank you.
He is going. Look at this. He is going to start his winter. It's full of snow. He is going to drop it on a hot day. He has reduced the heat for a week. Now he will have some powdery wind. Let’s go.