Hello friends, welcome back! Today's recipe is a Biryani recipe. It is a tasty biryani made especially in Malabar areas and for weddings in Kerala. It's very easy to make at home. Let's see how to make it.
First, for making the rice, we use Jeerakasala (Kaima) rice, which is usually used in Malabar wedding biryanis. Let's boil the water to cook the rice.
250 ml cup rice – for 1 cup of rice, use 1.5 cups of water.
For 2.5 cups of rice, use 4 cups of water. Add salt to taste. I haven't used oil or ghee in this. Add the washed rice when the water is boiling. No need to soak the rice.
After soaking the rice in water for half an hour, add a little more water and salt and cook it well. This is the best method. If you follow this method, there's no need to soak. I kept it closed for about 10 minutes and the rice is well-cooked. Now the rice is ready. Let's prepare the masala.
We don’t need too many ingredients for the masala. First, add sunflower oil.
Add 1 kg beef and 1 big onion.
Add 1 tbsp ginger garlic paste and 2 tbsp chopped tomatoes. Sauté until the raw smell goes away.
Add 1½ tbsp garam masala, 1½ tsp turmeric powder, coriander leaves, and pepper powder. Mix well.
Add 1 tsp pepper powder and the cooked beef.
Mix the beef well with the masala. If you’ve cooked beef without adding water, use the water released during cooking. The masala should be a bit moist for better taste.
After mixing, cook it for 10 minutes on a low flame. For this biryani, we need to roast some ingredients. Add 3 tbsp of sunflower oil to a pan and roast the ingredients.
Now the masala is ready. We need a little gravy for the masala, otherwise, the biryani won't taste right.
To start the dum, first add a layer of rice. We haven’t added oil to the rice – it was cooked only with salt. Now, add the fried ingredients.
The oil used for frying can be reused here. I used around 3 tbsp oil. Add coriander leaves. If you have pineapple, you can add it now for a unique flavor. Then, add another layer of rice.
After adding rice, pour some ghee on top. We didn’t use ghee earlier, so now add about 2 tbsp of cow’s ghee. Sprinkle some garam masala on top.
Now, we won’t add anything else. Just dum it. If you can use maida dough to seal it, that’s best. Otherwise, use aluminium foil to seal and dum.
Dum it for 30 to 40 minutes on the smallest flame.
When you open the dum, the biryani will have a delicious aroma. It tastes exactly like wedding-style biryani. Do try it and share your feedback. If you make it in the afternoon and eat in the evening, it tastes amazing.
You can also make it early in the morning if you're planning to serve it for lunch. Try it and let me know what you think.
The list of ingredients is given in the description box. Please try this biryani. If you like my videos, subscribe to my channel and press the bell icon. Thank you for watching.