Today's recipe is a special biryani. I'm going to make a very popular Sindhi Biryani from Pakistan. This biryani is quite different in preparation and taste from the ones we usually make in Kerala. Before we begin, please don't forget to subscribe to the channel. First, heat a pan and add 1 cup of ghee. When the ghee is hot, add 2 shallots and fry them.
[Audio unclear — skipped for continuity.]
Add 2 tbsp ginger paste and 1 tbsp garlic paste. Sauté well. Then add 1 kg chicken.
[Audio unclear — skipped.]
Add 1 tbsp turmeric powder and 1 tbsp chili powder. Mix well. Then add boiled potatoes, 1 cup curd, and 1 cup water.
Now the rice is half-cooked. You can pour it over the chicken mixture. The chicken has been cooking for about 10 minutes. Let’s open the lid. The chicken is now well cooked. Add the fried tomato pieces on top. Then add lemon slices, coriander leaves, and mint leaves.
[Audio unclear — skipped.]
Add 1 tsp garam masala and 1 tsp fried onions. Close the lid and cook on high flame for 5 minutes. Then reduce the flame to low and cook for another 10 minutes. After a total of 15 minutes, open the lid and cook for an additional 15 minutes.
Now our Sindhi Biryani is ready to serve!