I had shown Nambur biryani earlier, but today I'm making Ambur biryani. It's very simple and quick to prepare.
Add mint leaves, coriander leaves, pudina, half a spoon of black pepper, garam masala, and one tablespoon of red chili powder and turmeric.
After mixing all this, I kept it aside to marinate for a while.
Don’t use a big vessel. Use a flat-bottomed pot for best results.
If you have biryani pots at home, use a medium-sized one. For 1 kg, this size works well.
If not, use a pressure cooker, but don’t close it fully.
You can also use a thick-bottomed vessel for better heat retention.
Now it’s cooking—let’s prepare the tomato mixture.
Now it’s ready. I’ve sautéed the tomatoes in oil.
Add a bit more tomato for this biryani than usual.
Add a few more than usual, around four.
I’ve taken three finely chopped tomatoes.
If you don’t have puree, chop and use them.
Sauté them well.
Unlike dum biryani, Ambur biryani is more like a pulav with dum at the end.
Add red chili powder, coriander powder, and mix well.
Mix well and cook until the oil separates. The taste comes from this base.
Then add garam masala, cooked rice, coriander, and pudina. Fry this nicely.
Finally, mix everything well with the rice.