In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. Peace be upon you. Everyone loves bringing a plate of biryani from the market and eating it at home. But wouldn't it be great if you could make biryani at home that's even tastier than the market? Today, we’ll make such a chicken biryani recipe that, God willing, you won’t need to buy expensive biryani from hotels anymore. Many people comment that the potatoes in their biryani don’t soften, or—
—or that the rice doesn’t turn out fluffy, or the rice remains undercooked. I’ll try to share a hotel-style biryani recipe with you with all the tips. First, let’s talk about the rice. Market biryani usually uses sela rice, but if you're cooking at home, I suggest using aged basmati rice. It has a much richer flavor.
So for this recipe, I’m using one kilogram of aged basmati rice. You must wash it two to three times and soak it for one hour.
You may have noticed that the potatoes in market biryani are large-sized. But how do they cook properly? I’ll share an easy method with you. I’ve taken four large potatoes and cut each into two big pieces.
First, apply yellow food color to the potatoes. As you can see, the color has been applied. Now, I’ll leave them like this for 20 minutes. After 20 minutes, put the potatoes in a pressure cooker. Add the same food color water in which they were soaked.
Along with that, add two glasses of water and half a teaspoon of salt. Now, tightly seal the pressure cooker and place the whistle. Once the whistle starts, turn off the stove after exactly 5 minutes. Remember, don’t overcook the potatoes or they will break.
Now look at the chicken—use one kilogram of chicken with bones. Biryani tastes much better with bone-in chicken.
Remove the lid; the potatoes are cooked well. Don’t let them stay in the water. Take them out and set them aside on a plate. They’re nicely cooked and haven’t broken. Now let’s move on to the main process—making the biryani. For 1 kg chicken biryani, you’ll need two cups of oil.
Start frying the spices and ingredients in oil.
Once the ginger-garlic changes color, the spices will start blooming. You’ll get that same aroma that comes from restaurant biryani.
Now we’ll add the chicken and fry it. Fry the chicken on medium flame until its water dries up and some parts get a slight golden color.
Once the chicken is well fried, add three chopped large tomatoes. These are the spices for 1 kg biryani.
Add two level teaspoons of salt. You can add two teaspoons of red chili powder, but if you prefer it less spicy, use 1.5 teaspoons instead.
Add turmeric powder and coriander powder.
Add Chinese salt (MSG) and chicken powder.
Also add chaat masala and one full tablespoon of any brand’s biryani masala. We add this for that artificial yet signature biryani aroma.
We want to ensure that aroma is present in the biryani. Since this is Sindhi biryani, I’ve added six dried plums (aloobukhara), one tablespoon of tamarind, and one cup of fried onions. These special ingredients are typical in Sindhi chicken biryani. Do add them—you’ll notice a clear difference in taste.
Mix everything well. Add two tablespoons of yogurt. Yogurt makes the chicken very juicy, tender, and soft. Mix all the ingredients well and cook the chicken on low flame, covered, for at least 5 minutes.
After five minutes, you’ll see the gravy is beautifully ready. Just give it a light mix. Now add the boiled potatoes. Mix the potatoes gently so the masala flavor seeps into them properly. We don’t want them to remain bland—
—or soaked and soggy. [inaudible or unclear audio at this point]
Take a large open vessel and fill it with water. I added four tablespoons of salt, two tablespoons of oil, and two tablespoons of vinegar. Add some whole cumin seeds and a piece of cinnamon stick. Once the water boils, add the soaked rice.
Do not boil rice covered—always boil it uncovered on high flame. It takes about 7–8 minutes for the rice to reach the perfect "ek kani" stage—where the grain is just slightly undercooked. I’ve now drained the rice from the water.
Now we’ll layer the biryani. First layer is the chicken curry, then half the rice, and then another layer of curry. I’m sharing a two-layer biryani recipe with you. On top, I’ve added the curry again. For Sindhi biryani, the special ingredients—aloobukhara and tamarind—are already in. These give it its distinct flavor.
Add fresh coriander and mint leaves, fried onions, a few tomato slices, and lemon slices cut thick. Also add 7–8 thick green chilies. The fragrance of these fresh herbs and spices is what makes it "Sindhi" biryani. Finally, sprinkle some yellow food color on top.
Place the pot on a tawa for dum (steam cooking). First cook on medium flame for five minutes. Then turn off the flame and let it sit for 20 minutes before removing the lid. Do let me know in the comments how you liked this delicious Sindhi chicken biryani recipe.