Hello! Welcome to Recipes Inmai Veet Inakku. Today we are going to make delicious Chicken Biryani using 750 grams of chicken and 600 grams of seeraga samba rice. Let's see how to prepare it and what ingredients are needed. First, add two teaspoons of oil in a pan.
Once the green chili changes color and is sautéed well, add a handful of mint leaves and half a handful of coriander leaves. Sauté on low flame for 30 seconds. Once sautéed well, grind it in a mixer with a little water.
Add four small pieces of cinnamon, 5 cloves, 5 cardamoms, 2 pieces of Marathi moggu, 2 star anise, and 1 tablespoon of black stone flower. Sauté for about 10 seconds. Then add 1 teaspoon of fennel seeds and 4 tablespoons of cashew nuts.
Chop 4 large onions lengthwise and add them to the pan. Use about 250 grams of onions. Add 3 tablespoons of finely chopped mint leaves. Sauté the onions until golden brown. We won’t be using tomatoes in this biryani.
Once the onions are sautéed well, add 5 tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste (approximately 100 grams). Sauté this until the raw smell disappears — about 1 minute — on medium flame.
Add 1 tablespoon of kasuri methi and 1 tablespoon of turmeric powder. Sauté for 1 minute. Kasuri methi gives a great aroma and taste to the biryani. You can find this dried fenugreek in most departmental stores.
Add thick curd that is not too sour — about half a cup. Mix it well. Now add the chicken and mix thoroughly. I’ve used 750 grams of chicken (mostly thigh pieces), which are slightly large in size.
If you use small pieces, they may break apart in the biryani. Add salt as needed for the chicken — about 1 tablespoon. Add about half a cup of water, mix well, and cook the chicken on medium flame for about 10–15 minutes.
We cooked it for 15 minutes — it's half-cooked now. Stir well. For this biryani, I’ve soaked 2 glasses of seeraga samba rice. We'll add 3 glasses of water to cook it. That’s about 600 grams of rice.
After adding the water, add salt as needed — I’m adding 2 tablespoons. That should be enough. Add 2 tablespoons of biryani masala and 1 tablespoon of satkara (optional). Add 2 tablespoons of ghee as well.
Let the water come to a full boil for about 5 minutes. Now that it’s boiling, add the 2 glasses of soaked seeraga samba rice (after draining the water). Also, squeeze in half a lemon juice and stir.
Boil on medium flame for about 10 minutes with a lid on. Stir once or twice in between. After 10 minutes, the rice and water will be well balanced. At this stage, stir from the bottom so that the rice on top also gets cooked evenly.
Now let's put it on "dum" (slow cooking). Place an old dosa pan on the stove, keep the biryani vessel on top of it, and place another vessel with boiling water on top as a weight. Cook on medium flame for 5 minutes and low flame for 10 minutes. Then let it rest for 35 minutes.
Now it smells amazing — our Karnataka-style Thondi Biryani is ready! Gently fluff the biryani using a spatula without breaking the chicken pieces.
Now I’m adding a little ghee — you can add as you prefer. I’ve made this Thondi Biryani with great flavor. Try it at home using the same measurements. If you liked this video, please like, comment, and share!