Today we'll teach you how to make Wazwan-style chicken pulao at home. We all really like Wazwan pulao, and today we’ve brought a special version for you. You can add chicken to make this Wazwan-style pulao.
We have taken three cups of brown basmati rice and soaked it in water for an hour. If you're using white basmati, there's no need to soak it; you can cook it directly. But we’re using brown rice.
Take a pan and heat it until it starts to smoke. Add three chopped onions, finely chopped. Fry them until they become very dark brown — the darker they get, the richer the color and flavor of your pulao will be.
In another pan, I’ve taken 10 cups of water using a measuring cup — the same one I used to measure the rice. I will later reduce this to 6 cups. In this same water, I’ve added the onions I just browned.
Add cinnamon sticks, three bay leaves, two green cardamoms, about eight to ten cloves, and about eight cumin seeds — in Kashmiri style. Add two big spoonfuls of these spices.
Mix all the spices into the water and let it boil. Add salt according to taste — two teaspoons or adjust as you prefer. Let this come to a boil and then reduce the heat.
I’ve cut the chicken into smaller pieces because smaller pieces work well in pulao. But if you prefer, you can also use whole chicken pieces. Once the chicken turns brown, take it out and set it aside.
As you can see, the flavor and color have infused into the water. Now strain out the spices and set them aside. I’ve separated the spices and will only use the spiced water.
Since we used three cups of basmati rice, we’ll use six cups of this stock water. This is the same stock I just strained. If it's not enough, you can add regular water to make up the difference.
Add plain water if needed to reach the right quantity.
Now add everything into a rice cooker and cook it once. Before the second cook, we’ll add the remaining ingredients. This will be cooked twice in total. The first cook is done — as you can see, it looks great.
Now add cashews and walnuts. You can also add raisins, dates, or any dry fruits of your choice. You can skip the walnuts if you prefer.
After adding all the dry fruits and ghee, do the second cook in the rice cooker. Now that the second cook is done, I’ll remove the lid — see, it’s ready! Let me show you by flipping it over.
It looks great and is fully cooked. This is how you can make Wazwan-style chicken pulao at home. Try making it for Eid or before, and don’t forget to send us your feedback on our Instagram page.