Hi.. Namaskar.. How are you? Hope all are doing good. Hope all of you are happy with your Eid. I have brought you a special Eid special Thalassery biriyani. All of you do try it out. Hope all of you will try our Veenas Curryworld special Thalassery biriyani.
I was not that much in a hurry for 2 weeks. Because I had exams for 2 students. So I hope you know the difficulty of teaching 2 students. They are the students who asked me to sit here.
I haven't been able to reply to many comments in the last 2 weeks. So don't think anything else. I'm not free now. I'm sure I've cleared all your doubts. But I haven't replied to any comments in the last 2 weeks. I've taken 1.5kg chicken for this chicken biriyani.
If you want you can make it with 2kg of chicken.I don't use much of chicken here If you want more gravy you can use 5-6 onions.You have to adjust accordingly So without any delay let's see how to make Thalassery chicken biriyani Don't you want to try Thalassery chicken biriyani? Tell them to try it out See you all with a new recipe
Now lets begin to make thalassery biriyani. For that we need chicken. I have taken 1.5kg chicken here. I have washed it well with vinegar and salt and drained it. I have drawn the pieces of the chicken as shown in the video.
I havent taken big pieces. This is not the size of the normal chicken pieces you get in hotels. You can increase or decrease the size as you like. Now lets marinate this. Take a vessel for that.
Add ¼ tsp of turmeric powder Usually we don't add chilli powder in thalassery biriyani We use only green chillies for the spiciness But I don't feel like having it if it is white in colour So I'm going to add less than ½ tsp of chilli powder Only for the marination.We don't add chilli powder for the rest of the procedure Add some salt into it
1tsp lemon juice Mix it well and then add it to the chicken pieces Mix it well
Mix it well and keep it aside The first step is to marinate the chicken I usually don't marinate the chicken just because I didn't add chilli powder But I marinate the chicken to get rid of the salt and spiciness of the chicken If you don't have time and are in a hurry,you can marinate the chicken and keep it in the fridge overnight Close the lid and keep the chicken pieces in the fridge Now let's get ready
This is the biriyani masala for this recipe. You can make it today itself. If you are making it the day before or the day before, you can use it at that time itself. If you have the rest, you can close it and use it next time. I have added 2tbsp of fennel seeds to this. Next add 12 cardamoms to this. Add 1tsp of curry leaves.
Then we need to add 3-4 small pieces of cinnamon to it 1½ tsp of pepper powder I'm going to add 1¼ tsp of shah jeera to it If you don't have this,you can avoid it.It gives a nice aroma to the biriyani masala
Then we need to add 1 quarter of the jathipathri flower. If you add more, the flavour will stand out. Some add the seeds of the jathika. But if you add the seeds of the jathika, the flavour of the masala will stand out. So I am adding only this much. If you want you can add 1 quarter of the seeds of the jathika.
So you can see the small differences in each one. We shall roast this and powder it once it cools down. Some people powder it without roasting it. If you keep it for a long time, the flavours will be lost. So powder it in small quantities at home. We shall powder it again after that. This will be more.
If you want you can roast it and then grind it. I am not showing you how to roast it. I have shown it in many garam masala videos. If you have doubts, watch that video. Let me roast it and then grind it.
I have powdered the biriyani masala. You can close it and open it at that time. If you dont have cumin seeds, you can add 2 pinches of cumin seeds. Since I have cumin seeds, I am not adding cumin seeds. Close it and open it or keep it in a bowl.
Now we have to fry the shallots. I have taken 4 small onions here. If you have 2-3 big onions, you can take 2-3 big onions. So the main taste of this biriyani is the shallots that we have fried. Try to chop them finely while chopping.
If you cut it very finely,you will get it fried quickly and it will be crispy too. So if you have a big knife,you cannot cut it very finely. If you have a small knife like this,cut it very finely. If you get this measurement,it will be the best. Let me cut all these 4 onions finely like this.
We have sliced the onions finely. If you do it with your hands, you can fry it easily. Now heat some oil and fry it. Before frying the onions, we have to soak the rice. I have taken 4 glasses of rice here. I am adding 4 glasses of rice here.
When we make Thalassery biriyani we have to use Kaya rice and not Jeera rice. They never use Basmati rice in Thalassery biriyani. So this is the authentic taste of the small rice. If you dont like it you can use it. But we shouldnt give it as Thalassery biriyani.
After washing it well,soak it for 20mts.After 20mts,drain it and keep it aside. I have poured some sunflower oil in a kadayi. We shall fry it in 2 batches when it becomes hot. When the oil is hot enough,we shall add the onions to it.
This is on medium flame. Once it reaches a slight change in colour, increase the flame. Once it reaches a golden colour reduce the flame. If you take it when it reaches a golden colour, it may get burnt.
If you keep it outside,it will become crisp and the colour will also change The important thing is the fried onion This is the most important part of the biriyani If it is not well fried,it will affect the taste of the biriyani If it is burnt,the biriyani will not be good So always be careful while frying the onion
At that time if you want you can increase the flame to high. After that it will get fried fast. When the colour starts to change reduce the flame to low. This is the benefit of finely chopped onions. It will get fried fast. At the same time it will take a lot of time to fry the onions.
If you use a strainer or a strainer when you are washing it,it will be done. Now reduce the flame. By the time you take it out,the colour will change. It has become golden in colour. When you see the water,it will change in colour. Otherwise it will get burnt.
When you look at it like this,it doesn't look crispy.But when you take it out,it becomes crispy.You can understand it by looking at it.You don't have to use a tissue paper.Just put it in a strainer.
Now we have to crush the ginger,garlic and green chillies I've taken a big piece of ginger and a small piece of garlic
I have taken 16 green chillies here. If you want you can take 13 of them.
If you want you can adjust the spice level according to your taste. Green chillies are the spices used in biriyani. I am not adding chilli powder here. You can adjust as per your taste. I shall crush all these and come. You shouldnt grind them. Just crush them. Now lets make the chicken biriyani.
Now lets make the masala For that we need to add 2 tbsp of fried onion oil into it Because the smell of the fried onion gives a good smell to the oil Add 2 tbsp of oil into it Let it become hot When the oil is hot enough,add 5 big onions finely chopped into it Saute till it becomes transparent Add a pinch of salt into it
When it becomes transparent,add the crushed ginger,garlic and green chillies This is my dear friend Kavitha who helped me to make this biriyani Thank you so much Kavitha Because I'm from Trissur,I don't know much about authentic malabar dishes
If you ask the people in Malabar,they will tell you the exact ingredients,tricks and all.But that might be the secret of any biriyani or any curry. Kavitha is from Thalassery.So she knows the authentic taste of Thalassery biriyani.Its because of Kavitha's help that I could make such a good biriyani. So Kavithakutty,I'm expecting more and more tips like this.Thank you so much.Let this become transparent.
Now add the crushed ginger,garlic and green chillies Saute them well
I've noticed that some people do not add oil in the beginning itself.But when I tried it like that,I felt that the raw smell of ginger,garlic and green chillies will be gone for a long time That's why I've sauted it with some oil If you want it to be oil free,you can saute it with the tomato first and then add ginger,green chilli,garlic and then saute it with the onion When you saute it in the oil,the raw smell will be gone very fast
Saute well till it turns brown. If you feel its not enough, add 1tbsp oil to it. You can cook the rice on the other stove while sauting this. But I am not able to show you both because of the camera. Usually when you make biriyani, you cook the rice on the other stove.
If you do it that way,you have to be careful.Otherwise you will waste a lot of time.We can do all the things in a short time The raw smell has gone and the colour has changed.Now add some coriander leaves and mint leaves
Do not add too much mint leaves into it Mix well Now add a big ripe tomato into it Add some turmeric powder into it Do not add too much turmeric powder into it Mix well
Close the lid and cook the tomatoes in medium flame The tomatoes are well cooked and mashed well Now add the marinated chicken pieces into it Mix them well in medium flame
Close the lid and cook it well. Only then the water will come out from the chicken.
Let's cook the rice while the chicken is cooking I've soaked the rice for 20mts and drained it Take a vessel and add 6.25 glasses of water into it I've soaked 4 glasses of rice into it Now let's add the water into it You can remove the spices after it is boiled I don't have to remove all the spices but I always remove them 1 cinnamon stick,4 cardamoms,5 cardamoms
Add 1 pinch of fennel seeds Add 1 tsp of salt and mix well We should add ghee only after the salt is well mixed with the water It will be difficult to adjust the salt after adding the ghee Let the water boil well and then we can add the rice Let me check the salt
I've added 1tsp salt in total. You can adjust the salt according to your taste. Now it is correct. Let it boil well. We need 1.5 glasses of water for each rice.
Do not forget to stir the chicken once in a while. Do not let it stick to the bottom of the pan. The chicken will take 15-20mts to get cooked. If you are using Kerala chicken, there will be some changes.
When the chicken is well cooked,add the fried onions into it The salt has been perfected in the water.After that add 1 tbsp of ghee into it You can adjust the amount of ghee according to your taste You can add 1-1 tbsp of ghee into it.But if you add more ghee,it will be difficult to cook the chicken Let the water boil well
Do not overcook the chicken. It will break when you thumb it. So be careful. Now lets add some pistachios to this. It gives a special smell to the biriyani. Add some fried onions to this. Close and cook again.
The rice water has boiled well. Now I shall remove the spices from it. You can remove it if you want. I always add rice only after removing the spices. I have removed most of the spices. Now lets add the rice to this. Mix well.
Close the lid only after it comes to a boil When it comes to a boil,we can put it in high flame now itself After it comes to a boil,put it in low flame
Let me close the lid. By the time I opened the lid, the chicken pieces are well cooked. It took me around 20mts to cook the chicken. It needs some water but not too much. So let it cook for 2-3mts and then we shall keep it aside. Chilli powder is not a must in small biriyanis. So its not necessary to add chilli powder while marinating. You can avoid it if you want. Let me check the salt.
Now add 1tsp biriyani masala and mix well
Now we have to add lemon juice into it. You can feel the sourness when you taste it. Always check the taste of the masala before adding.
I'm going to add 1tsp of tamarind juice into it. Let me taste and see. You can add only if needed. If the tamarind is too sour, the biriyani won't taste good. The taste should always be balanced. The rice has begun to boil. I've closed the lid and kept it on low flame.
Do not forget to stir it from time to time When the water inside the biriyani becomes dry,turn off the flame I've closed the flame and kept it in low flame Let me check the taste of the biriyani after adding the lemon juice This is perfect for me The water in the biriyani has become dry enough Let's close the flame and keep it aside so that the flavour of the biriyani masala doesn't go out Keep it closed and keep it aside Stir it from time to time
Now the water has dried completely. We shall switch it off and keep it for 20mts. Then the rice will be cooked well. After 20mts we shall open it.
The rice is well cooked now. If you feel it is not cooked well, you can boil some hot water and close it for 5mts.
Now we have to dum the chicken. So lets begin to dum it. Take a non stick pan. I am adding little ghee to it. So that it doesnt stick to the pan.
Add the chicken masala into it If you are preparing chicken masala in a big vessel,you can keep it in that vessel itself But since it is my small vessel,I'm changing it into a big one Only after making sure that the taste of the chicken masala is correct,you can add more salt into it When I checked,everything is correct for me Make sure that the masala should not become too dry It should have a little moisture in it
The chicken is well cooked. Add some fried onions over it. Add some coriander leaves, mint leaves, cashew nuts and raisins. Sprinkle some biriyani masala powder over it. We will be adding the rice after the chicken masala is added. We will be adding the rice layer by layer.
First layer of rice is done. Now we shall repeat the same on top of this. Add few leaves and fried onions, cashew nuts, cashew nuts and masala powder.
If you want you can add some ghee into it. I am adding little. I had added little while cooking the rice. Now I am adding little more.
I've sprinkled some turmeric powder in some milk. It gives a nice colour to the rice. Its just for the beauty. You can add colour or turmeric powder if you want. Its the safest, healthiest and most natural turmeric powder. Don't add too much. Just add little at a time.
I used to add pineapple essence when I make Kerala biriyani. So we shouldnt add any essence in Thalassery biriyani. Now lets layer the remaining rice. This is for 7-8 people.
We have added the final layer of rice into it. Now we shall add the rest of the leaves into it. The salt of the rice will give the correct taste to the biriyani. Always be careful with the salt. Now close it with a foil paper.
If you cover it with a lid,it won't come off easily Now take a dosa tawa
Keep it on medium flame for a while and when you hear the sound of the chicken,put it on low flame
Turn off the flame after 10mts. Then open it after 10mts. I have kept it on medium flame. When you hear the boiling sound, switch off the flame. If you want you can bake it.
Preheat the oven and bake it for 20 minutes at 180 degree celsius I've switched it off after 10 minutes If you touch the lid,it should be very hot.So that the steam can reach to the top Let it be off and let it sit for 20 minutes After 20 minutes,let's remove the dum
You can see that the rice is not sticking to the bottom of the pan. That is how it should be. I shall tell you how to do the plating. Keep the rice aside. Put the masala rice and chicken pieces into a bowl and then add the rice to it. Mix well and transfer it to a bowl.
I've transferred all the rice into another bowl.Its only the rice and chicken in the bottom of the bowl.So I'm going to transfer the rice and chicken into the bowl which I'm going to serve in the beginning itself.So add the gravy and a piece of chicken into it.
After that we can add the rice into it. If you want you can add an egg into it. I always add an egg while serving biriyani. After that we can add the rice over it. If you want you can spread some onions over it.
Now our Thalassery Dum Biriyani is ready Its very easy to make.Its because I'm making a video.So I can't do all the things at the same time But you can make all the things at the same time if you have 4 stoves Let me taste it now I'm not taking the chicken pieces from the inside.The rice is hot enough
This is a perfect dish. Its spicy, salty and tasty.
I'm serving the salad with curd,tomato,onion and green chillies.I'm also serving the pickle with onion and vinegar.I'm also serving the date lemon pickle with it.I'm also serving the pineapple with it.I always serve it with biriyani.If we have any problem with the pineapple,it helps to get rid of it.
So if you have pineapple,try to have it with it. I had roasted cashew nuts and raisins in ghee. Its optional. If you want you can add it. Some dont add it. Some add it without roasting the cashew nuts and raisins. But I do it after roasting it. Its very tasty when you have it with raisins. So all of you do try out Veenas Curryworld special Thalassery biriyani on Friday.
See you all with a new recipe.Till then thank you