Hello friends! Welcome to Mettur Kitchen! Today in Mettur Kitchen, we are going to prepare a delicious, ready-to-serve, super tasty chicken biryani. For this, we need to prepare a small masala which will give the biryani an excellent flavor.
To make this, take a pan and add about one tablespoon of oil. Once the oil is hot, add about one tablespoon of chopped ginger — it’s roughly 20 grams. Along with that, add one tablespoon of garlic — crushed.
Add about 12 small onions, which I’ve chopped into two or three pieces each. Add them to the mix. After sautéing for a bit, add 5 green chilies sliced in half. Also add 5 cashew nuts, a handful of mint leaves, and a handful of coriander leaves.
Once it cools down, transfer everything to a blender jar. Add about ¼ cup of thick yogurt, and finally ¼ cup of water. Grind everything well. I’ve already ground it to a paste like this.
Now, for making the biryani, take a pot and add about 4 tablespoons of oil. Also add 3–4 tablespoons of ghee. Once it gets hot, add 2 bay leaves, 4 pieces of cinnamon, 5 cloves, 5 cardamoms, a bit of star anise, and a small...
...fennel seed (sombu). Sauté until the onions turn golden brown — this is very important. As you can see now, the onions have turned a nice golden brown. At this stage, we need to add the chicken. I’m using ¾ kg of chicken with bones today.
Add the chicken and mix it well with the sautéed onions. After a thorough mix, add the following masala: ¼ teaspoon turmeric powder, 1 teaspoon coriander powder, and 1 teaspoon biryani masala (or chicken masala, if you don’t have biryani masala).
Mix it all thoroughly. Then add the ground masala paste we made earlier. Also add salt to taste — I’ve used a little more than 1 teaspoon, just as per taste.
As you can see now, the chicken and masala are cooking well and everything looks beautiful. Now add half a tomato, chopped like this. Mix that in well.
Now you’ll see that the chicken, masala, and water are boiling nicely. Once it reaches this stage, we need to add the rice. Today I’m using 2 cups (400 grams) of seeraga samba rice. I’ve rinsed and cleaned it well.
Cook it on a medium flame. If you’re using a pressure cooker, give it just one whistle on medium flame. That way, when we open it, it’ll be cooked just right. Let it sit for 20–30 minutes undisturbed. Only then the biryani will be perfectly cooked and super tasty.
Today, I’ve made a little bit of chicken biryani. Along with it, I’ve added a boiled egg and curd raita — that’s it. Our delicious, aromatic chicken biryani is now ready! Let’s serve and taste it now.
It tastes absolutely great! You too should definitely try this recipe at home. If you liked this video, please subscribe to Mettur Kitchen. May your day be bright and beautiful!