Bismillah ir-Rahman ir-Rahim, Assalamu Alaikum. Welcome back to Crafted Kitchen, and today we are making Lucknowi Mutton Biryani.
Every biryani is special in its own way, but this one is my favorite because I’m from Lucknow. Lucknowi biryani is prepared with great delicacy and finesse. So, watch the video till the end as I’ll be sharing all the fine details.
Onions, coriander leaves, mint, tomatoes, lemon, green chilies, dried plums—oh no, none of these go into this biryani. Instead, we’ll use aromatic and flavorful spices prepared in two different ways. Some spices will be used whole.
Lucknow is famous for its aromatic touch, which enhances the biryani’s flavor. One tablespoon black pepper adds not only flavor but a hint of heat. Add 6–7 green cardamoms for aroma, and 7–8 cloves, which are...
Break a few pieces of cinnamon. All these whole spices will add both flavor and aroma. Now let’s move to the spices that we’ll grind coarsely: one tablespoon fennel, one tablespoon cumin, and 5–6 green cardamoms.
2–3 pieces of mace, one black cardamom, and a few cinnamon sticks. Grind these two spice blends separately. We will add the coarsely ground spices to the mutton broth.
And the finely ground spices will be added to the milk. A unique thing about this biryani is that it includes milk. Lucknowi biryani is presented in a special way and should not contain any whole spices. I’ve used medium-aged goat meat here.
For one kilo of meat, I’ve taken one kilo of extra-long grain basmati rice, which I’ve washed thoroughly in running water and soaked for 30 minutes. Rinsing the rice multiple times to remove starch is a very important step.
I’ll also be adding half a cup of pure ghee. Typically, only oil is used in restaurant biryani, but since this is homemade, it deserves something special. The oil is hot now, and I’m adding freshly ground ginger-garlic paste.
Add the mutton and sauté it until the color changes and it loses its raw smell. Lucknow is in North India, so its cuisine is also known as Awadhi cuisine. Although we call it biryani, technically...
...it's a layered rice and meat dish with elements like milk, rice, and meat, which were easily available in old times. With a few unique spices, this biryani evolved. The meat is well sautéed now, so I’ll add one tablespoon red chili powder...
...but the key ingredient is yogurt. I'm using 300 grams of fresh, homemade yogurt, which I’ll mix and cook slowly with the meat. Before adding yogurt to the meat, whisk it well to prevent curdling.
Now, sauté the yogurt and mutton together on low heat.
A few videos ago, I posted a Hyderabadi chicken dum biryani recipe—you must check that out too; I’m sure you’ll love it. To save time, I usually prepare the broth in a pressure cooker, but here, for the video...
...we don’t want any whole spices while eating this biryani. It should be refined, as Nawabi food demands. Now, I’ll add one liter of water to cook the meat and form the yakhni (broth).
Mix the water well, cover it with a lid, and cook until the meat is tender. It took me about 45 minutes here.
Let’s lift the lid—what an aroma! Let’s check if the meat is cooked. Yes, it's nicely done. When you touch the meat, it should be slightly sticky.
Now we need to strain the yakhni. First, remove all the meat pieces to a separate bowl. In the next step, we’ll prepare saffron milk and add the meat and yakhni to it. Strain the yakhni through cheesecloth or muslin.
If you’re a biryani lover, do let me know in the comments where you're watching from and which biryani you love the most. Gently separate all spices from the yakhni using a spoon and strain it.
Now our aromatic and flavorful yakhni is ready. Let’s prepare the saffron milk. In the same pot, I’m taking half a liter of milk.
Add about two pinches of saffron—it enhances both color and flavor. Mix well and wait for it to boil. For extra color, I’m adding a pinch of yellow food coloring and mixing it in.
Lucknowi biryani traditionally has yellow and orange tones. But if you want to skip the orange color, you can. The milk has come to a boil—now add the finely ground spice mix and stir well.
Good mutton biryani should have slightly sticky mutton with a perfectly balanced flavor. Add one tablespoon sugar—it helps balance the spices.
At this point, don’t let the yakhni dry too much. Cook for 3–4 more minutes to infuse flavors. Let’s get the rice ready. I’ve added 4–5 bay leaves to 4 liters of boiling water, along with...
Cover the pot and wait for the water to boil. The water has boiled—now add the soaked rice. As mentioned earlier, cook the rice to only 75%. A good indicator is when the grains fully elongate but still have a bite.
The rice is 75% cooked. Now strain it and add it over the yakhni. Don’t worry—since the yakhni has enough liquid and milk, the rice will finish cooking through steam.
Spread the rice gently using a spoon and seal the pot. I’m adding orange color for beauty—it’s optional. I’m also drizzling some ghee on top. You can use oil instead.
For the dum (steam cooking), cook the biryani on medium-high heat for 10 minutes and then on low heat for 20 minutes. Lucknowi biryani is traditionally served with finely sliced onion laccha. You can also serve it with yogurt raita or a bowl of yakhni.
So, you saw how easily this famous milk-based Lucknowi mutton biryani was prepared. A good biryani is one where the grains are separate. Always let it rest covered for 10 minutes before serving so the rice softens a bit.
Words can’t describe how flavorful this biryani is. Melt-in-the-mouth meat, long aromatic rice—this is a fragrant masterpiece. In Awadhi biryani, the balance of taste and aroma is unmatched.
Try this biryani recipe step by step and remember me in your prayers. Before you go, please like this video, subscribe to my channel, and share the recipe with your family and friends. Take good care and I’ll see you again, Insha’Allah, in the next video.