Hello Foodies, Welcome to Wish My Food. Today’s recipe is…
First, take a pan...
Now, slowly add ghee into the biryani handi. To the melted ghee, add a couple of cloves, a piece of cinnamon, one mace, one black cardamom, two green cardamoms, one bay leaf, and a teaspoon of shahi jeera.
Once the color starts to change slightly, add 1 tablespoon of ginger-garlic paste. After frying that, grind and add your special masala powder. Pour a little water so the masalas don’t burn.
You’ll see the ghee floating over the curd-based masala — just like this. Now, add the paste of 6-7 green chilies. This biryani gets its spice only from green chilies, not red chili powder.
Add some water, then drop in the paneer cubes. Boil them for a few minutes so all the flavors get absorbed. Some people think there’s no importance to marination — that's okay, but this method enhances the flavor.
Boil for just 3 minutes on high flame — no more. Then reduce to a simmer. Add 1 cup of fried brown onions to the handi. You can also use store-bought fried onions if needed.
After 2–3 minutes, remove the onions and set them aside. Now, add 2 liters of water and bring it to a boil. While boiling, add 3-inch cinnamon stick, 2 black cardamoms, half a teaspoon of…
Salt… a little more salt… sea salt.
After boiling well for 5–6 minutes, add 2 cups of soaked basmati rice. Cook on high flame only till it's 80% done. 80% means the rice should be almost fully cooked, but still firm.
At 80% done, stop boiling. Strain the rice…
Layer the rice over the paneer masala. Now cover with a lid tightly. Cook on high flame for 4 minutes, then on low flame for 5 minutes. Then turn off the stove and let it rest for 30 minutes.
Just look at how good it turned out! The taste is on the next level — very mild and flavorful. If you want more spice, serve with spicy mirchi ka salan. Did you like it? Then like, share, and...