Assalamu Alaikum, I'm Chef Afzal and today I'm going to share with you the recipe for Sindhi Biryani. Friends, this is a delicious biryani you can make at home for parties.
I believe this biryani is easier to make than other Karachi-style biryanis, and InshaAllah it will be delicious too. It's a very simple recipe, and whenever you make it for a party, everyone will enjoy it. So without wasting time, let’s start this amazing recipe.
Bismillah ir-Rahman ir-Rahim. Friends, Sindhi Biryani is traditionally made with sela rice, but I know my viewers use basmati rice. So in this video, I'm using basmati rice. I’ve taken 3 glasses, which weigh around 1 kg. I’ll tell you later how many people this serves. First, let's wash the rice.
We’ll wash the rice twice gently by rubbing it lightly. Then we’ll soak it for an hour. Meanwhile, I’ve taken a pressure cooker. I have 1.5 kg of meat with some fat. I’m adding 3 tomatoes to it.
Now add 1.5 tablespoons of red chili powder and 1.5 tablespoons of salt. The salt in biryani should be slightly more than usual so that it tastes right in the final dish. Then I added 1 tablespoon of cumin seeds.
Add ½ tablespoon turmeric, ¼ tablespoon nutmeg and mace powder, 1 small spoon whole cumin seeds, 1 broken piece of star anise, 8–10 cloves, 5 green cardamoms, and 1 small spoon black peppercorns.
Add two pieces of cinnamon, 3 bay leaves, and 1 cup of yogurt. Add 1.5 tablespoons of green chili paste. If you're using whole chilies, grind about 5.
Add 2.5 tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste. Use a generous amount of this paste. Then add two glasses of water. Since we’ll cook in a pressure cooker for 25–28 minutes, I’m using a little extra water. We'll reduce it later.
Now I’ve closed the pressure cooker and placed it on the stove for 25 minutes—first 5–6 minutes on high, then on medium flame. Meanwhile, on another burner, we’ll fry onions. I took 1 cup oil and sliced two medium onions for frying.
As you can see, the onions are nicely fried. Save the oil; we’ll need it later in the biryani. First, remove the fried onions from the pot and then strain and store the leftover oil separately. The pressure cooker has finished as well—here’s a look at the meat—it’s perfectly cooked.
I cooked it for about 25 minutes, and the meat is now tender. We’ll use the same pot where we fried the onions to finish cooking the biryani. Let’s dry the curry a bit and sauté it to reduce the water. We'll also add some ingredients during this time.
Add 7–8 dried plums and around 8–10 prunes. These are essential in Sindhi biryani. Add ½ tablespoon of Chinese salt (MSG)—most popular biryanis use it for better flavor. Also add kewra water (screwpine essence).
Without kewra water, biryani lacks its signature aroma. Add 3 tablespoons of it, and sauté everything well. We’ll dry this curry mixture over the next 5–7 minutes until the water evaporates.
Now we'll add water for cooking the rice. (Note: line repeated for emphasis.) The idea is to add water based on rice quantity.
For premium basmati rice, 4.5 glasses of water should be enough to keep the biryani fluffy. Let it boil on high heat, then add the soaked rice. Keep the flame high initially, then lower it to allow the rice to expand.
We haven’t added oil yet because the meat itself was fatty. If you’re using lean meat, then add 1 cup of cooking oil while making the curry. Now after 4–5 minutes on low flame, most of the water is absorbed by the rice.
Now gently shake the pot—don’t stir too much with a spoon because basmati rice breaks easily. I’m adding about ½ tablespoon of yellow food color at this stage.
Add food color when there’s still a bit of water left in the rice. Also, I’m adding ½ cup of the previously saved fried onion oil. It enhances flavor and prevents the rice from sticking. Finally, sprinkle the fried onions over the top.
Now it’s time to let it steam (dum). Place a pan (tawa) under the pot, and let it cook for 12–15 minutes. Always note the time when doing dum so the rice doesn’t overcook. I’ll leave it for 15 minutes and then show you the final result.
After exactly 15 minutes, I’ll open the lid. MashaAllah, the aroma is amazing—and look how beautiful this biryani has turned out!
Just looking at it must have made your mouth water! Whether you serve this at a gathering or make it at home, I’m sure you’ll love it. Let me now show you the final look and check how well the meat has cooked. See how tender it is—despite the large chunks.
Now let’s check it. Bismillah ir-Rahman ir-Rahim.
MashaAllah, this biryani turned out absolutely delicious. The spices are mild, but if you prefer it spicier, you can increase the quantity, especially red chili. But in my opinion, this is a perfectly balanced biryani. If you liked this recipe, please give it a like and share with your friends.