Hello and welcome back to my YouTube channel. Today on Khana Khazana, I’ll be making a very yummy dish — Beef Biryani. You can make this anytime — on Eid, Bakrid, or any festival. You can also make this biryani with mutton, i.e., goat meat.
So first, we’ll prepare the yakhni (broth). I’ve added the meat into a pressure cooker — it’s 1 kg of beef. I’ve also added two glasses of water. To tenderize the meat, I’ve added 1 teaspoon of salt and 1 teaspoon of cumin seeds.
And 4 to 5 green cardamoms, 2 teaspoons of fennel seeds — fennel gives a very nice flavor. In Lucknow, fennel is always added to biryani. Also adding 4 to 5 bay leaves.
Now we’ll give it a light mix, then I’ll close the lid of the pressure cooker. We’ll cook this on low flame until it gives 7 to 8 whistles. As you can see, the broth is done after 7 whistles on low flame — the meat is nicely tender.
And our yakhni is ready. I’ve set it aside. Meanwhile, let’s start the next process. I’ve taken a large pot and added 2 tablespoons of mustard oil. Now I’m adding one medium-sized chopped onion.
Adding 2 tablespoons of crushed ginger-garlic paste. I’ll cook the paste well with the onions. Make sure to sauté it properly so that the oil separates from the masala. Then we’ll add the meat.
So I’m directly adding the meat pieces from the yakhni into this. Do not add the whole spices from the yakhni, just the meat. I’ve also added the water from the yakhni. So now both the meat and broth have been added to the pot.
Now we’ll add salt here. About 2 teaspoons of salt is perfect — I’ve added a full 2 teaspoons. You can also taste and adjust it later, after adding the rice. Now I’m adding half a chopped lemon.
Give this a gentle mix. You can also add juice of half a lemon if you prefer. I’ve added the half lemon here. Now I’m adding the rice — two glasses of raw rice. Since we’re making it like a pulao-style biryani…
… and we had one glass of broth from the yakhni, the total water added to the rice is three glasses for two glasses of rice. The rice had been soaked for half an hour. I’ve stirred it gently so it doesn't break.
Now I’ve mixed a pinch of red food color in a bit of water. I’m adding 2 to 4 drops of kewra water. If you’re using the larger bottle of kewra, just add 1 teaspoon.
After placing on dum (slow cooking), the rice has become perfectly soft, the color is well absorbed, and the fragrance of the kewra essence has blended beautifully. Now I’m going to serve it. I’ve turned off the flame — and this delicious biryani is ready.