Hello friends, my name is Khursheed Alam and you're watching your favorite channel "Biryani Ka Sheher." Today, I’ve brought for you a very special, authentic Hyderabadi Biryani. I’ll show you how to easily make it at home.
Even if you don’t have a lagan (traditional pot), you can use any thick-bottomed vessel. One thing to keep in mind is: the mutton should go directly into the same pot you’ll cook the biryani in, like I’ve done here.
Add two tablespoons of red chili powder, one teaspoon of green chili paste, and one teaspoon of turmeric powder. The soul of Hyderabadi biryani is fried onions.
In restaurants, we keep fried onions ready. If you're making this at home and don’t have them, fry onions first. I’ve already made a video showing how to fry onions properly. You’ll find the link above in the “i” button.
Now, take a mortar and pestle and add cardamom — at least ten. Lightly crush them before adding. Don't add whole cardamom pods; crush them slightly so they release aroma.
Crush them just a little like this — that enhances the fragrance beautifully. After that, add two-inch cinnamon sticks, broken into pieces.
Now mash the onions well so they blend into the mixture — just like I’m doing. Mix it well and mash it thoroughly. Just ensure the mutton bones don’t prick your hands.
Whisk the yogurt first. Add one cup of oil — preferably the oil left over from frying onions. That oil gives it the special aroma — the very essence of Hyderabadi biryani.
Now mix everything thoroughly, just like I’m doing. Set this mixture aside — this is the marination step. Now I’ll tell you about the rice preparation.
I’ve soaked one kilogram of rice. Then I’ve taken two small bowls, added a little water in each — in one, add yellow food color, like this, and in the other…
Both are essential. If you’re making it at home, you can use saffron entirely. But for restaurants or selling, you can't use that much saffron — so a little color is necessary.
Now mix well with hot water. You can even use your hands. After adding water, it will cool slightly — come to room temperature. You’ll need just enough to pour later.
Add two mace flowers, four bay leaves, eight green cardamoms — be sure to add these. Then, add two tablespoons of salt. Also add mint leaves — this is essential.
Turn the gas on and wait for the water to boil. Meanwhile, drain the soaked rice like this.
This way, the excess water drains and the rice cooks faster. Our water is boiling now. I’ll add the rice and show you how long to boil it.
After adding rice, don’t turn the heat to max — stir it gently, like this. Boil the rice only up to 60% — not more. See how well it’s boiling? This is what you want.
If you want, you can remove the bay leaves and green chilies before layering — or leave them in. That’s your choice. Now layer the rice evenly on top of the marinated mutton like this.
If you don’t have a strainer, use a colander — your choice. Layer the rice evenly, and then you can either make small holes or gently mix it like I did.
If you don’t like food color, you can use turmeric instead. After that, drizzle desi ghee on top — slightly warm ghee like this.
It’s optional. Now take regular roti flour (wheat dough) and roll it into a strip like this. This is for sealing the lid for dum (slow cooking), like I’ve done here.
We don’t use kewra water or rose water in Hyderabadi biryani. Its authentic aroma comes from saffron, mint, and fried onions. If you like kewra or rose water, you can add them, but every dish has its unique beauty.
Now dampen your hands with water and run them around the rim like this before sealing with a lid. Press the lid down well after sealing with dough.
Turn on the gas. First cook on high for 10 minutes — like now. Then turn the heat to low and leave it. I’ll tell you the total time once I open it. Don’t lift the lid in between.
Your biryani won’t burn. If you're worried, place a tawa (flat pan) underneath. It won’t burn because the mutton releases moisture, and we’ve added yogurt.
Before opening the biryani, let me answer some questions my viewers asked — will mutton cook in 30 minutes? It’s raw — will it become tender?
Yes, it becomes very tender when cooked properly. No steam escaped — this means it was sealed well. I cooked it for 45 minutes — 10 minutes on high, 15 on low, and so on.
Mutton will become tender — even in a cooker it softens in 15 minutes, so why not in 45 here? You just need to follow the correct method like I did.
If you're unsure, you can use papaya paste during marination. Now I’ll open it and show you — the dough seal dries completely. See how nicely it dried? That means it’s cooked perfectly.
Such an amazing aroma — it's beyond words! The rice is beautifully cooked and separated. You can count the grains. Absolutely wonderful.
Just look at these beautiful grains. I’m saying it again — it’s amazing. I’m so hungry because I haven’t eaten anything while making this biryani. Now I’ll plate it and show you.
When you see the mutton separate from the bone like this — see that? That means it’s fully cooked. Mutton separates only when it’s perfectly tender.
Mint leaves, mint leaves, mint leaves, mint leaves, mint leaves, mint leaves.
Subscribe to my channel.