Now we are going to prepare Malabar style chicken biriyani. Let's see how to make it. Take 1 kg chicken cut into big pieces. Add salt, 2 tsp lemon juice, half of a small lemon, ¼ tsp turmeric powder, and 1 tsp chilli powder. Mix it well and keep it aside.
[unintelligible]
Add 1 tsp fennel seeds, 1 tsp cashew nuts, a small piece of cinnamon, ½ tsp cloves, 1 bay leaf, 1 clove, and 10 cardamoms.
Add 1.5 tsp turmeric powder, 1.5 tsp cumin powder, and 2 tsp chilli powder.
Now add the marinated chicken.
Marinate for just 15 minutes since we didn’t add ginger and garlic, so it doesn’t need long marination. Add one big tomato directly with the chicken (no need to sauté with onion). Add ¼ cup curd and mix well. The curd softens the chicken, and we already added lemon juice earlier.
Add some salt and some coriander leaves.
Add plenty of fresh mint leaves — make sure they are nice and fresh for better flavor.
The chicken is cooked well. Don’t cook it on high flame — use medium flame. Add 1.25 cups of coconut milk and mix. Cook for 5 more minutes and set aside. It shouldn’t be too dry; some gravy is needed. The chicken masala is ready. Now we will prepare ghee rice using basmati rice.
Heat 3 tbsp ghee. Add 1 tsp fennel seeds, 1 tsp pepper, 8 cardamoms, 1 tbsp tomato, 1 tbsp cashew nut powder, and 1 tbsp curry leaves.
Add another 1 tbsp curry leaves, 1 tsp of shallots, 6 large shallots, and 4 tbsp washed tamarind.
[unintelligible]
Add 1 tbsp salt, mix well, and close the lid. When the rice is half cooked, stir it and close again. Once it is cooked, set it aside. We’ll cook it for 10 more minutes while “dumming.” For garnishing, add ghee in a pan and roast the raisins.
Add cashew nuts and fry well. Then add onion and fry. In a big vessel, layer the chicken masala and add the cooked rice on top.
[unintelligible]
After 20 minutes, turn off the flame and let it rest for 5–10 minutes. Then open the lid. Our biriyani is ready. Everyone should try this tasty biriyani. It tastes better than biriyani made with basmati rice. This rice has a unique flavor. Most people don’t know about this version.
Our Malabar Chicken Biriyani is ready. Serve hot with biriyani chutney, pappadam, pickle, or any side. If you liked this recipe, share it with your friends. Like, comment, and subscribe to our channel.