If you make mutton biryani like this, everyone will enjoy it. It’s easy to prepare.
I’ll show you how to make tasty mutton biryani at home. I took ½ kg mutton and ½ kg bullet rice, soaked and washed.
This rice yields about 2.5 bowls. If you don’t have bullet rice, use cumin rice or regular rice.
Marinate the mutton with ¾ tsp salt, ½ tsp turmeric, ½ tsp ginger-garlic paste, and ½ cup (100g) yogurt. Mix well and marinate for at least 30 minutes.
Grind mint, coriander, 1-inch sliced ginger, 8–10 garlic cloves, ½ onion, ½ tsp black pepper, ½ tsp anise, and ½ glass water into a fine paste.
Add green masala to the marinated mutton. Heat a heavy-bottomed pan, add 4–5 tbsp ghee and oil.
Add whole garam masala and ½ handful kasoori methi. Fry, then add 3 finely sliced onions and cook till golden brown and crispy.
Add marinated mutton. Cook it covered on low heat (or pressure cook for 3–4 whistles). Fry mutton for 2–3 minutes, cover, and cook for 15 minutes, stirring occasionally.
Add green masala and fry till raw smell disappears. Cook another 15–20 minutes until water is absorbed. Add ½ glass water and continue cooking until mutton is soft.
Add salt to taste and ½ tsp garam masala powder. Mix well and cook another 15–20 minutes on medium flame, stirring every 2 minutes.
Once mutton is fully cooked and water evaporates, add soaked rice and mix gently.
Add more green masala. Use bullet, cumin, or normal rice. Add 5 cups of water for 2.5 cups of rice. Squeeze ½ lemon for sourness.
Do not cover. Let rice boil on high heat until 75% cooked. Then reduce to low heat.
When rice is almost cooked, cover with a heavy lid (like a pot with water or a stone) and cook on low for 20 minutes.
After 20 minutes, open and mix gently. Biryani is cooked perfectly with no sticking.
This method is simple and doesn’t require pressure cooking. Thank you for watching.