If you're a beginner at cooking or want to make the perfect Hyderabadi Kacchi Gosht-style Chicken Dum Biryani, then this recipe is for you. We’ll make a very delicious and perfect Chicken Dum Biryani using simple home spices.
We’ll make this recipe with 1.5 kg of rice and 1.5 kg of chicken. First, take 1.5 cups of oil and heat it. Into the hot oil, add 500 grams of thinly sliced onions. Fry the onions on medium to high flame until golden.
Once the oil has cooled down, we’ll add 1.5 kg of chicken to it. I’ve used slightly bigger pieces of chicken, but you can use smaller pieces if you prefer. Now, for the whole spices, take 12 green cardamoms, 10 cloves, and 10 kabab chini (cubebs).
Add 3 tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste. Add 1 cup of well-whisked yogurt. Add the fried onions — about 1 cup full or two handfuls. Add one handful of mint leaves and one handful of coriander leaves.
Add 5 to 6 whole green chilies. Add 1 teaspoon of cumin powder, 1 teaspoon of coriander powder, 1 teaspoon of spicy red chili powder, half a teaspoon of turmeric powder, 1 teaspoon of garam masala powder, and salt according to the 1.5 kg quantity.
Squeeze half a lemon into this mixture. Now mix everything thoroughly. Let the chicken marinate with the spices for at least 2 hours. If you have time, marinate the chicken overnight for best results.
Add the whole spices again. Also add green chilies, some coriander leaves, and mint leaves. Squeeze the juice of half a lemon again. Add the lemon peels as well. Add 2 tablespoons of salt.
Add the rice and gently stir it once with a spoon. As soon as the rice starts to boil, let it cook in the boiling water for just 3 minutes. For Kacchi Gosht Dum Biryani, the rice should not be cooked more than 70-80%.
Now transfer it all to a large pot in which we’ll cook the biryani. It’s best if the pot has a thick bottom. If your pot has a thin bottom, place a tawa (griddle) underneath it while cooking on dum.
Add 1 cup of hot water directly into the chicken along with the rice. Spread the chicken evenly. Add half a teaspoon of garam masala powder to the fried onions. Mix it well and spread this over the chicken.
I’ve taken 1/4 teaspoon of saffron and 1/4 teaspoon of yellow food color, mixed well, and added it on top of the rice. Also, add some of the fried onions mixed with garam masala here.
Now we need to seal the pot. I’m using aluminum foil so the biryani cooks well with steam. You can also use dough to seal the pot. After applying foil, cover with the lid.
Now cook the biryani on dum (low flame) for one hour. Once the biryani is properly cooked on dum, remove the lid. After cooking, insert a spoon like this to check if water is at the bottom.
As soon as I removed the lid and foil, a wonderful aroma spread throughout the house. Gently mix the rice from bottom to top so that the spices and chicken mix well with the rice. This is the Hyderabadi...
Serve this Hyderabadi Dum Biryani with yogurt raita or chutney.