Peace and blessings of Allah be upon you. Peace and blessings of Allah be upon you. Peace and blessings of Allah be upon you. Peace and blessings of Allah be upon you. Peace and blessings be upon you.
There are many different types of biryani, and Inshallah in upcoming videos we will cover all those different types. But generally, if you talk in broad categories, biryani is of only two types.
So let's start the recipe. Bismillah ir-Rahman ir-Rahim. First, we will prepare the biryani masala. For that, I’ve taken 1 tablespoon cumin seeds, 1 tablespoon fennel seeds, and 1 heaped spoon of black peppercorns.
Mace is also added to this, because I’m making this with half a kilo of meat. So mace will go in about a whole flower. I didn’t have it right now, so please add it. You won’t see it here.
This is for our biryani masala, we have taken all the whole spices needed.
I had small desi roses, which I dried and saved. I’ve taken petals from 3-4 of those and removed the stems and the seed parts. I’ve also taken two bay leaves.
Half a teaspoon cumin, about 7-8 black peppercorns, and dried plums (alu bukhara) are essential for biryani. They give it great flavor and also act as tenderizers.
I've taken five dried plums. We will now grind this masala and mix it with the other whole spices. Let me show you this in a separate bowl. I’ve pounded the masala in a mortar and pestle, but you can use a grinder if you want.
But the essential oils in spices fly away in high-speed grinders, so it’s better to pound it manually. After mixing both masalas, I added one teaspoon kewra water.
Now, in a separate pan, we take two tablespoons of ghee and two tablespoons of oil — the same oil in which I fried onions, because fried onions are a must in biryani, as you know.
One tablespoon red chili powder, 1/4 teaspoon turmeric, and around 1.5 teaspoons coriander powder. We’ll mix it well and also add half a tablespoon of salt, and some chopped cilantro.
I wanted to chop 4-5 green chilies but couldn’t do it in the chopper, so I added mint and coriander along with them to chop all three together easily.
The masala is now fully sautéed and I’ve set it aside. Now we’ll prepare the mutton. I’ve taken 500 grams of mutton and added half a teaspoon of dried papaya powder to it. I dry and store papaya at home.
So whether you have fresh or dry papaya, do add it because it works as a meat tenderizer. Papaya must go in.
Now we add yogurt — about 100 grams. But we won't add all of it now.
We will mix everything properly — all the ingredients.
We’re getting ready for biryani! We’re getting ready for biryani! We’re getting ready for biryani!
Keep aside one tablespoon of the dry masala we made earlier — we will use this in layering. I’ve added almost all of the biryani masala to the marination. Mix well and break up any lumps.
I’ve added about one tablespoon more. Now we will cover and let this marinate for 2.5 to 3 hours at least. If you marinate it overnight, it will be even better — you can't even imagine how good!
We will let it rest. Just wait and see how amazing it becomes.
After black pepper, we add 2-3 green cardamoms and one tablespoon of the same oil — I’m adding this oil in stages. First, I’m adding it into the marinade.
When the water boils, we add some chopped coriander, mint leaves, and one tablespoon of the fried onions — this gives a great aroma. Now we’ll boil the water.
We will cook it for five minutes — just the water, for flavoring. This will be the base of the rice.
Let’s do the layering. After 5 minutes, take a thick-bottomed pot. First, drizzle a little oil at the bottom, then spread all the marinated mutton evenly.
Add 100g of yogurt, fried onions, cilantro, mint, green chilies, lemon slices, and some roasted cashews.
Add about 1 tablespoon of the same onion-fried oil. That’s our first layer. Now we’ll add the rice. Note that the rice is not fully cooked — I’ll show again to be clear.
Basmati rice cooks quickly — make sure you don’t boil it for more than 5-6 minutes. Then we layer half the rice and repeat the toppings just like before.
Now on the top layer we pour saffron water — I’ll share the recipe for that soon, Inshallah. It’s very easy to make. So saffron water is added, then two tablespoons of desi ghee.
Saffron water has been added.
Then kewra water. Now we take some dough and seal the rim of the pot with it to make it airtight. Before adding color, I forgot to pour the remaining water.
I forgot to add that earlier. You should do that before adding food coloring. Now cover the pot tightly and seal it. Place a heavy object on top to keep it sealed.
Place it on high flame for 5 minutes. After that, lower the heat completely and cook on low for the next 20 minutes. So after 5 minutes, reduce the heat to a minimum.
The biryani is fully cooked now. I’ve opened the lid — wait 5 minutes after turning off the gas before opening the lid. See, the top rice is nicely done.
Don’t mix the whole pot together at once — it will feel odd. Take it out gently and serve in a dish.
Garnish it with some cashews. You can also add more fried onions if you wish. I’ve added a few mint leaves. Serve it with your favorite raita or salad.
The rice is perfectly cooked — not overdone. And the meat is juicy and tender. See how easily it breaks apart. That means it’s well-cooked.
If you follow all the steps like this, Inshallah your biryani will turn out just as amazing — or even better. That’s my prayer for you.
May you make it beautifully and with love. Ameen. Summa Ameen.