Assalamu Alaikum! In today’s meal, I am your host Taood, and today’s dish is the queen of all biryanis — Bombay Biryani! And we’re going to make it in an authentic way, just like the restaurant-style or wedding-style Bombay Biryani. Before we begin, I request you to please subscribe to the channel, like, share, and press the bell icon. Come along with me, let’s get started quickly.
Bismillah-ir-Rahman-ir-Rahim. Let's begin by reciting Durood Sharif. For our Bombay Biryani, which we are making with mutton, we are taking 1 kg of mutton and adding two tomatoes. This will create a great marinade for the Bombay Biryani. I’ve chopped about 8–10 green chilies here.
Whole spices include 1 tablespoon cumin, along with black cardamom, cinnamon, cloves, and bay leaf. Use as needed, but generously, because the packaged garam masala doesn’t have strong flavor. I’ve browned 3 onions here. I’m adding one and a half onions to the marinade and saving the rest for layering later.
Now I’m adding ½ kg yogurt. The better the yogurt, the better the marinade. The more flavorful the masalas you add to the biryani, the better the outcome. Add 1 tbsp crushed red chili, 1½ tbsp ground red chili, 1 tbsp coriander powder, and 1 tsp turmeric.
1 tablespoon garam masala powder, 1 teaspoon nutmeg and mace powder. We’ll also add some dried plums. Mix the marinade well. This is the same oil in which I fried the onions. It’s very easy — some people cook the meat raw in Bombay, while others marinate it like this. But this method gives a very tasty and aromatic result — people are crazy about Bombay Biryani.
By the grace of Allah, Alhamdulillah, I make good recipes — especially Indian and Bombay-style recipes. You've seen many of them before. Now we’ll marinate the meat. Once this is done, half of our job is done. When you marinate mutton or chicken properly, the rest becomes easy. Marinate it with dedication.
Marination is done.
Even after cooking, you can adjust the salt level. The Bombay Biryani should be slightly salty so that when you add the rice — since here the masala is kept separate unlike other biryanis — it balances well. I’ll also show you how I separate the masala. Our marination is now complete.
I’ll now keep it for about 2 hours to marinate. So we’ve marinated the meat for 2 hours. Following a very simple procedure — we won’t add any more spices now. Just a few things for layering. First, I’ll clean this large tray (thaal), turn on the stove, and get it ready.
I’ve poured water into the tray to keep it ready. Once the meat is sautéed, we’ll use this water to cook it through. First step — since my meat is well-marinated, I’ll sauté it until the color changes. The vegetables like tomato and onion we added earlier will also soften. Sauté everything really well.
As you can see, the meat and masala have been sautéed.
Always clean your blender and chopper well after making the masala. My tray is clean now, and I’ll add water as needed. We’ll cook the meat until tender — the more tender the meat, the more delicious the Bombay Biryani. The water looks perfect now.
Now I’ll let it cook for at least an hour. I showed you 1 kg of meat with bones and fat — this will create a great yakhni (broth). While the meat cooks, we’ll prepare the rice. For Bombay Biryani, rice is often parboiled. I’ll add 2 tablespoons of...
...salt and a little oil to give the rice a shine. I’ve soaked 1 kg of good-quality basmati rice for the 1 kg meat. These are the perfect rice for Bombay Biryani.
They are semi-steamed rice. My rice is 80% cooked — we’ll keep it slightly underdone because the Bombay Biryani has a lot of gravy. I’ll now drain the rice and move on to the next steps.
Mashallah, the meat is wonderfully tender and the masala is flavorful — exactly the feel and taste of Bombay Biryani. (repeating: “Bombay Bombay...” many times)
Now the browned onions that we saved earlier during marination are added. For layering, we’ll also add large tomato slices, fresh coriander, and mint.
Half a bunch of coriander, half a bunch of mint — you can even use a full bunch of mint to make it even better. And now all the rice will go on top.
Now comes the yellow coloring on top. Normally, kewra essence isn’t used in Bombay Biryani because the marination itself provides such a wonderful fragrance. Here goes the saffron or yellow food color mixed in water.
We’ll add this light saffron water to give the rice a two-tone color. Now we’ll cover it with a lid and put it on dum (slow steam) for a while.
After 15–16 minutes, oh Alhamdulillah, what a fragrance! We won’t touch it yet — first, we sprinkle about 3–4 tablespoons of oil on top. This keeps the rice separate in Bombay Biryani. We’ll cover it again for 2 more minutes. Alhamdulillah, my Bombay Biryani is ready with an amazing aroma.
Let me now show you something interesting — I always like to present dishes in the way they are traditionally made in their region or country. All the rice will go to one side...
Now I’ll show you the presentation — see this brown masala underneath? This is the real soul of Bombay Biryani. This beautiful layer at the bottom — I’ll plate it and show you on the presentation table.