Assalamu Alaikum, welcome to my channel Nawabi Dishes. Today your host brings you a very special Eid dish from Lucknow, a very famous one called Mutton Biryani. Viewers, Lucknow’s mutton biryani is truly special, whether for weddings or for serving guests at home.
So let’s get started. But before that, I request you to please subscribe to my channel, like the video, and don’t forget to share it.
So viewers, for mutton biryani we’ll need 1 kg of long grain basmati rice which we’ll soak for half an hour. We've taken 700 grams of meat and washed it well. We need 2 teaspoons of ginger paste and 2 teaspoons of garlic paste.
We'll need 100 grams of yogurt, 1 teaspoon of sugar, and 100 grams of fresh cream. Add salt to taste. We’ll also use half a teaspoon of edible yellow food color.
We’ll take a pinch of saffron. 2 teaspoons of red chili powder. 2 teaspoons of cardamom and mace powder. And we’ll need 200 ml of milk. Also, we’ll need 150 ml of oil.
We’ll also need 2 tablespoons of desi ghee. For aroma, we’ll use kewra water, rose water, or rose gel, and edible sweet essence.
So viewers, our ingredients are ready. Let’s begin making the mutton biryani. For whole spices, we’ll need 8-10 green cardamoms, 8-10 cloves, and one bay leaf. Take a pan and place it on high flame. Once the oil heats up, add the onions.
We’ll sauté the onions until they turn light golden brown. Keep stirring continuously to avoid burning. See, the onions have started to turn golden. Now we’ll add the meat.
We need to fry the meat well in oil. Now we’ll add 3-4 small cardamoms and cloves. I’ve kept the flame high.
The meat has been fried well and changed color. Now we’ll add the spices — add 2 teaspoons of ginger paste. You can reduce the flame if needed.
Add 2 teaspoons of garlic paste and mix it well.
Sauté this mixture for 2-3 minutes. After that, add red chili powder. You can add more if you like it spicy. Then we’ll add around 3 teaspoons of salt. You can taste and adjust later.
Now we’ll add about 1 teaspoon of cardamom and mace powder. Mix and keep sautéing. We’ve lowered the flame to avoid burning. Now we’ll add yogurt.
Take about 100 grams of yogurt, approximately 4-5 tablespoons. After frying the yogurt properly, we’ll add 3 drops of edible sweet essence. Mix it well.
We’ve added all the spices. Now we’ll add one cup of water. Since we need to cook the meat, we’ve added 200–250 ml of water. Cover with a lid and cook on low flame for 15–20 minutes. Viewers, if you want...
Now we’ll take another pot with 4 liters of water and add 5–6 tablespoons of salt. Also add cloves and cardamom. Bring it to a boil, and once it boils, we’ll add the rice which we had soaked earlier.
We’ll cover it and let it come to a boil. Meanwhile, let’s check the biryani gravy to see if the meat is tender. It’s been around 20 minutes. The spices have released oil. First, let’s check the meat for doneness.
The biryani masala is perfectly ready now. We’ll switch off the flame and keep it covered for 10 minutes. Viewers, now I’m going to share a very important step that makes Lucknowi mutton biryani truly unique.
Watch this step carefully as it is key. First, we’ll separate all the oil into a bowl. Then, in the next step, we’ll take the mutton pieces out separately — not the masala, just the pieces.
We’ve taken out all the meat pieces. Now take a large bowl in which we’ll prepare the biryani gravy. Transfer the masala into this bowl. We’ve separated the oil and the mutton pieces. Now in this masala...
We’ll add 1 teaspoon of cardamom and mace powder. Then add 1 teaspoon of sugar. After that, add salt.
We’ve added 1 teaspoon of salt. We’ll check later and adjust if needed. Now add fresh cream. Then add 2 teaspoons of kewra water.
You can easily find kewra water anywhere. After that, add 1 to 1.5 teaspoons of rose water.
So our gravy is almost ready. Now we’ll add the saffron that we soaked in a spoon of water. Mix everything well. Then I added half a teaspoon of red chili powder.
You can add 1 to 1.5 teaspoons if you like it spicier. We don’t eat very spicy, so I’m using less. Now take the oil we had separated from the gravy, and add 3 drops of edible sweet essence to it.
Then add 2 tablespoons of desi ghee. The mutton biryani masala is completely ready. Now add the mutton pieces to this gravy.
Mix everything well. Now add the separated oil into it. Viewers, authentic Lucknowi biryani is made exactly with this kind of prepared gravy.
Let’s now check the water for rice that we kept on the stove. Yes, it’s boiling. Now add the soaked rice after draining the water.
Mix well. If the salt seems less, you can taste and add more. Let it come to a boil again. When it boils, check the rice. It should be half-cooked, not fully done.
Now in the pot in which we’ll assemble the biryani for dum, first add a layer of rice. On top of the rice, add the biryani masala. Place all the meat pieces and half of the gravy.
As you can see, we’ve added all the pieces on the first layer. Now pour half of the gravy evenly over this layer. Then add another layer of rice on top and pour the remaining gravy over it evenly.
Now add the remaining rice as the final top layer. Spread it evenly. Then mix the yellow food color with 2 tablespoons of water and pour it over the rice like this.
Now we’ll put the biryani on dum. First place it on high flame for 5 minutes with the lid on. After 5 minutes, reduce the flame and place a tawa underneath the pot.
Viewers, placing the tawa prevents the biryani from burning at the bottom. Cook on medium flame for 5 minutes, then lower the flame for 10 more minutes. Then switch off the gas. The biryani is on dum now.
Alright viewers, 30 minutes have passed. Let’s open the biryani. The rice is perfectly cooked and the aroma is amazing. It looks beautiful too. Each grain of rice is separate and fluffy.
Viewers, the whole house is filled with the aroma of biryani and everyone is excited to eat it. While serving, be gentle so that the rice grains don’t break. Serve it from one side carefully.
So viewers, the Lucknowi mutton biryani is ready. Serve it with yogurt raita and salad. Do make this biryani on special occasions and don’t forget to share this recipe with your friends and relatives.
For that, please subscribe to our channel and press the bell icon so that you can get notifications of upcoming videos easily.