Today’s recipe is Mughlai Biryani. It's a very delicious and flavorful biryani—one of the perfect versions. We'll prepare it in three stages.
This method makes the process really easy. It’s simple to follow and uses some special spices to make it rich and flavorful. One of our viewers requested this Mughlai Biryani recipe.
We'll share some tips too. There are many types of biryanis—like Yakhni Pulao, which is different—and many others I don’t have time to name right now.
Let’s begin this perfect biryani. We've taken around 1 kg of chicken, and used golden basmati sela rice. If you’re unsure, just go with this type. I’ve soaked the rice already.
I used about 700 grams of rice and over 1 kg of chicken. We’ll also use some mint leaves, coriander leaves, cashews, almonds, raisins, and crushed ginger-garlic.
About 2 inches of ginger and 15 cloves of garlic, and lemon juice—1.5 lemons. We also need 200g curd and 100g cream, and 3 medium tomatoes.
We can easily make this using homemade spices—no need for any special store-bought ones. Just pick a good brand if buying. We’ll use salt based on the chicken quantity.
We’re also using 2 star anise, 2 cinnamon sticks, and 4 cloves. Around 1 tablespoon of green cardamom powder. Now we’ll marinate the chicken.
We’ll mix everything well. Add mint, coriander, and some onions. This saves time during cooking.
We’ll also add crushed garlic—not paste—and lemon juice. Mix everything well with hands and let it rest for half an hour.
We don’t need water here because the chicken releases moisture. Meanwhile, boil water for the rice and add whole spices to it for flavor.
We’ll boil extra water—enough for 1 kg of rice. Keep in mind we’ll drain this rice later. Once boiling, add the soaked rice.
The tomatoes should be cooked until they melt and the oil separates. Let’s check—it’s nicely cooked and the oil is releasing.
Now mix the marinated chicken into the tomato mixture. It’s already releasing some boil. We'll reduce the flame and let it cook on low.
We’ll keep stirring and cooking on low flame for 5-minute intervals until the chicken is fully cooked and the moisture evaporates.
Once the water dries up, you’ll notice the aroma coming through—that means it’s nearly ready.
The water has dried up completely.
Now the masala is fragrant and the base is ready for layering.
It has been roasted well—the masala looks perfect and aromatic.
Now that it's cooked, we’ll layer it with rice. We’ve drained the boiled rice and will start with one layer.
Place the rice in a separate pot for layering. We already added one base layer earlier. Now add golden fried onions.
Spread evenly. You can add them directly or like this. Then add the chicken masala in a single, even layer—not too thick.
Next, add fried onions, mint, and coriander leaves again, and more chicken masala as needed.
The chicken is so aromatic and ready. This is the perfect marinated Mughlai Biryani. Add a final rice layer, and place any remaining chicken on top.
Now we’ll add saffron milk and food color. Only saffron might not give a strong color, so I’ve added both. You can use just saffron if you want.
Keep a few cashews and raisins aside for garnish. Add 3-4 tablespoons of ghee as tadka from a small pan. Add the rest of the garnish.
Seal the pot tightly so no steam escapes. I’m doing this with dough now. After that, we’ll cover it properly.
You can use dough around the edges for sealing.
There are many ways to seal it—it doesn’t really matter which as long as no steam escapes and the rice cooks well.
The dum (steam) cooking is done. The rice is cooked beautifully and the biryani is ready.
This Mughlai Biryani turns out really special and delicious.
Do try this Mughlai Biryani. It’s super tasty and yummy. Try it and let us know your feedback. Like, share, and subscribe to support our channel.