Assalamu Alaikum dear Dastarkhwan! A heartfelt welcome to all my loving viewers and subscribers. Today I’m sharing with you the recipe for an amazing chicken biryani from Kolkata’s Bengali-area shop. Just by looking at it, you can tell it’s a total hit—so flavorful and rich. You must make it, and when you do, you won’t just make one—because it’s that good.
The Kolkata Bengali-area shop biryani is known for its deep dark‑brown color. It isn’t made with brown food color. So try making this biryani once—you’ll be astonished at how superb it turns out at home. Let’s quickly get into the recipe.
To make the biryani, I’m taking 300 g mustard oil. Once it gets hot, reduce the flame to medium and add 150 g finely chopped onions. Fry them until golden and crispy—that’s your birista. The oil needs to be hot and, on medium flame, fry until birista forms well.
Now in the same oil, fry the potatoes. The Kolkata Bengali‑area shop biryani uses this method. Fry the potatoes on medium flame until the color changes nicely. I’ll also show how to test—poke with a knife, and if it goes in without the potato falling apart, it’s about 80% cooked.
When testing, if the knife goes in and the potato holds, it’s good—20% will finish cooking during the dum stage. …
… (Omitted repeated filler lines.)
Use plenty of oil for this biryani—it makes Kolkata biryani rich. As you fry potatoes and onions, the oil level drops. Now add 150 g onions and fry them. With the onions, add 2 bay leaves, 3 small green cardamoms, 2 large cardamoms, 10–12 cloves, and 2–3 cinnamon sticks.
Fry the onions until very dark brown. Kolkata Bengali‑area shop biryani deliberately avoids food color—relying instead on dark‑fried onions for the beautiful brown hue on potatoes and chicken, and later on the rice. You’ll taste it when you try it!
Now add 3 glasses of water. Into it, add 1 Tbsp ginger paste and 1 Tbsp garlic paste, plus salt and chicken.
Add salt and the chicken.
If you’ve eaten Kolkata biryani in restaurants or weddings, you’ll notice the meat pieces are large—that gives a deeper taste. Because Kolkata biryani is made with yakhni (meat broth), you want big pieces that won’t break during dum.
… (Repeated lines omitted.)
After about 15 minutes cooking the chicken, turn it over. The chicken isn't fully cooked yet, as the pieces are large and need time. Now I’ll add yogurt—that makes this biryani distinctive, and the flavor is exceptional. Be sure to try it—Kolkata biryani is famous.
After adding the yogurt, stir well—add nothing else—and cook covered on medium flame for 15 minutes. At that point, you’ll see the bones emerging from the chicken—then you know it's ready. Don’t use small pieces, or the chicken may fall apart during dum. We use large chunks for that reason. Remove all the meat pieces and strain the yakhni (broth). If it seems too much, dry it by simmering 5–6 minutes high flame. The broth will thicken nicely.
Yakhni is ready. Strain out the spices—don’t use them further—they’ve imparted their flavor to the broth. I poured about two cups of yakhni. Now add ½ cup warm milk (not hot) and 1 tsp sugar—to balance the flavors. Also add 1 Tbsp biryani masala—the one used in Bengali‑area restaurant/wedding style—which I've uploaded on my channel; see the link in description. Add juice of one lemon—its flavor is excellent.
Next, add 1 Tbsp rose water and 1 Tbsp kewra water (kewra is strong—adjust to taste), and about 6 drops of sweet melaleuca attar—it gives a lovely fragrance and is traditional in Kolkata biryani. Also, I had fried birista earlier—add that now.
I also boiled four eggs earlier, and we’ll add a little yellow food color typical of restaurants and weddings—but lightly, if desired. Now: potatoes go in first, with chicken placed around them.
After mixing the yakhni with the potatoes and chicken, we add them. The taste comes from cooked rice that’s only 70–75% done—the broth makes the rice perfect with dum steam. Then add the previously fried potatoes and birista (fried onions) over the mixture. I can’t explain the aroma; you must make it. I’m also adding 50 g mawa (khoa)—available at sweet shops and dairies—to enrich it. Cover and set aside.
Add 10–12 cloves, 2–3 green cardamoms, and salt to taste in the water. Then the rice. I used 1 kg rice—biryani rice works best, soaked for half an hour. The water is boiling …
… Cook the rice to only 70% doneness: once you add rice when the water first boils, after it boils again, time six minutes. Rice quality affects cooking time, so use high-quality rice. After cooking, drain quickly, then layer the chicken and potatoes, followed by rice, quickly so the basmati doesn’t overcook.
Using a spoon, gently spread the rice to help dum form properly—some chefs use cloth, but this works well. Then add a little yellow food color—don’t overdo it. Do this quickly so warm rice stays fluffy.
That birista (fried onions) from the Bengali area is placed over the rice—In Kolkata’s main hotels they don’t use it, but the Bengali-area shops do. Add a drizzle of oil (no ghee yet). Let it sit.
When ready, drizzle 3–4 Tbsp ghee on top of the rice. In Kolkata Bengali‑area biryani, ghee is added at the least phase to infuse the aroma. Cover immediately.
I’m using the oil left from frying onions—this gives flavor. Then we dum on a hot tawa—or use a heavy-bottom pot if not using a tawa—high flame for 10 minutes, then low flame for 30–40 minutes.
And finally, our biryani is ready—beautiful, rich, and fragrantly aromatic. Top with 3–4 Tbsp ghee. Cover for 2–3 minutes to finish off the flavor.
See the grains—they're fully separate and fluffy with amazing aroma. Use the exact method I described to achieve this spectacular Kolkata Bengali-area shop biryani at home.
This is the top-quality Bengali-area shop biryani, replicable at home. Now, to serve, we first scoop rice to one side, then place chicken or potatoes on the rice, then carefully layer the rest—this ensures oily bottom favorites go to those who want them, while the top stays lighter. That’s why Kolkata biryani is rich and layered.
After mixing chicken and potatoes, you’ll see how beautiful the dish looks. I boiled three to four eggs earlier—eggs are commonly used in Kolkata biryani, and people love it.
If you’re from Kolkata or visiting, try the Bengali-area shop biryani—like at Patelnagar, Dum Dum, or Ruby by Qadhaba—they offer this distinct taste. Try it at home; it’s extraordinary.
I hope you enjoyed this recipe. Please like, subscribe, and comment—it means a lot. Don’t forget to press the bell icon so you get notified about my new videos first. Make it, enjoy it, share it, be happy—Allah Hafiz.