Today, the biryani recipe we’re going to share with you — believe me, whether it's a professional chef or home cook, this recipe will impress everyone. It's a very delicious and aromatic biryani.
When you try this recipe, be sure to give your feedback. If you like the video, give it a like and share it with your friends. First, we’ve taken chicken, which we’ve washed and cleaned well. The method is on our channel.
1.5 tsp salt
1.5 tsp turmeric powder
1 tbsp coriander powder
1 tsp red chili powder
1 tsp Kashmiri red chili powder
We’ll add roasted cumin here. Then we’re going to add some orange food color.
Now we’re adding 2 teaspoons of biryani masala. The recipe is already on our channel and the link is in the description, so you can easily make it at home. If you don’t want to make it at home, you can use store-bought.
Mix everything well with the chicken. Now add a handful of finely chopped coriander and a handful of mint leaves. We've taken 4–5 small green chilies.
Now we’ve started to roast it. We'll continue adding ingredients as it cooks.
Use onions according to your preference — more or less as you like.
You can adjust everything based on your taste and preference.
We will not add water at this stage.
Now we're taking rice — for 1 kg of chicken, we’ve taken 1 kg of rice. We soaked it for two hours. We’ve used Golden Sella rice. You can use any rice of your choice.
Make sure to prepare everything carefully.
After taking out the whole spices, add 2 tablespoons of mint and 2 tablespoons of coriander, and juice from half a lemon. This makes the rice fluffy and flavorful. Now add the soaked rice.
It’s been 15 minutes since the chicken started cooking — it’s nicely tender now. Stir and check that there's no excess water. The masala has turned out great. It’s been 7 minutes since the rice started boiling — check it.
Add half of the rice, then add fried onions over it.
This adds great flavor. We've added 1 tablespoon kewra water and two pinches of saffron. Add some orange food color, coriander, and mint — about 1–2 handfuls.
If you don’t have foil, you can use a cloth to seal the pot. Cover it with a lid and place a heavy object on top for pressure. Now turn the gas flame to low.
The biryani is now on dum (steam cooking) and finishing beautifully.
The biryani has turned out incredibly delicious and aromatic — even better than what you get at weddings. When you make this at home, you’ll see just how amazing this recipe is. Now, let's serve our biryani.