Assalamu Alaikum! Welcome back to another vlog. Today, we are making a very easy and tempting biryani in a rice cooker. It’s made with simple ingredients and turns out very tasty. You should definitely try this recipe. Let’s get started.
[Music/No dialogue]
After a while, you can see the chicken is well boiled and tender. We will now separate it. We've transferred it into a bowl and taken a pan in which we will add mustard oil. Heat the oil properly.
As you can see, the oil is hot. Now add the boiled chicken pieces and fry them until the outer layer becomes light brown. Do not over-fry. The chicken is nicely fried now, and we’ll remove it into a bowl.
Follow the same procedure. The chicken pieces are properly fried and set aside. Reheat the oil and add chopped onions—three large onions, pre-chopped. Fry them well until they turn golden brown.
As you can see, the onions are well fried. Don’t over-fry them or the biryani will become too bitter. We’ve removed the fried onions. Now, in the same oil, add cinnamon stick, green and black cardamoms, bay leaf, cloves, black pepper, and one tablespoon cumin seeds. Stir them slightly.
Next, add ginger-garlic paste and mix well. Then add chopped tomatoes—about two to three—and stir well so they fry properly.
Now add the spices: 3 tablespoons Kashmiri red chili powder, 1 tablespoon turmeric powder, 1 tablespoon coriander powder, and 1 tablespoon garam masala. Mix everything well. Make sure to use fresh ingredients for the best flavor.
We’ve added 2 tablespoons of salt—adjust to taste. After mixing well and letting it cool slightly, we’ll add this mixture to the preheated rice cooker. Now start layering: first, the fried chicken pieces, then the masala mixture.
[Unintelligible repetitive filler about water – removed]
Pay attention to the measurements. Mix well and add 1 tablespoon biryani masala. For color, we used half a tablespoon red food color—this is optional. Add the fried onions on top.
You can see the color looks great. Now cover the rice cooker and cook the biryani. After some time, it's ready—very tasty and tempting.
The biryani has a nice color, and the rice is perfectly cooked. Now it's ready to be served hot. You can serve it with lemon, dry fruits, and coriander.
When we tasted it, it was very delicious and amazing. You should definitely try this recipe and share your feedback with us. That’s all for today’s video!