In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. Peace be upon you. Today we are sharing a very special recipe for chicken biryani with you. This is Kashmiri chicken biryani, which you could also call a special type of chicken biryani. The method is a bit different and very lovely. It uses slightly different spices, which give it an amazing flavor. You'll really enjoy making it.
The recipe is very easy to make, but the results are fantastic. I suggest you try this at least once. God willing, your family will really enjoy this biryani.
So how do we prepare this recipe? If you like the video, don’t forget to give it a like. To make your biryani perfect and delicious, don't skip the video and follow all the steps exactly. We’ll start this recipe by boiling the chicken in turmeric and water. We've taken about 1 liter of water and set it to heat.
As mentioned, this recipe is a bit different but very special. Boiling the chicken in turmeric water gives it a nice aroma and color. When you try it, you'll see what I mean. We added 1 tsp of salt and 1 tsp of turmeric. To speed up the boiling, we’ve turned up the heat.
At my home, we prefer raw basmati rice, but this biryani is traditionally made with sela basmati rice. You can use that if you like—just soak it for about two hours. Since we’re using long grain raw basmati rice, we’ll soak it for 30 to 45 minutes only.
We've taken 5 cups of rice, about 1250 grams. Wash it 3 to 4 times gently and soak for 30 to 45 minutes. The turmeric and salt water is now boiling well. We’ll now add the chicken.
We’ve taken about 1.1 kg of cleaned chicken. Add it to the boiling water and let it cook on high to medium heat for about 5 to 7 minutes. If your chicken usually takes 12 to 15 minutes to cook fully, only boil it for about 5 to 6 minutes here to soften it slightly.
Turn off the heat and set it aside. We’ve heated around 300 ml of oil. Authentic Kashmiri chicken biryani is made in mustard oil, so that’s what we’ve used. But feel free to use any cooking oil you prefer.
Add 6 medium-sized sliced onions and a pinch or two of salt. Fry until golden brown to make crispy fried onions. Next, we’ll prepare a spice mix with yogurt. Take about half a kilo of well-beaten yogurt.
Add 1.5 tbsp fennel powder, 1.5 tbsp red chili powder (adjust to taste), 0.5 tbsp turmeric, 0.5 tbsp coriander powder, 1/4 tsp garam masala, and 2 tbsp biryani masala. Now add whole spices: 8–9 green cardamoms, 3–4 pieces of cinnamon, 2 star anise, 9–10 cloves (adjust if large), and 4 bay leaves.
Mix all the spices into the yogurt and let it sit for 5–7 minutes. Meanwhile, for the rice, boil 4 liters of water and add 4–5 tbsp salt and 3–4 bay leaves.
The onions are now golden, so remove them from the oil, straining well. We’ll fry the chicken in the same leftover oil. Spread out the onions so they stay crispy. Now fry the chicken in two batches until both sides are well browned.
These steps give the biryani an amazing flavor. As I said, the method is a bit unique but really special. After frying the chicken, add the yogurt spice mix. We’ve also crushed about 15 garlic cloves. You can use paste, but crushed works best here.
Add half of the fried onions to the chicken and mix everything gently. Since we’ve added yogurt, keep the heat low and mix well.
Cook on low heat until the gravy comes to a boil. Add 1.5 tsp salt and mix well again. Let it cook on low until the chicken becomes soft. After about 5–6 minutes, stir it once and check. If needed, cook it a bit longer.
Eventually, the yogurt water will reduce and blend into the chicken. Let it simmer. Meanwhile, the rice water has come to a boil. Add the soaked rice. Keep the heat high and wait for the water to return to a boil.
Once boiling again, cook the rice for 7 minutes—until it’s about 70% done. Don’t overcook, or the rice will turn mushy. After 7 minutes, test by pressing a grain: it should break into three parts but still feel slightly firm inside.
Now strain the rice. The gravy is ready and looks great—oil floating on top and a little thickened. Time to layer the biryani. Divide the rice into three parts. First, sprinkle some biryani masala.
Add some fried chicken pieces and chopped cilantro. Gently mix without breaking the rice. This spreads the aroma evenly. Then add half the remaining chicken and gravy on top.
Add the second layer of rice and repeat the same steps. Do this for three layers. Add the remaining chicken and gravy, mix gently. For aroma, add saffron milk and a few drops of food color if desired.
You can also add a bit of kewra water. Top with the remaining fried onions and chopped coriander.
Add 0.5 tsp more biryani masala. Cover the pot with a thick cloth and seal the lid tightly. Tuck in the edges of the cloth to avoid heat loss. Cook on high to medium heat for 3–4 minutes, then on low heat for 20 minutes.
Place a heavy object on the lid to trap the steam. After 20 minutes, it should be perfectly steamed. Add the remaining oil on top and 2–3 tbsp of desi ghee for extra aroma and flavor.
This enhances both smell and richness. Let it rest covered for 10 minutes so the rice sets. This prevents it from breaking when served. Use a spoon from the side to gently loosen the rice.
This biryani turns out very flavorful. You should definitely try this recipe. God willing, you won’t be disappointed. Do share your feedback and experience. If you liked the video, give it a like and share it with family and friends.
If you're visiting the channel for the first time, don’t forget to subscribe for updates on future recipes. Take care and remember us in your prayers. See you in the next video. Allah Hafiz.