Today we will make Kolkata’s very famous, tasty, and aromatic biryani – Arsalan Chicken Biryani. To begin, let's first prepare its biryani masala. For that, take 2 teaspoons cumin seeds, 2 teaspoons white pepper—you can also use black pepper.
Take half a nutmeg and crush it like this before adding. Add 4 tablespoons of dried rose petals. Now grind all these ingredients. Our fragrant Arsalan Biryani Masala is ready.
Take two pinches or 1/8 teaspoon of orange food color. Mix everything together. Rub the color well onto the chicken. Now refrigerate it for marination for at least half an hour. This makes the chicken soft and helps the color soak in.
Add 2 teaspoons of the prepared biryani masala, 2 teaspoons red chili powder, 1 cup water, and again 2 pinches (or 1/8 tsp) of orange food color.
Add 1 teaspoon of salt. Mix everything thoroughly so there are no lumps of yogurt. Now add the potatoes—I’ve taken half a kilo. If you have large potatoes—
—mix the potatoes in the masala. Once it starts boiling, reduce to low flame and cover it to cook for 15–20 minutes. After 20–25 minutes, once the potatoes are soft, drain the water and remove the potatoes. Save the leftover masala.
Add 2 medium-sized sliced onions.
Fry the onions until golden brown. Once nicely golden, remove them and drain the oil. Transfer the onions to a plate. Now in the same oil, add the marinated chicken.
Fry the chicken well. Once golden on one side, flip it. Once both sides are nicely golden, remove the chicken. Fry the next batch as well. This way, fry all the chicken.
Now in the same oil, add the pre-boiled potatoes, one by one. Fry them until golden on one side, then flip. Once golden on both sides, remove the potatoes.
Now take a big pot to prepare the biryani. Add the leftover oil used to fry the onions, potatoes, and chicken. Also add the leftover masala in which the potatoes were boiled.
Add 4 to 5 green cardamoms. Add 1/4 cup khoya (milk solids). Now add 1/4 cup fresh cream—you can also use milk cream. Mix everything well and mix the khoya thoroughly.
Now layer the chicken nicely. Cover and cook the chicken on low flame for 15–20 minutes. Meanwhile, prepare the rice. Take 2.5–3 liters of water in a pot. Add 2 bay leaves, green cardamom—
I had soaked basmati rice for half an hour. Wash it well and drain the water, then add it to the boiling water. Add 1 teaspoon of salt. Let the rice boil. Now back to the chicken—remove the lid.
Now our chicken and potato layer is ready. The chicken is well-cooked, and so are the potatoes. Add 4 to 5 dried plums—they add great flavor to biryani. Add 1 teaspoon biryani masala as well.
Now add 3 to 4 tablespoons of desi ghee (clarified butter).
Now add the rice. The rice has been cooked to 90%. Drain the water and layer the rice over the biryani. Spread it evenly to form a good layer of rice.
Add 1 teaspoon of biryani masala. I’m adding orange food color—if you don’t prefer food color, you can skip it. Add 2 drops of kewra essence (or rose water if preferred).
Add the fried onions on top. Now add 2 to 3 tablespoons of desi ghee. Cover with a lid and let it dum cook (steam) for 15–20 minutes on low flame. The chicken and potatoes are already cooked, and the rice is nearly done.
Now we serve it—definitely try this Kolkata-style Arsalan biryani. If you liked this recipe, please like, share, comment, and subscribe to our channel.