Assalamualaikum, welcome to Home Cooking Point. Today we’re going to share the recipe of Shan Bombay Biryani Masala with you. This biryani is very quick to make and turns out very delicious. Follow my recipe step...
So let’s begin. We’ve taken 1 cup of yogurt here. Now we’ll add the Shan Bombay Biryani Masala packet into it. We’ll add the entire packet as we’re making 1 kg of biryani. Now we’ll mix it well...
We’ll add a few more spices into it. We have coriander powder here. 1 tablespoon red chili powder. ½ teaspoon turmeric powder. ½ teaspoon garam masala powder. Now we’ll mix it all well...
After mixing, we’ll set it aside. We’re making 1 kg of biryani, so we’ve added some whole spices as well. Everything is mixed well. Now we’ll keep this aside. Let’s move on...
We’ve taken 3 medium-sized potatoes, cut like this. Now we’ll fry them. Our potatoes are nicely fried now. We’ll take them out.
The potatoes are fried. We’ve taken them out. Now we’ll add 1 tablespoon of whole garam masala — one star anise, one black cardamom, a cinnamon stick, 3–4 cloves, 5 black peppers, and 3 green cardamoms...
We’ve taken 1 kg of chicken. Now we’ll add the chicken into it.
Now we’ll mix it well and fry until the chicken changes color. See, we’ve roasted it well for 3–4 minutes. Now we’ll add 4 tablespoons of ginger garlic paste...
Add 1 teaspoon of salt and roast it well until the raw smell of the ginger is gone.
We’ve roasted the ginger-garlic paste. Now we’ll add tomatoes.
Now we’ll add the Shan Bombay Biryani masala mix that we prepared with yogurt. At this stage, you can taste and adjust salt and chili as per your preference. We’ll also add the fried potatoes now.
Now mix everything well, cover, and cook for 10 minutes on medium flame so the masala cooks properly. Cover and cook on medium flame for 10 minutes.
It’s been 10 minutes. Our masala is perfectly cooked. Now we’ll add 1 cup of brown fried onions. We had prepared these earlier. If you don’t have them ready...
We’ve added 1 cup of brown onions. We had browned 4–5 medium-sized onions. The recipe for fried onions is on our channel. You can check the link in the description box.
Now we’ll add a little fresh coriander and mix it well. Then we’ll cover and cook it for 5 minutes on medium flame.
5 minutes have passed, let’s check the masala. It smells amazing. Our korma is ready. Turn off the gas and set it aside. Now we’ll boil the rice for the biryani.
We’ve taken 3–4 liters of water to boil the rice — that’s about 10–12 glasses. Into this, add a cinnamon stick, ½ teaspoon cumin seeds, some curry leaves, and a little...
We’ve taken juice of one lemon — add that too. Instead of lemon juice, you can also use vinegar. (Repeated many times unnecessarily in original.)
See, the water is boiling. Now we’ll add the rice. We’ve taken 1 kg of basmati rice and soaked it an hour earlier. Now we’ll add it — this is 4 cups of rice.
Mix it well and cook it 80% — the grains should still have a slight bite.
The rice is 80% cooked now. Turn off the gas, strain the rice, and begin layering the biryani in the same pot we boiled the rice in. First, drizzle a bit of oil...
Now we’ll add a layer of rice. After the rice layer, we’ll add a layer of the korma.
We’ve added the korma layer. Now we’ll add fresh coriander and mint. We’ve cut green chilies in half and added them. Now we’ll add fried onions. Next comes the second layer of rice.
We’ve added the second rice layer. Now we’ll add another layer of korma. That makes two layers total. Then again add coriander, mint, and fried onions. Now on top...
We’ll add the final rice layer. We’ve added the final rice layer. Now we’ll add yellow food color and 1 tablespoon of kewra water. Add fried onions on top...
A bit more coriander and mint leaves on top. Now cover and steam (dum) the biryani for 15 minutes. After 15 minutes of dum, the biryani is completely ready. Now we’ll...
See how perfectly the biryani turned out. The aroma is amazing, and the rice is perfectly fluffy and separate.
Now we’ll serve it. Look how wonderful our Shan Bombay Biryani has turned out. The rice is perfectly cooked and separate, just like the biryani you get at restaurants.
Your biryani will turn out just as amazing. I hope you liked today’s recipe. If you did, please like, share, and subscribe to our channel. And don’t forget to press the bell icon.