Today we are going to make Bombay Chicken Dum Biryani, in my style. So come, let’s look at the recipe.
I have taken one kilo of chicken. The chicken should be cleaned and washed thoroughly. We will mix spices into it. I’m adding 3 tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste, 2 tablespoons of red chili powder, and 2 tablespoons of coriander powder.
Half a teaspoon of turmeric powder, 1 teaspoon of garam masala powder, 2 teaspoons of Bombay Biryani masala – I’ve shown how to make this on my channel – and salt to taste.
Half a bowl of yogurt. We will whisk the yogurt well.
I’ve made birista from onions (fried onions). I’ve made birista from onions. I’ve made birista from onions. I’ve made birista from onions. I’ve made birista from onions. I’ve made birista from onions.
After adding all this, mix it well. Add the juice of one lemon – I forgot to mention earlier, so I’m saying it now. Mix everything well and leave it to marinate for one hour.
For 1 kilo of rice, I’m using 3 liters of water. The water is boiling well. I will add the basmati rice to it. I didn’t soak it earlier. Add the rice. Use whatever basmati rice you prefer.
Into this, I’ll add some whole spices: 3 pieces of bay leaf, 1 teaspoon of cumin seeds, 1 teaspoon of shahi jeera (caraway), 5 sticks of cinnamon, 5 green cardamoms, 5 black cardamoms, and 1 flower (mace or star anise).
Add 2 heaped tablespoons of salt, as we’ll be draining this water later. The salt needs to be a little more than usual since the water will be discarded. Mix well.
Now we’ll cook the rice, but not fully – just until it’s a little undercooked, since we will cook it more during the "dum" (steam) process. As you can see, the rice is ready. I’ve drained it using a strainer and separated the water completely.
We’ll heat some oil. The oil is hot now. I’ll pour it in.
Level the mixture evenly on all sides. Keep the flame on medium – not high.
After placing the potatoes, we’ll add rice on top.
We’ll keep the flame low. Add half of the rice first, then layer it with birista (fried onions).
Add a bit of mint, a bit of fresh coriander, and powdered cardamom and nutmeg.
I had soaked saffron in milk – pour a little now and save some to add on top later. Now we’ll add the remaining rice on top.
Repeat the same layering as before. Add a few drops of food color – this is optional. If you want to add it, go ahead. If not, you can skip it. I’ve prepared this at home.
Add 3 to 4 tablespoons of milk over it. Also add the nutmeg and cardamom powder. Sprinkle a little garam masala powder on top. I’ve shown how to make this on my channel – you can check it out.
Now we’ll add more mint and coriander. I’ll also add a few drops of kewra water. This is how you prepare it and it turns out great.
If this method doesn’t work for you, you can take a small bowl of water, add a few drops of kewra water, and pour that over. Add desi ghee as per your taste – I’ll add 3 to 4 tablespoons because I like it.
Instead of desi ghee, you can also use oil. Now wrap everything well with foil so the steam doesn’t escape, and cook it on low flame on dum. We’ll steam it for about 10 to 15 minutes so it cooks properly.
Place a lid and put a heavy weight on it so the steam doesn't escape and the chicken cooks well. As you can see, steam has started to come out from the sides.
Now our chicken has cooked thoroughly. Earlier I said 10–15 minutes, but I’ve kept it for 20–25 minutes on dum. In that time, the chicken gets cooked perfectly. Now we’ll turn off the gas.
So our Bombay Chicken Dum Biryani is ready! InshaAllah, you try it too and remember me in your prayers. For more such delicious recipes, follow me on YouTube, like, share, and send good comments.