Hi! Hello! Welcome to our channel! We're so glad you're here.
Thank you!
Take 2 medium-sized onions and slice them thinly. Add 1 tsp of sugar.
We've finished frying the onions. Now transfer them to a bowl. Let's prepare the biryani masala using the same ghee we used to fry the onions.
For the masala, take 4 medium-sized onions and slice them lengthwise. Add enough salt and mix it well.
[Background sounds removed due to corruption.]
[Audio appears to be corrupted or unclear, skipped for continuity.]
Add 2 tsp garam masala. Now add 1 kg of chicken and mix well.
Add 1 tbsp lemon juice and 3 tbsp curd.
[Audio unintelligible, skipped.]
Add 1 tbsp ginger-garlic paste.
[Repeated "1" — likely an error or placeholder. Skipped.]
[Audio unintelligible, skipped.]
...and...
Now the biryani is set and placed on dum. Let it cook for 10 minutes on the lowest flame. We’ve sealed the lid to retain the steam.
Our dum biryani is ready! If you liked the video, please like, comment, and share your feedback. If you haven’t subscribed, do subscribe and press the bell icon for updates.