We’re going to make a fragrant, mildly spiced authentic Lucknowi mutton biryani — just like the one made in Lucknow. To begin, take one cup of oil. Heat the oil on medium flame and—
—fry sliced onions until soft. Once lightly soft, add the meat. Add 1 kg of mutton. Now increase the flame to high and keep stirring continuously to sear the mutton well. As the meat cooks—
Once the mutton is nicely seared, add two heaped tablespoons of ginger-garlic paste. Sauté the paste with the meat until the raw smell goes away. Then we add the rest of the spices—
Now mix everything well and roast all the spices with the meat for 3–4 minutes while stirring continuously.
Now lower the flame and add yogurt — around 200 grams, roughly 1 cup, well whisked. After adding it, mix everything again nicely. Once the yogurt blends in with the spices, keep the flame—
Now I'm going to cook the mutton in the same handi (pot). It'll take about an hour. You can also pressure-cook it if you like. I’ve added 3 cups of water, and I’m going to cook it on very low flame.
Now after opening the lid, you can see the mutton is well cooked. The biryani korma (gravy) won’t be too thick — it should remain slightly thin. Now we’ll tilt the handi like this and collect the rogan (flavored oil) separately from the meat.
Add 1/4 tsp of mace (javitri) powder, 10–12 saffron strands, 1 tbsp kewra water, and fresh cream (or malai made from milk). Whisk the cream well before adding — about half a cup. Now pour the remaining stock from the mutton.
Mix everything thoroughly — this is your biryani masala (akhni) which is now ready. Set it aside. Now to the extracted rogan, add 2 tablespoons of desi ghee and a few drops of edible sweet essence (meetha ittar).
Mix the rogan well with ghee and sweet ittar — this spice mixture is now ready. Time to cook the rice. We’ll cook the rice 50% only. To boiling water, add whole spices, 2 heaped tablespoons of salt, and a bit of ghee.
Cook the rice until 50% done or until it has a slight bite (two kanis). When the water starts to boil, cook for 2–3 minutes and then strain the rice. Now in the vessel where you’ll layer the biryani, add—
After spreading the mutton evenly, pour the milk and spice mixture over it. Then pour all the rogan over that. After adding the rogan, add the rice — the same rice you just parboiled.
Now we’ll add food color over the top. If you don’t prefer food coloring, you can also add saffron soaked in milk. I’ve taken a bit of orange food color, mixed it with water, and poured it over the rice.
To cook the Lucknowi mutton biryani properly on dum (steam), cover it tightly. Once you remove the lid, your entire kitchen will be filled with aroma. Now serve it — gently fluff the rice from bottom to top, mixing with the masala layer first.