Hello and welcome friends! Today we are going to make a basic mutton biryani — Kerala-style Thalassery mutton biryani. Let's see how to make this super simple Thalassery biryani.
First, we need to gather the ingredients. Gather the ingredients, gather the ingredients, gather the ingredients.
We can cut the onions into slices. Place the pan on the stove. Place the pan on the stove, on the stove, on the stove…
Next, for around 5 teaspoons, we add turmeric powder and red chili powder. Red chili powder, red chili powder, red chili powder…
After the mutton is well mixed, add about six glasses of water, because we need the mutton to cook properly. Close the cooker and cook it for 4–5 whistles. The mutton should be about 80–90% cooked.
We are sautéing one onion — small shallots are added. Sauté the onions well. Add one teaspoon of ginger-garlic paste and green chilies. Add those too. Next, add some…
After boiling water in the kettle, we’ll add the cooked mutton to it. We’ve pressure cooked the mutton with 4–5 whistles. It should be about 80–90% done. The rest will cook in the dum process.
It’s well cooked. Now we boil water on the side. We’ll cook the rice now. We are using Kaima rice or Jeerakasala rice — traditional Kerala biryani rice.
The rice should be ¾ cooked. We drain the rice. Some water remains, so it gets a little steamed. The rice will cook further in the dum.
Now we’ll close the pot and let it cook on low flame for 5 to 10 minutes on dum. After 5–10 minutes, our Thalassery biryani will be ready. Super delicious!
The mutton is cooked perfectly — soft and juicy. There’s a nice layer at the bottom too. The Thalassery biryani we made turned out really tasty! We made it in proper Kerala style.
Look at our mutton — super soft, juicy, and well-cooked. We cooked 80–90% of it in the cooker, and the remaining 10% was done in dum. That’s why it’s so soft and flavorful.