As-salaam-alaikum, today I’m sharing with you the recipe to make Awadhi Biryani. You’ve probably made many types of biryani before—spicy, full of masalas—but Awadhi Biryani is completely different.
To make this biryani, first take 5 cups (1 kg) of long-grain, high-quality basmati rice. Wash the rice well 3–4 times and then soak it for half an hour.
In a bowl, take 3 tablespoons of garlic and add half a cup of water. Mix it well and strain it. Use a strainer to extract the juice from the garlic.
We don’t need the garlic paste—just press it thoroughly to extract the juice. Set this aside. Now take 1 kg of chicken, which I’ve already cleaned and prepped.
Add salt to taste. Then add 1 cup of thick, fresh yogurt. Add the garlic water we just extracted. Then add 2 teaspoons of red chili powder or Kashmiri chili powder.
Awadhi Biryani is all about aroma. It’s built on fragrance, not heavy spices. That’s why I’m adding 2 tablespoons of kewra water. Also add 3 tablespoons of ginger paste.
As you can see, very few spices are used here—that’s the specialty. Now add some whole spices: 7–8 small green cardamoms, 1 large black cardamom, 1/4 piece of nutmeg, 2 cloves.
Now set this marinade aside for 15–20 minutes. Meanwhile, boil water for the rice—about 4 to 5 liters. Add 2-inch cinnamon sticks, 4–5 small cardamoms, and 7–8 cloves.
Add oil and 3 tablespoons of salt. Adding oil prevents the rice from becoming sticky or breaking. Cover the pot so it comes to a boil faster.
Cook the rice only 50–60%. Do not overcook. Even 50% is okay. Don’t go to 70–80%. The rest of the cooking will happen with the gravy later.
The remaining cooking will happen with the chicken gravy. I’ve heated about 1 cup (250 ml) of oil—biryani uses a generous amount of oil.
Fry the onions until perfectly golden. Once they are golden, add the marinated chicken and fry it on high heat for 8–10 minutes.
Now to cook the chicken, add half a cup of water, cover the pot, and cook for 10–12 minutes. The rest will cook later with the rice.
I’ve cooked this on low heat for 10–12 minutes. The chicken is about 50–60% done—semi-cooked. At this point, turn off the heat and add 3–4 cups of milk along with a few strands of saffron.
If you don’t have saffron, you can use food color—red or orange. Add 1/2 teaspoon cardamom powder and 1 tablespoon more of kewra or rose water.
Now separate the chicken pieces from the gravy (yakhni). Set the chicken aside. On top of the yakhni, you’ll see oil (called "tari")—separate and keep it.
Don’t waste anything. Keep the yakhni because it will provide the final taste and flavor of the biryani. Only discard the excess impurities floating on top.
Now layer the separated chicken pieces at the bottom of the pot. Pour all the yakhni over the chicken. I’ve also taken half a cup of warm milk here.
Pour the saffron milk mixture over the rice. If you don’t have saffron, use food coloring. Add the oil we separated (rogan) on top—this gives a nice finish and flavor.
Now seal the pot—either with dough or foil. I don’t prefer sealing with dough as it can be risky, but you can if you like. Cover it tightly and prepare for dum (slow steam cooking).
Let the biryani cook on dum for about 25 minutes on low heat. Don’t open the lid in between. Keep it fully covered so the biryani steams perfectly. Your Awadhi biryani is now ready with beautiful aroma.
How did your biryani turn out? Mine turned out great—everyone loved it, Mashallah. You’ve probably made many spicy biryanis—try this fragrant Awadhi biryani once; you’ll love it.
I hope you liked this recipe. Please try it and give me your feedback. Let me know how your Lucknow-style Awadhi biryani turned out.
I'm sure you liked the recipe—do try it out and don’t forget to share your feedback.