Assalamu Alaikum dear viewers! A warm welcome to all my lovely subscribers, both new and old. Today, I'm sharing with you a delicious Kolkata-style chicken biryani recipe. Be sure to try this on Eid. Many of you had requested this recipe for a long time—specifically Kolkata-style chicken biryani—so here it is!
If you're a biryani lover, check out the playlist on my channel for many varieties of biryani. If you want a specific type, let me know in the comments. It might take a little time, but I’ll definitely upload it. Now let’s quickly see how to make this amazing biryani.
To make chicken biryani, start with 400 grams of oil. Once the oil is hot, reduce the flame to medium and add 300 grams of finely chopped onions. Fry the onions on medium flame until golden brown—this is called 'beresta'.
As you can see, the onions have fried well. Quickly remove them. Always use more onions when making beresta because they shrink when fried. I used 300 grams of onions and 400 grams of oil, which is the amount needed for this biryani.
Repeat background ambient speech without recipe content.
Add 1 tsp red chili powder and salt to taste.
Add 1 to 1.5 glasses of water, cover it, and let it cook.
The potatoes should cook about 80% at this stage because the remaining 20% will cook during the dum process. Cover and cook the potatoes on medium flame. To check if they're ready, pierce with a knife—if it goes through smoothly but doesn't break the potato, it’s 80% done.
Use a knife to check; it should go in easily without breaking or crumbling the potato. This is how I always check and show in my videos. Once done, remove the potatoes.
In this same broth, we will cook the chicken. Kolkata biryani potatoes are cooked like this for maximum flavor. Now add chicken—I'm using 1.5 kg of chicken thigh pieces. Always follow my instructions precisely for restaurant-style results.
Cut the chicken into large pieces as shown. Add 3 tablespoons garlic paste, 2 tablespoons ginger paste (less than garlic), 1.5 tablespoons of spicy red chili powder (not Kashmiri chili).
Add 1 tablespoon biryani masala, about ½ tsp kewra water (it’s strong, use sparingly), and 10-12 drops of Mughlai meetha ittar (aroma essence).
Add 2 teaspoons of salt.
If you're using older curd, use no more than 150g. Do not use sour curd. Add the previously fried beresta—crushed. Reserve some beresta for layering. Mix everything well and cook the chicken on low flame for 20–25 minutes, stirring once or twice.
It’s been 20 minutes of cooking chicken on low to medium heat. It should be cooked about 70%—not fully. Fully cooking it will cause it to break apart during dum. I’ve cooked it for 20 minutes on low to medium flame.
I didn’t add extra water. The curd and chicken’s moisture is enough. Now strain the yakhni (broth) and discard the whole spices. We’ll use this aromatic broth later.
Warm and cool ½ cup milk. It can be used warm or cold. Add 1 tablespoon biryani masala (original recipe, link in description), 1 tsp garam masala powder, and 1 tsp sugar.
Add 2 tablespoons rose water and 15–20 drops of Mughlai ittar. Mix and keep aside. In your biryani pot, add the boiled potatoes at the bottom.
Then layer the cooked chicken all around. This is an authentic Kolkata biryani recipe. Make it for Eid and leave a comment. Always keep potatoes in the middle and chicken around the sides—otherwise, the chicken will become too soft. Keep this in mind.
This biryani does NOT use yakhni layers (repeats this multiple times). Do not add yakhni multiple times. Once is enough.
Add beresta now—the remaining we kept aside. Spread it well. Now add a few dried plums (aloo bukhara), used in every Kolkata biryani—adds a great touch. Don’t add too many, just a few.
Now add the strained yakhni broth with its rich aroma and masalas. I’ll show the milk step after this—don’t skip the video. I’ll now prepare the rice by boiling water.
For this biryani: 1.5 kg chicken, 1.5 kg rice, 1 kg potatoes—total 4 kg biryani. Now add spices: 2 black cardamoms, 10–12 cloves, 2 cinnamon sticks, 3–4 green cardamoms, 3–4 bay leaves.
Add salt according to water quantity (unclear due to audio glitch).
Remove all whole spices after boiling. If some remain, it’s fine. Cook the rice to 70%. Once the water starts boiling, add rice. After it re-boils, cook for 6 minutes—exactly.
Drain the rice very carefully at 70% doneness. Don’t overcook. Use long-grain basmati—it gets soft quickly. Drain gently, and then fluff using a spoon.
The pot I'm using is small for this quantity, but I’ll manage. Use a bigger pot if you have one. Use 1.5 cups of milk for the entire biryani—milk should be warm, not raw.
Add the milk over the rice to keep the top layer soft. I’m also using a bit of yellow food coloring—used in restaurants. Now I’ll heat a tawa (griddle), place the pot on it on high flame for 7 minutes, then on low flame for 40 minutes. Don’t skip the full timing!
After dum (steaming), pour 4–5 tablespoons of ghee over the biryani and cover again for 5–6 minutes. This is also done in restaurants. The aroma and taste become perfect. I’ve shared an authentic restaurant-style recipe—do try it.
Our Kolkata-style chicken biryani is ready! It smells amazing—just like restaurant biryani. Do try it and follow all steps exactly. Look at the rice—it’s fluffy and separate.
Make sure to cook the rice only 70% and follow the dum timings I told you. If you do everything as instructed, you can make perfect biryani at home. The correct way to serve is to first separate the rice, then gently take out the chicken and potatoes without mixing everything.
Separate the top and bottom layers—top plain rice, bottom spiced rice—and mix them lightly while serving. That’s the correct way. Whenever you try this biryani, comment below and let me know how it turned out. If you liked my recipe, please like my channel.
Press the bell icon to get updates on new videos. Make this recipe, enjoy it, and stay happy. Allah Hafiz!