Hello everyone, welcome to Home Cooking with me, Hema Subramanian. When it comes to biryanis, there are different varieties from different regions. Today, I'm going to share a very special biryani all the way from Kerala. This is from the Malabar region—Talasheri Chicken Biryani. It's made using small-grain Jeeraga Sala or Jeeraga Samba rice, also known as Kaima rice. There are a couple of steps involved, so let's get started and dive right into the recipe.
First, we’re going to prepare the garam masala powder. I'm going to add a bunch of whole spices: 4 cardamoms, 2 pieces of cinnamon, 5 cloves, 2 star anise, ½ teaspoon of whole peppercorns, 2 small pieces of nutmeg, 2 small pieces of mace, and 1 teaspoon of fennel seeds.
Also add 1 teaspoon of shahi jeera and 2 Kashmiri red chilies. Dry roast all the whole spices for about 2–3 minutes on a medium-low flame. You'll start to get a lovely aroma. Turn off the stove, transfer the spices to a plate, and let them cool completely. Once cooled, grind the spices into a fine powder.
Our garam masala is ready and we'll use this for the biryani. It’s always best to grind it fresh. Now, we're going to fry the onions. In a kadai, pour enough oil for deep-frying. Once the oil is hot, gently add in two large thinly sliced onions.
Fried onions are very important for this recipe. Fry them until golden brown, then remove and set aside. For garnish, we’ll also use cashew nuts and raisins. I’ve taken about 1 cup of cashews. Fry them till golden brown, remove, and keep aside.
Next, fry about ½ cup of golden raisins. Once done, remove and keep aside. Now we have all the garnish elements ready. Next, we’ll cook the chicken. Take a wide pan or kadai and add ¼ cup of ghee.
For this recipe, I’ve taken 4 medium-sized onions, thinly sliced. Sauté the onions till golden. Then add 1½ tablespoons of garlic paste, 1½ tablespoons of ginger paste, and 2 tablespoons of green chili paste.
After sautéing for 2–3 minutes, add 1 kg of bone-in chicken. Cook for 5 minutes, ensuring the ginger, garlic, and chili paste coats the chicken well. Add ½ tsp of turmeric powder and 2 tsp of salt.
We’re cooking the chicken on high flame. Now add the freshly ground garam masala. This will add a lot of flavor. Also add 3 medium-sized chopped tomatoes.
After 10 minutes, add ½ cup of whisked curd. Continue cooking the chicken on high flame and mix well. Reduce the flame to medium. Add a few mint and chopped coriander leaves. Mix everything together.
Add 2–3 handfuls of crushed fried onions to the chicken. Mix it well. This adds great flavor. Finally, add 2 tablespoons of thick coconut milk. This is optional but adds a lovely flavor.
The chicken masala is ready. Keep it aside. Now we’ll cook the rice. I’ve taken 2 cups of Jeeraga Samba rice, also called Jeeraga Shala or Kaima rice. This is a short-grain rice and ideal for this recipe, but basmati can be used if unavailable. Wash the rice well and soak it in water for 10 minutes.
To cook the rice, take a deep pot and add 2 teaspoons of ghee. Add whole spices: cinnamon, cloves, cardamom, bay leaf, and star anise. For 2 cups of rice, I’ve used 3¼ cups of water (250 ml measure). Add 1 tsp salt, mix well, cover the pot, and bring the water to a boil.
Once the water starts boiling, add the soaked rice. Cover and cook on medium-high flame until the rice is done. Once cooked, turn off the stove.
Now that everything is ready, we’ll start the dum cooking. Take a heavy-bottomed pot and begin layering. First, add all the chicken at the bottom and spread it evenly. Then add half of the cooked rice and spread it out. Drizzle 1 teaspoon of ghee.
Add chopped coriander and mint leaves, some fried onions, fried raisins, and fried cashew nuts.
For added flavor, sprinkle a little garam masala powder and some saffron water (saffron strands soaked in hot water). Add the rest of the rice and spread it out evenly. Press gently. Drizzle another teaspoon of ghee.
Top with chopped coriander, mint leaves, fried onions, raisins, and cashew nuts. Sprinkle a little more garam masala powder and the remaining saffron water. Cover the pot with foil or seal with dough made from wheat flour or maida. Place a plate on top.
Heat a tawa and place the pot on it. Keep the flame on medium-low and cook on dum for 20 minutes. After 20 minutes, open the pot. The biryani looks amazing. Use a large spatula to scoop from the bottom and serve hot with raita.
This Talasheri Biryani is full of flavor—chicken, fried onions, golden raisins, and cashew nuts. It’s absolutely delicious. You must try it. Let me know how it turned out for you!
Here is the absolutely delicious, fragrant, and flavorful Talasheri Chicken Biryani. Follow all the steps to get it just right. Enjoy it with some raita. Try the recipe, enjoy, and share it with your loved ones. The second edition of our Home Cooking book is now available on our website: 21frames.in. I’ll share the link in the description. It’s currently available only in India.
You can place your orders on 21frames.in.