Today I’m sharing a Kolkata-style biryani recipe with you, which includes potatoes and eggs. It’s quite light, with a perfect blend of spices—not too heavy—so you can easily enjoy a full plate. It’s also very easy to make.
First, we’ve taken 600 grams of chicken. Then we added 4 to 5 teaspoons of yogurt, 1 to 2 teaspoons of ginger-garlic-green chili paste, fried onions, salt, Kashmiri red chili, turmeric powder, biryani masala, and 2 teaspoons of kewra water.
In a cooker or pot, add ghee. Then add soaked potatoes and hard-boiled eggs. Add a pinch of turmeric powder and fry them for 3 minutes. We had cut the potatoes in half, and the eggs are hard-boiled.
Take out the eggs. We fried the potatoes until golden and crisp and set them aside. In the leftover oil, we added chopped onions. Mix and cook until golden. The onions must be well browned.
Add the chicken and mix it well. Cook it on medium flame for about 5 minutes. After that, we added the fried potatoes. Cook them for another 5 minutes.
The most special part of Kolkata chicken biryani is the potatoes and eggs—so don’t skip them. After cooking the potatoes like this, we added water—just enough to submerge the chicken. Mix it well.
Take the gravy out into a bowl. Add saffron milk to it and mix. This yakhni is now ready—it’s essential for biryani. To prepare the rice, we added salt and whole spices to boiling water.
Mix well. Note: Kolkata-style biryani doesn’t use whole spices, so after boiling we’ll remove them. Then add the soaked rice—we used 2 cups—and cook it to 70%, then strain and set it aside.
Add about a spoonful of kewra water—it gives a great flavor. Then add the prepared yakhni and layer the rice well. Spread the rice evenly. Then again add kewra water and—
—it adds a wonderful aroma. Please try this chicken recipe at least once; you’ll love it. We've layered the yakhni. Then we top it with fried onions and ghee. Now we’ll seal it—
Cover it well, and cook on medium flame for 15 to 20 minutes. After that, our biryani is perfectly ready. Just look—it’s perfect chicken biryani. The rice is so fluffy and well-separated.
If you’re not subscribed to the channel, don’t forget to subscribe. See you in the next video—bye!