Today I’m going to show you how to make this amazing recipe – Lucknowi Chicken Biryani. So you must learn how to make it. Watch the full video. The first thing you need to do is soak the rice.
After soaking 1 kg of rice, wash it thoroughly. Meanwhile, take some saffron strands and mix them in 3 tablespoons of milk. See this – let it soak well.
After slicing onions, place your preferred cooking pot on the stove and pour in half a cup of oil. Once the oil heats up, add the sliced onions. Look at this – fry the onions until they turn golden brown.
(Additional lines unclear/repetitive – skipping for clarity.)
Now add 8 green cardamoms and 6 cloves. Then add ginger garlic paste. Cook the paste really well to remove the raw smell.
Now add red chili powder – keep stirring well. (Note: The line repeats "aloo chili powder" – likely a mis-speak of "lal mirch" (red chili)).
Turn the flame low. Add 200 grams of whisked curd/yogurt. Stir it gently and let it cook nicely.
Now add a pinch of mace powder, half a teaspoon cardamom powder, and a pinch of nutmeg powder. Mix it all in gently. When you see a nice sheen in the chicken, move to the next step.
Cook it for a while until the chicken is 80–90% cooked – no more than that. As you can see, the chicken is beautifully cooked now. And the gravy you see here is very important.
Now we strain the yakhni (stock). Look at this – it smells amazing! Use a strainer to collect all the aromatic yakhni into a bowl.
Now extract the 'rogan' (flavored oil/fat). Do this as I’m showing you – collect it in a bowl. Then add 2 tablespoons of ghee into the rogan, mix it well, and keep it aside. We’ll use it later.
Now add cinnamon powder, a pinch of mace powder, half teaspoon cardamom powder, a pinch of nutmeg, 1 tbsp kewra water, 1 tbsp rose water, 100g milk, and 100g fresh cream. Mix this well.
Now add 5–6 liters of water in a large vessel. Add 8–10 green cardamoms, 2 cinnamon sticks, 2 bay leaves, 7–8 cloves, and at least 3–4 tablespoons of salt.
Add plenty of salt – it's important. Then add 4 tablespoons of desi ghee. While the water is heating, strain the soaked rice. Once the water is boiling, squeeze the juice of a lemon into it.
You can now remove the whole spices if you prefer, or leave them in – your choice. Now turn the flame high and boil the rice. Our rice is now cooked properly.
Now lift the pot and strain all the rice thoroughly as shown. Take the vessel in which you'll layer the biryani. Add 2 tablespoons of ghee and coat the bottom.
Now layer the strained rice, followed by the cooked chicken. Then pour the yakhni (flavored stock) evenly on top, and add the remaining rice over that.
Gently layer everything. Now pour the remaining yakhni around the sides. Then add the saffron milk we soaked earlier – this is going to be magical.
Now pour the reserved rogan on top. Then add 3 drops of meetha ittar (sweet edible essence), 2 pinches of cardamom powder, 1 pinch nutmeg powder, 2 pinches of cinnamon powder, and 1 pinch of mace powder.
Cover the pot tightly, as I’m showing you, and seal it. Then keep it on low flame and cook on dum (slow steam) for 15–20 minutes.
First, cook on high flame for 2 minutes to generate steam inside. Then lower the flame completely and let it cook for 15 minutes on dum.
25 minutes have passed, and the biryani has been beautifully cooked on dum. I’m taking it to the table to show you how stunning it looks. Hold your heart – it’s going to be impressive!
Look at this – every grain of rice is separate and has amazing color. The saffron and rogan have given it a royal touch. This is a biryani you can count every grain of!
Now see how to serve it – gently lift it like this. Look at that color! Serve it on a plate. I’ll say it again – every grain of rice is distinct, and the aroma is just divine, beyond words!
Now, if you liked the video, and if you appreciated my work and it touched your heart, then please subscribe to the channel and share the video with your friends and family.