Hi, hello, welcome back to our channel! This Sunday I am going to show you how to make Dindigul special Talapakatti Chicken Biryani. This biryani will be spicy with a unique flavor, so let’s see how to prepare this Dindigul biryani.
Before preparing the Dindigul Talapakatti Biryani, take half a cup of chopped onions, half a green chili, some ginger, garlic, a little coriander, and a quarter cup of mint leaves in a mixer jar and grind them to a paste.
Take 2 mace, 2 bay leaves, and 6 cloves (more spice ingredients follow, cut off in original).
Biryani masala is ready. Next, to prepare the biryani, heat half a cup of oil and 2 tablespoons of ghee in a vessel. Add the ground paste and sauté well until the raw smell disappears.
Take 500 grams of chicken and mix it with the green chili paste. Add 1 tablespoon of red chili powder and let it marinate well.
Add 0.5 tablespoon turmeric powder, 0.5 tablespoon biryani masala, and 0.5 cup of chopped coriander leaves.
Add 1 cup of mint leaves, 10 cashew nuts, and 1 cup of curd.
Take 2 cups of basmati rice and 2 cups of water.
6 cardamoms.
END END END END END