Today, we will make biryani in a simple way. If you want a delicious biryani that can be made instantly, easily, and perfectly, just follow this recipe step by step.
To make this biryani, we will first cook the meat. Put the meat in a pressure cooker. I’ve taken one kilogram of meat. Add one tablespoon of ginger‑garlic paste and one teaspoon of salt.
After one whistle, lower the flame and cook it on low heat so the meat becomes tender. Once the pressure releases by itself, we will open the cooker.
Now we’ll prepare the fragrant homemade biryani masala. Take 7–8 cloves, half teaspoon of fennel seeds, 1 teaspoon of cumin seeds, 9–10 green cardamoms, 1 mace, half teaspoon black pepper, and 1 bay leaf.
This spice mix is perfect for a 1 kg biryani. You can dry-grind it or grind it with green chillies. I’ll blend them together, but you may do it separately if you prefer.
If you wish, grind the spices and green chillies separately and then combine. I’m grinding them together with about one-third cup of water until smooth.
We’ll also use some powdered spices. Add 1 tsp Kashmiri red chilli powder, 1 tsp red chilli powder, 1 tsp cumin powder, and 1 tsp salt (keeping in mind salt was already added to the stock).
Let's start cooking the biryani. In a pan, I’ve added 1 cup (approx. 250 ml) of mustard oil. I prefer this oil these days as it's a bit healthier.
You can prep stock a day before—it shortens cooking time significantly. I hosted an Eid feast, so I made my stock in advance and finished cooking the next day.
I used the oil to fry three medium onions until golden brown. I’ll reserve one part aside for garnish and use two parts in the stock.
Now I’ve added two tablespoons of ginger‑garlic paste. One tablespoon was added earlier to the stock, totaling three tablespoons.
Sauté this for 7–8 minutes on high flame to lose the raw aroma, then add one cup (250 g) of yogurt.
With the yogurt, the meat is partially cooked. Add the fried onions—two portions—keeping one aside for layering garnish.
The masala is partially cooked—don’t let it dry out. Maintain about ¼ cup of water in the gravy. Also remove about one-third of the oil.
This helps keep rice fluffy. See, the gravy still has some moisture. Keep a little—don’t let it dry. The masala is now ready.
Give it a mix—this is our gravy ready for biryani assembly. Keep aside. Now let’s prepare the rice.
Boil about 3.5 liters of water. Add 1 tbsp oil (to keep rice grains separate), juice of half a lemon, and 3 tbsp salt.
While the water heats, note I soaked basmati golden sela rice 1.5–2 hours earlier. Always wash well before soaking.
Drain the soaked rice and add to boiling water. Cook on high flame for 5–6 minutes until the rice is about 80 % done.
Now assemble the biryani. Grease the bottom of your assembly pan with some oil to prevent sticking. Add one-third of the rice (I divided mine into three).
Feel free to do a single layer if preferred. Add fried onions, coriander leaves, mint leaves, red‑orange food color, kewra water, and half the gravy. Reserve the other half for the second layer.
Now add the remaining gravy, then cover with the rest of the rice. I chose two gravy layers, but you can choose just one.
Top again with coriander, mint, fried onions, and pour in the reserved oil. Also add the drained rice water—this aids steaming nicely.
Cover the pot and cook on high flame for 2 minutes so the vessel heats up. Then place it on a heavy tawa or pan and simmer on low flame.
[Repeated filler sounds—unintelligible—omitted for clarity.]
At this point, gently mix the top and bottom rice layers so the masala distributes evenly. Cover and let rest for 10–15 minutes before serving.
The biryani turned out delicious. As you saw, it’s easy and quick to make. I hope you enjoy this simple yet tasty biryani recipe. Perfect for your Eid feasts!