To make a perfect Aamai (tortoise) biryani, just do these three things right — that's enough for it to turn out amazing. I’ll tell you everything. First, let’s prepare the chili paste. I’ve soaked dry red chilies for an hour in hot water and added them to a jar.
Make the paste, and add it to the cooker. Heat it up. You can also add a tablespoon of ghee. Here, we’re only adding bay leaf, clove, and cardamom. As always, add a little bit of oil with the biryani. In this...
Add finely sliced onions — about two large onions will do. Add a bit of salt as well to help them sauté. In this biryani, the garlic shouldn't be visible to kids — sauté the garlic really well. Then...
...keep the flame on medium while sautéing. When sautéing, you’ll see that the garlic doesn’t stick out. Add two large tomatoes, finely chopped. Add a handful of mint, and an equal amount of chopped coriander. Chop them both finely.
Sautéing the ginger-garlic paste separately is very important. Now we can add the chili paste. I added one tablespoon just for the spice. You can add one tablespoon of curd too. Then add half...
...a lemon and mix it lightly. I’ve cleaned 1 kg of chicken and kept it ready. Add it in and mix well with the masala. It will release some water. At this point, I’ll add one cup of...
I’ve soaked seeraga samba rice for half an hour — that’s the rice you must use. Do not use basmati rice for this biryani. Only with seeraga samba will you get that superb, original taste. That’s when you’ll really notice the flavor. Once...
I’ll tell you the water ratio: for 1 cup of seeraga samba rice, add 1.25 cups of water. Since we’ve already drained and added it, just 1 cup of water is enough. Now close the lid and cook it on dum (slow steam) for 10 minutes on low flame.
The aroma is amazing! Once you eat this biryani, you’ll forget five others for sure. Try it out and comment to let me know. After making this tortoise biryani, enjoy it and have fun. Eat this biryani on a Sunday, and we’ll...
But for this biryani, for one cup of seeraga samba rice, just one cup of water is enough. We're adding it lightly after draining it.