Today we’re making Lucknowi Chicken Biryani, also known as Awadhi Chicken Biryani. It’s a lightly spiced biryani with a very rich flavor. First, we’ll take half a cup of oil.
We’ll lightly fry the onions to golden. Once they are fried, add 1 kg chicken. As soon as we add it, increase the flame to high and mix the chicken well with the oil. Fry it nicely on high flame.
Add 5 cloves. With just these whole spices, we'll roast the chicken until the raw smell of ginger-garlic goes away. Continue mixing on high flame. This biryani uses yellow chili powder which adds excellent flavor.
Add 2 tbsp of yellow chili powder and 1 tbsp of red chili powder. Mix the chicken well with these spices for 1 to 1.5 minutes. Now reduce the flame to low and add 3/4 cup of whisked curd — about 150 grams.
To make biryani masala, take 10g green cardamom, 10g mace (javitri), and half a nutmeg. Grind them into a fine aromatic powder. Add ½ tsp of this biryani masala into the pan.
Now mix the curd thoroughly with the chicken. Once it is well mixed, increase the flame again. Once the chicken boils nicely, add about half a cup of water. Let it cook well.
Add 3–4 drops of sweet ittar (aromatic essence). Cover and cook the chicken for at least 15 minutes on medium to low flame. Cook it 80–90% through. The rest will cook with the rice later.
Now strain the broth (yakhni) properly. Squeeze out all the flavor from the spices while straining.
Now add all the fragrance: 1 tbsp kewra water, 1 tbsp rose water, 3–4 drops of sweet ittar, and 1 cup of milk to make the biryani even richer.
Mix everything well. This fragrant yakhni is now ready. Now scoop out 2–3 tablespoons of the oil or gravy (rogan) from the top. Save about 1 tbsp more for layering later.
Add green cardamom and a bay leaf. Add 2 tbsp of salt. Also, add 2 tbsp of ghee — this makes the rice soft and rich. Squeeze in half a lemon.
Cook the rice until it is about 75% done. Use the same pot in which we prepared the chicken for layering the biryani.
Drizzle a little ghee in the base. Spread a layer of 75% cooked rice evenly. Now add the chicken. After that, pour the aromatic yakhni over it.
Drain the remaining water from the rice and layer it on top. After layering all the rice, pour the saved rogan mixture over it. Add a bit of orange food color. You can also soak saffron in milk and add that.
Cover and cook the biryani on low flame for 20–25 minutes. After 20 minutes, remove the lid. This biryani doesn’t use coriander, mint leaves, or fried onions — just enjoy it as is.