In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. As-salamu Alaikum. Today we will be making the Lucknow-style wedding special "Deg" Chicken Biryani recipe. This flavorful and extremely aromatic biryani is very easy to make.
You can enjoy this perfectly made biryani at home whenever you feel like it. So let's get started. If you like the video, don’t forget to give it a like. First, we will make this biryani perfectly...
Here we have taken 5 cups or 1 kg of rice. Wash them well 3–4 times and soak them for half to one hour. For 1 kg of rice, we need at least 4 liters of water, and we will add...
Whole spices like bay leaves, cloves, and green cardamom. Let them crackle for 10 seconds. Then add 1 large finely sliced onion and fry it. This is how we cut the onions for this.
Fry the onions on medium to high heat, stirring continuously, until they turn golden and crispy. Once they’re fried like this, add 1.25 kg (1250g) of well-washed chicken.
The chicken is washed thoroughly and left aside for a bit so the excess water drains out. That way, when we fry it, it won’t release too much water. Once it’s nicely fried, we add 3 tablespoons of...
And for whole spices, we use only a few aromatic ones: 2 blades of mace, 12 green cardamoms, 2 small pieces of cinnamon, 10 cloves, and three small pieces of...
The chicken is now well sautéed. Add 2 teaspoons of yellow chili powder, 1 teaspoon of red chili powder, and 1 teaspoon of salt. In Lucknow biryani, yellow chili powder is traditionally used...
Add 1 tablespoon of homemade cream (malai). Lower the heat now to prevent the yogurt from splitting and mix everything well. Then add 2–3 pinches of yellow food color. Two colors are used in this biryani...
This helps make the chicken soft and tender. Once it starts boiling, we’ve cooked the masala and water together for 10 minutes. Now add the soaked rice and cover, cooking on high heat until a boil comes.
We've cooked the chicken for about 10 minutes. Stirred it once in between. It’s now cooked through and sautéed well. Add 1.5 teaspoons of the aromatic spice mix we prepared.
Now add 1 tablespoon of rose water and 3–4 drops of sweet edible perfume (kewra essence). Then add just under 1 cup of milk. Cook on medium heat until the gravy...
About 70% of the rice is cooked. Don’t cook it any further because the rice is still raw and cooks quickly. The remaining cooking will happen on dum (steam), and it will soften completely...
Now divide the rice into three parts. First layer half the chicken with gravy. Then a second layer of remaining rice. Then layer the remaining chicken with its gravy and top with more chicken. After that...
Here’s the secret of restaurant-style biryani: on top, they add biryani essence. So take 2–3 pinches of orange food color, add half a teaspoon of biryani essence, 3 tablespoons of water, and mix well.
Make sure it doesn’t mix with the yellow color below. Now we’ll place it on dum. Cover the pot with a thick cloth and then place the lid tightly. Wrap the cloth all around to prevent heat escape.
After turning off the heat, we left it for 10 more minutes so the rice sets properly. First, separate and spread the oil (rogan) from the top. Then gently fluff the rice before serving...
Definitely try it, and enjoy with your favorite raita, salad, or chutney. Do try it and share your feedback, your experience. If you liked the video, please like it and subscribe if you’re new.