Assalamualaikum, friends. Biryani is made in many ways, and each city and state has its own style. Today we’re making a very simple Mughlai Chicken Biryani, easily made at home.
Let’s begin the recipe. First, marinate around 750g of chicken. Add 1 tbsp ginger-garlic paste, 1 cup curd, and half a tsp of...
...lemon juice. Mix everything well and set aside for 30 minutes. In a wok, heat some oil, add 3 green cardamoms, 3 cloves, and 1 black cardamom.
Once the onions are golden brown, add the marinated chicken. Cook on high flame for 4–5 minutes, then cover and cook for 20–25 minutes until the chicken is tender.
Add nutmeg and mace powder, mix everything, and cook for 1–2 minutes. The chicken masala is now ready. See how simple it was?
The masala has the right amount of gravy—not too dry, around 1 cup of liquid. Now we turn off the flame and move on to the next step.
We’re using 400g of basmati rice, boiled with bay leaf, cumin seeds, lemon juice, and a bit of oil. Cooked about 95%. You can see the grains are separate.
Add a little mint, then layer the rest of the rice. Pour about 1/4 cup milk, 1 tbsp melted ghee, and the same nutmeg-mace powder on top.
Add about 1 tsp kewra water and some fried onions. Cover tightly with silver foil and steam on high for 1 minute, then on low for 12–15 minutes.
Enjoy your delicious biryani!