Today we're going to make a very delicious and very yummy biryani, which we'll prepare in a rice cooker. It’s super quick to make, so do try this recipe and share your feedback with us on our Facebook or Instagram page.
We're about to hit 100 subscribers quickly, so please subscribe quickly too! Let's start. First, we took 1.5 kg of chicken. This is 1.5 kg of chicken which we've cleaned properly.
After that, we’ll add one spoon of turmeric powder and mix everything well. We’ll keep it aside for marination. This enhances the flavor of the chicken and gives a really good taste.
We'll leave the marinated chicken aside for one hour, covered. Meanwhile, we’ve taken 1.5 kg of rice. If we're using 1.5 kg of chicken, then we also need 1.5 kg of rice.
We’ll wash the rice well 2–4 times, then soak it for 30 minutes. Next, we’ve taken four medium-sized onions which we'll chop finely.
Now we’ve taken a pan and added mustard oil to it. Heat the oil until smoke comes out. Then we’ll add the onions and fry them. Initially, I told you...
We need to fry them till they turn golden brown. Keep stirring continuously until they get the right color. Look, our onions are nicely fried. We'll remove and place them on a plate so they remain crispy.
Our onions are nicely fried. In the same oil, we’ll now add the marinated chicken and fry it a bit. We don’t need to brown it too much—just a light fry for color.
(Repeated phrase unintelligible—likely an editing error in the source.)
Next, we’ll remove half of the oil and leave half in the pan. Now we add one spoon of ginger-garlic paste and three finely chopped medium tomatoes. Then we’ll add a quarter pack of curd.
Currently the flame is off. We’ve also added a full packet of store-bought biryani masala. You can use homemade too. Mix it all well.
Keep stirring continuously because we’ve added curd. If you don’t stir, it might split. You can see it has started boiling and the curd hasn't split.
The tomatoes have also softened quickly because we chopped them finely. Keep stirring until the oil starts to separate and becomes visible. Lastly, we’ll add...
We’ve added one spoon of Kashmiri red chili powder. This is optional but makes it tasty and slightly spicy. Mix well so the chili's sharpness reduces and it blends in.
You can see the curd has reduced and the oil has separated nicely. Now we’ll add one cup of water—don’t add more. Mix everything thoroughly.
Our soaked rice has grown slightly in size. In a separate vessel, we’ve boiled water and added one stick of cinnamon, four green cardamoms, three black cardamoms, and one spoon of cumin.
Add salt to taste—we added three spoons. Boil the spices well until the water changes color slightly. This infuses the flavor into the water.
The rice needs to be cooked partially—biryani rice should stay slightly hard. It doesn’t take long since we soaked it. We added a little oil to the boiling water too.
You need to be very careful when cooking biryani rice. Keep an eye on the size of the grains—once they swell slightly...
Check the rice by pressing it between your finger and thumb. If it breaks into two or three parts, then it’s done. We turned off the gas at this point.
Now in our rice cooker bowl, we added all the chicken. We’re not layering it because that gets hectic. This method works well. See, we added a little water too so the chicken remains moist.
Now we’ll push the chicken to the sides. This makes it easier to serve the biryani later, ensuring the chicken comes out cleanly.
We took a little curd and mixed it with some water and added food color. This gives a beautiful color. Please try this trick. We’ll pour this over the chicken.
This is about 2–3 tablespoons of curd. Then we added the remaining fried onions as a sprinkle, followed by half a bunch of chopped coriander and half a bunch of chopped mint.
Now we’ll add all the rice on top.
Once half the rice is added, we take one packet of Maggi masala. This is a secret trick—restaurants use such flavor boosters for their unique taste.
So instead of that, add one packet of Maggi masala. Trust me, it turns out amazing—very spicy and just like restaurant-style biryani. Then we add the remaining rice on top.
Now we cook it in the rice cooker just like we normally cook rice. This is how we’ll finish cooking it. Alongside, we’ve prepared a tasty...
...raita using curd, cucumber, half an onion, and some coriander. It pairs perfectly with biryani, doubling its taste. And as you can see, our biryani is ready.
Check it by inserting a spoon down to the bottom. If it comes out clean and dry, that means the biryani is perfectly cooked. See?
It turned out so delicious! The rice we added was 1.5 kg, just like the chicken. And you can see our flavorful chicken biryani is ready. So do...
...follow this recipe properly. I swear, it tastes even better than restaurant biryani. So follow the recipe fully, like the video, and if you enjoyed it, please subscribe to the channel.