Today we're going to make Bombay Biryani using homemade spices. So let's see how easily we can make it at home. Let's move!
First, let's look at the spices. For the dry whole spices, we have taken 30 bay leaves. 2-3 star anise. 2 teaspoons of cloves. 2 teaspoons of black peppercorns. 1 tablespoon of cumin seeds.
We have taken 2 small mace blades, 5 small green cardamoms.
We have taken 2 large star anise, a small piece of nutmeg, and 2 cinnamon sticks. All the whole spices should be ground very well. Next, we have the ground spices: 2 teaspoons of turmeric powder.
We've ground all the whole spices nicely. Now we'll add all the powdered spices one by one. We’ll also add salt to taste. Additionally, we’ll add some more whole spices: this small piece of...
...bay leaf, i.e., 3-4 bay leaves, 3-4 green cardamoms, black cardamoms, 5-6 cloves, 7-8 black peppercorns, and 1 stick of cinnamon. About 7-8 pieces.
On the other side, we’ve prepared the rest of the ingredients. We've taken a bunch of mint leaves and separated them from the stems. Similarly, we’ve taken fresh coriander leaves and separated them from the stems.
We have taken chicken, washed it thoroughly. We have 500 grams of tomatoes, which we have cut into slices. 4-5 potatoes, peeled and chopped into chunks. 1.5 cups...
...and 2 teaspoons of garlic paste added and mixed well. Then we add the chicken. Fry the chicken well with the garlic paste until the chicken changes color. As you can see, the potatoes...
...have also been added. We’ll keep repeating the same about the onions, onions, onions… (repetition likely due to video or subtitle glitch).
Cook it covered on medium-low flame for 10-15 minutes. After 10 minutes, we’ll open the lid. As you can see, the tomatoes are softened. Stir a bit and then we’ll add the biryani masala that we prepared earlier at home.
Mix it thoroughly. Sauté it well. After sautéing, add a little water as needed so that both the potatoes and chicken cook properly. Cover again and cook both well.
Chicken and potatoes are cooked. We’ll now add the remaining masala. We’ve added a few more fried potatoes, and added green spices like coriander, mint, and green chilies. Cook this for another 10-15 minutes.
After adding mint, we’ve also added saffron. We soaked the basmati rice an hour earlier. Now we’ll add the rice gently. Cook this on high flame. See, two layers are done. We’ll gently level them out.
On the other side, our chicken and potato korma is also ready. You can see the oil has come on top. Remove it from the stove. Meanwhile, heat a griddle on the stove. The pot with rice...
...add the second layer. After that, add some food color to the milk. Then add this colored milk in layers. Spread the chicken and potato mixture evenly. Then layer the rice again, and spread evenly.
Add the food color. Then add 1 teaspoon of biryani essence. Cover the pot. First steam the rice on high flame for about 5-7 minutes. After that, lower the flame and steam it for another 10 minutes.
Now we’ll dish it out. Viewers, our Bombay Biryani made with homemade spices is ready. If you liked today’s video, please like, share, and comment. Don’t forget to subscribe and press the bell icon to stay updated.