Today we’ll teach you how to make Mughal Darbar-style chicken biryani at home using a rice cooker. If you’ve ever tried Mughal Darbar’s biryani, you probably liked it. That’s why this recipe was highly requested.
Please share your feedback on our Facebook and Instagram pages, Kashmir Food Fusion. This biryani turns out very tasty and is a bit different from regular biryani, but still delicious. First, let’s look at the ingredients we've used.
We soaked the chicken in vinegar and salt water. This helps it become soft, tender, and clean. Then we used nutmeg and mace — both are essential in this recipe.
First, we’ll take a pressure cooker, add water, and put in the remaining chicken parts like the neck, back, and waist — parts that aren't great for eating in biryani. We’ll extract stock from them.
We had powdered nutmeg and mace — one each. Here's a pinch going in now, the rest will be added later in the recipe.
Now I'm adding MSG or monosodium glutamate, also known as Chinese salt — just a pinch, to enhance the flavor. It’s commonly used in restaurant-style recipes. After extracting the stock, we’ll cook the chicken separately in another pan.
We’re adding cloves (3), green cardamom (3), bay leaf (1), and turmeric powder (half a teaspoon).
Now I’m adding a pinch of red food color. This gives the chicken its signature reddish color. Boil this on high flame for about five minutes. After that, drain the water and keep the chicken aside for frying.
In Mughal Darbar-style biryani, the chicken is cooked separately. Take a pan, heat it well until it smokes lightly...
...then place the chicken on a plate after it’s done. This part seems to repeat unintentionally in the video.
Add black pepper — about 20 — along with two bay leaves, two black cardamoms, and one teaspoon cumin seeds.
After a brief sauté, add two chopped onions. Fry them well until about 50-60% caramelized. Then add red chili powder.
Now add tomato purée — made from three tomatoes blended in a mixer. After adding, fry the tomatoes well to eliminate the raw flavor.
The tomato and onion curry is ready. Now add coriander powder (1 teaspoon) and biryani masala powder, which you can find in stores.
(This section repeats unintentionally. Possibly filler in the original video.)
Then add half a teaspoon of the nutmeg and mace powder. The curry is ready. Now we’ll do the layering. Take a rice cooker, add peas, tomatoes, and the prepared onion curry at the bottom.
We’ve washed and added white basmati rice. If you're using sela rice, soak it beforehand. Here we’ve added the rice. Sela rice needs to be soaked for at least 20 minutes.
Now that the rice is added, pour in the chicken stock we made earlier. For 3 cups of white basmati rice, use 5 cups of stock. For sela or brown basmati, adjust the stock accordingly.
Mix everything well. At this stage, add the remaining nutmeg and mace powder. Also add more food color here — it’s important because that’s what gives the biryani its iconic look.
Mix all the ingredients — rice, chicken, and spices — thoroughly. Cook it in the rice cooker twice. First cook it once, stir gently, then cook it a second time. This ensures everything is perfectly done.
Always scoop biryani from the sides, not the center — that helps prevent the rice from breaking. The biryani rice is ready now. Let it cool down before serving.