Hello Fans, today I will teach you how to make Hyderabadi-style Chicken Dum Biryani. This biryani is extremely tasty to eat, and after today, you’ll be able to make it easily at home because I’m going to show you a very simple method.
First of all, I have taken 1.3 kilograms of chicken here. Wash the chicken thoroughly. After washing, put it into the same vessel in which you’re going to make the biryani. Now we have to marinate the chicken.
After that, add some Kashmiri red chili powder — I’ve added one and a half tablespoons here. This will make the biryani spicy and give it a nice color. Then add a little turmeric powder as well.
Along with this, we’ll add some brown onions, also called birista. If you don’t know how to make brown onions, there’s a video on the channel. You can watch and learn how to make them. Also, add 5–6 green chilies.
Add one tablespoon of garam masala powder or biryani masala powder. Now add some mint leaves — wash them well. Also add some finely chopped fresh coriander. Along with this, add some ginger-garlic paste.
Mix everything well. Now leave the chicken in this marinade for at least half an hour so that the salt, spice, and flavor seep deep into the chicken. Also, squeeze in a bit of lemon juice.
Add two tablespoons of desi ghee and mix it well. After adding ghee or oil, don’t use your hands, because the oil starts sticking to your hands.
Let the chicken rest in the marinade for at least 30 minutes. Now I’ve taken basmati long-grain rice here, and I’ve washed them properly so that all the dust and starch are removed.
You need to soak the rice. Soaking gives the rice good fluffiness and length after cooking. Let it soak. Now in a vessel, I’ve put water for boiling rice. First, add salt to the water.
Then add two small green cardamoms, and 4–5 pieces of cinnamon sticks. Add one tablespoon of shahi jeera (royal cumin). Let these spices boil with the water for at least 5–7 minutes.
Once the water is boiling, add the rice. Turn the flame to high so that it comes to a boil quickly. Once you’ve added the rice, stir gently with a ladle so that the rice doesn't stick together in the hot water.
Once the boil comes, reduce the flame to medium and cook for 7 minutes. Also, make sure to add enough salt while boiling the rice; otherwise, the biryani will taste bland. The rice should be well-seasoned.
Let it cook for another minute. I told you to cook the rice for 7 minutes. The first layer of rice should go in after 7 minutes. Pour a little of the hot rice water over the marinated chicken.
Now gently layer the first batch of partially cooked rice over the chicken. This rice should be slightly undercooked because the moisture in the chicken will help cook it further.
Now add the remaining rice as the third layer and spread it evenly across the top so the bottom layer of rice gets covered properly. The top layer should be nicely spread.
Now pour a little kewra water over the top. You’ll need to work quickly here, because if the rice cools down, it will take time to heat up again. Sprinkle some saffron soaked in water over the top as well.
I’m using foil paper to seal the pot for dum (slow steam cooking). You can also seal it with dough and place a lid on top. As you can see, I’ve sealed both sides with foil. Now sprinkle a little water over the top.
Place the lid on top. First, cook it on high flame for 2–3 minutes because the chicken is still cold and will take time to heat up. So give it 3 minutes on high.
Then reduce the flame to medium-low. As you can see, steam has formed nicely inside the biryani and the foil paper has started to puff up. This is the kind of flame you need. And always use a tawa (griddle) below if possible.
Now remove the foil paper. In 20 minutes, the chicken cooks completely, especially if you’ve used medium-sized pieces — they cook even faster. Now sprinkle a little mace powder on top for an excellent aroma.
And finally, garnish with some finely chopped fresh coriander leaves. This adds great flavor and freshness to the biryani.
Now start serving the rice like this. Whenever you scoop out biryani, do it from the sides. Don’t dig from the center, or the rice will break. This is how you properly serve biryani.
If you liked the video, don’t forget to like, share, and comment, my friends. Thank you!