As-salamu alaikum. Stop ordering Hyderabadi Chicken Dum Biryani from restaurants now. What's the need when you can make delicious, authentic Hyderabadi Chicken Dum Biryani at home? It’s very easy to make.
You’re going to love it a lot. Let’s start making Hyderabadi Biryani. To make Hyderabadi Chicken Dum Biryani, first we need 1 kg of chicken. You can keep the chicken pieces either large or medium in size.
A little more than half a teaspoon of crushed green chilies – you can finely chop or crush them coarsely. Add 2 teaspoons of salt, and juice of one lemon. Add 4 tablespoons full of—
Fresh coriander and mint leaves—wash them well and add. 1 tablespoon of garam masala powder. This is Hyderabadi garam masala powder. You’ll find the link in the description box. Just type Hyderabadi G—
Add 1 cup of oil. This is the same oil in which we fried the onions. We are also going to add fried onions now—birista. Now mix everything well. It’s mixed properly. Now we’ll add the fried onions too—
Take half a cup of milk, add 2 to 3 pinches of saffron in it. Add this as well. If you don’t have saffron, just add plain milk. Add 1 teaspoon of cardamom powder. If you don’t have powder, crush 4–5 cardamoms and add.
All the ingredients have mixed well with the chicken. Cover it with a lid and let it marinate for 2 hours. You can also marinate it for 3 or 4 hours, or even overnight in the refrigerator.
Meanwhile, soak 1 kg of basmati rice for one hour. Our chicken has marinated well and the rice is soaked. Now let’s start preparing to boil the rice. For that, take a large pot—
Add some chopped coriander and mint leaves like this. Now add garam masala powder—a little less than 1 teaspoon. 2 to 3 small cinnamon sticks, 4 to 5 cloves, cardamom, and about a teaspoon of shahi jeera—
This gives a nice aroma to the rice. Juice of half a lemon. Add 2 tablespoons of oil. Mix everything well. Once the water starts boiling, we will add the rice.
Let it boil for a minute like this so the spices release their flavor into the water. After adding the rice, mix once or twice gently. Keep the flame on high while the rice is cooking. Now I’ll tell you the timing—
Boil the rice for only 3 minutes. After boiling, we’re going to make the first layer of biryani over the chicken. Look, the water now—we’ll take a little of it. The chicken is absorbing the flavors. Three minutes are done.
Now let’s make the first layer of biryani. Strain the rice properly and layer it over the chicken.
After making the first layer, we’ll boil the rice again for 2 to 3 minutes for the second layer. Two to three minutes are done. Add the second layer. Spread it out evenly. Mix a bit of orange food color in milk—
You can also add yellow food color. Add a little ghee—3 teaspoons. Fresh coriander and mint leaves. Now seal the vessel—with aluminum foil or a cotton cloth. To seal it well, place an old tawa (griddle) below.
Cook on high flame for 2–3 minutes. After that, lower the flame and let it cook on "dum" (steam) for 30–40 minutes. Two to three minutes have passed, now we’ll lower the flame. We’ll steam it for 30–40 minutes.
Hot chicken biryani is ready!
It smells amazing. You all must try it. You can eat it with "Bagara Baingan" and "Dahi ki Chutney". You’ll find both videos on my channel. Just type “Dahi ki Chutney Bhai Cooks with Fame” or “Bagara Baingan”.
If you liked the video, do like and share it with your family and friends so they too can cook and enjoy delicious recipes. Tell us in the comments how you liked this biryani recipe.