Fragrant, delicious Kolkata Chicken Biryani made in flavorful yakhni with a mild flavor — today we’ll make it just like professional chefs do, just like it’s served at grand feasts. To make this biryani, we’ll begin with ginger-garlic preparation.
After mixing, we’ll strain it properly to extract all the juice. We'll set the water aside. Now let's prepare the potatoes — about 750 grams. We’ll make slits with a knife so that the masala penetrates inside.
We’ll take out half of the fried onions for garnishing, and leave the other half in the pan.
Now we’ll add the ginger-garlic water that we had prepared earlier. Add 1 heaped tablespoon of red chili powder, and ¼ teaspoon of yellow food color (you can use saffron instead). Add 1 heaped tablespoon of biryani masala.
Add 1 heaped tablespoon of beaten curd. I’m adding half a cup of water as well so that the potatoes cook properly. Mix everything well. Now add the prepped potatoes to it. Add a pinch of salt.
Mix well. Now we’ll cover and cook it on medium to low flame for 15 minutes. The potatoes need to be cooked only 70%, the rest will cook with the rice. Remove the lid, and take out the potatoes from the yakhni. Set them aside.
Now cover and let the chicken cook for 10–12 minutes. Chicken too needs to be cooked only 70%. Remove the lid, turn off the flame, and take out all the chicken pieces. Set the chicken aside. Now we’ll strain the yakhni thoroughly.
Add 1 tablespoon of kewra water. Add 1 tablespoon of rose water. This is mogra or sweet attar (perfume) — it's very strong, so we’ll add only 2–3 drops. Mix everything well. The rogan (flavored oil) on top of the yakhni will now be used.
After skimming off the rogan, add 1 full cup of milk. Add half a cup of curd, beaten well — I’ve blended it in a grinder for half a minute. Also add 1 heaped tablespoon of biryani masala, and half a teaspoon of red chili powder.
Add juice of half a lemon, 2 tablespoons of oil, 1 heaped tablespoon of salt. For whole spices, add a 3-inch cinnamon stick, 7–8 cloves, 6–7 green cardamoms, and 2 bay leaves. Boil these whole spices in water thoroughly.
Let the rice cook — we need to cook it till it’s 70% done. Now we’ll layer the biryani. First, add the chicken. Then set the prepared potatoes in place. Add 5–6 dried plums (alu bukhara) — they’re great for digestion.
Sprinkle about 1 tablespoon of Kolkata biryani masala all over. To enrich the biryani, add about 50 grams of khoya (dried milk solids). The rice is 70% cooked, so now we’ll layer it on top.
Spread the fragrant rogan we skimmed earlier all over the top. Add 2–3 tablespoons of desi ghee. Now we’ll cover it tightly. You can seal it with dough if you like. Cook on high flame initially.
You can serve this with boiled eggs and yogurt raita. A very delicious biryani is now ready. Do try it out! If you’re not yet subscribed to the channel, subscribe for more such recipes.